{"1141-MKT-DISTRICT": [{"number": 1, "question": "What type of law focuses on issues regarding the promises that businesses make with their customers, vendors, and other business partners? ", "choices": ["A. Patent", "B. Constitutional", "C. Probate", "D. Contract"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Contract. Contract law is an area of law that governs oral and written agreements\u2014promises\u2014that involve the exchange of goods, services, money, and/or property. Constitutional law is a body of law that addresses issues related to the Constitution and Constitutional rights. Probate is the legal process of validating a will and distributing assets to beneficiaries. A patent protects an owner's invention from use and distribution by unauthorized individuals. SOURCE: BL:001 SOURCE: Thomson Reuters. (2016). Contract law. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://smallbusiness.findlaw.com/business-contracts-forms/contract-law.html "}, {"number": 2, "question": "A basic principle of procedural due process involves __________ before taking action. ", "choices": ["A. awarding damages", "B. obtaining witnesses", "C. providing notice", "D. creating evidence"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Providing notice. Due process is the concept that the government must respect all of the legal rights that are owed to individuals and businesses according to the law of the land. Legal procedure refers to the methods and processes that are used to protect an individual's or business's legal rights. In many societies, these rights include the right to be notified of accusation or lawsuit (providing notice), the right to obtain legal counsel, the right to be heard in court, the right to confront the accuser, etc. Obtaining witnesses is a pretrial activity. Awarding damages is a possible remedy or outcome of civil litigation. Due process involves presenting evidence, not creating it. SOURCE: BL:070 SOURCE: Farlex, Inc. (2016). Due process of law. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://legaldictionary.thefreedictionary.com/due+process+of+law "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Which of the following statements is true regarding joint ventures: ", "choices": ["A. Large corporations are the only business structures that can benefit from joint ventures.", "B. Joint ventures are used only when it is necessary to raise a lot of capital.", "C. Joint venture arrangements are usually short-term relationships.", "D. An independent attorney must always be consulted before signing a joint venture agreement."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Joint venture arrangements are usually short-term relationships. A joint venture is an arrangement that involves two or more businesses entering into a relationship by combining complementary resources such as technology, skills, capital, or distribution channels for the benefit of all parties. The relationship is usually short-term and involves the execution of a single project or transaction. A joint-venture arrangement can be used by virtually any type and size of business. Although it is a good idea to have an attorney draw up or review a contractual agreement between both parties, it is not usually required in the United States. SOURCE: BL:003 SOURCE: BL LAP 1\u2014Own It Your Way (Types of Business Ownership) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Providing marketing information is an important channel activity. Businesses rely on marketing information to determine ", "choices": ["A. their target markets' needs and wants.", "B. how intermediaries are performing.", "C. how much to charge for their products.", "D. what to name their products."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Their target markets' needs and wants. Businesses rely on marketing information to determine their target markets' needs and wants. Intermediaries are often able to provide producers with valuable marketing information since they deal with final consumers more closely. Marketing information may or may not help businesses determine how intermediaries are performing, how much to charge for their products, or what to name their products. SOURCE: CM:001 SOURCE: CM LAP 2\u2014Chart Your Channels (Channel Management) "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Which of the following is a benefit of channels of distribution: ", "choices": ["A. Producers must spend more money.", "B. We can more easily obtain products from all over the world.", "C. Retailers must spend more money.", "D. We spend more time looking for products we want."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "We can more easily obtain products from all over the world. Channels of distribution allow consumers, industrial users, producers, and other channel intermediaries to save time and money. They also allow us to more easily obtain products from all over the world, since we do not have to travel and search for each individual item we wish to purchase. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: CM LAP 3\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "A manufacturer that has 65% of the market share is pressuring its wholesalers to sign an agreement stating that they will not sell competing products. In this situation, the agreement is illegal because it ", "choices": ["A. controls resale prices.", "B. prohibits monopolies.", "C. violates antitrust laws.", "D. limits producers' rights."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Violates antitrust laws. In this situation, the manufacturer is engaging in exclusive dealing, which is a distribution strategy that forbids dealers from carrying the competitors' products. This strategy is usually considered illegal because it restricts competition. And because the manufacturer holds a majority of the market share, it violates antitrust laws and has the potential to create a monopoly. Exclusive dealing agreements are legal in certain situations, such as a franchisor requiring a franchisee to sell only the franchisor's products. There is not enough information to determine if the manufacturer is controlling resale prices. The manufacturer's actions may limit other producers' ability to fairly compete in the market place, but it is not limiting their rights to seek legal recourse. SOURCE: CM:005 SOURCE: Thomson Reuters. (2016). What is antitrust law and trade regulation? Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://hirealawyer.findlaw.com/choosing-the-right-lawyer/antitrust-and-traderegulation.html "}, {"number": 7, "question": "A producer can minimize channel conflict among its distributors and retailers by ", "choices": ["A. offering different products through each channel.", "B. selling its items directly to the end users.", "C. establishing slotting fees for certain channels.", "D. requesting that the channel members carry only its brand."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Offering different products through each channel. Channel conflict can occur when channel members are competing among themselves for customers. When each channel sells different products, they are not directly competing among themselves for business. For example, if a guitar manufacturer sells its line of guitars through authorized distributors and sells accessories for the guitars through online retailers, the channel members are not competing for the customers because they are selling different products. Bypassing channel members and selling directly to end users, establishing slotting fees, and requesting channel members to carry only its brand are actions that tend to create channel conflict rather than minimize it. SOURCE: CM:008 SOURCE: Perreault, W.D., Cannon, J.P., & McCarthy, E.J. (2008). Basic marketing: A marketing strategy planning approach (16th ed.) [pp. 298-301]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Which of the following is a leading question: ", "choices": ["A. Mia is a great manager, isn't she?", "B. How was your weekend?", "C. What did you discuss in the meeting?", "D. What are you having for lunch?"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Mia is a great manager, isn't she? Leading questions \u201clead\u201d the answerer into giving a certain response. When you ask \u201cMia is a great manager, isn't she?\u201d you are leading someone into agreeing with you. \u201cHow was your weekend?\u201d, \u201cWhat did you discuss in the meeting?\u201d, and \u201cWhat are you having for lunch?\u201d are all open questions. SOURCE: CO:058 SOURCE: MindTools. (1996-2016). Questioning techniques: Asking questions effectively. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/newTMC_88.htm "}, {"number": 9, "question": "During a brainstorming session, should participants be allowed to add new ideas to the list that are based on another group member's idea? ", "choices": ["A. Yes, because ideas that are too outrageous should be immediately modified", "B. No, because using someone else's idea is considered stealing", "C. No, because it can be interpreted as a poor evaluation of the idea", "D. Yes, because other participants' ideas can trigger new ideas"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Yes, because other participants' ideas can trigger new ideas. This process is called steppingstones or triggers, and it is encouraged in brainstorming because one person's ideas can easily trigger new and different ideas. It is not considered stealing, but instead is an important part of working together to build on each other\u2019s ideas to find more ideas. Adding a steppingstone idea to a brainstorming list is not a form of evaluating the original ideas. All ideas are considered equal in a brainstorming session, including those that are very outlandish or outrageous. SOURCE: CO:061 SOURCE: DuBrin, A. (2010). Leadership: Research findings, practice, and skills (6th ed.) [pp. 326-328]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 10, "question": "When businesses need to formalize the information provided to employees, customers, or other businesses, they often use __________ communication. ", "choices": ["A. written", "B. lateral", "C. upward", "D. verbal"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Written. Written communication involves putting ideas, thoughts, and agreements into words and writing those words in a document or letter. Written communication is often considered to be formal because a copy of the information exists which indicates that all parties involved received the same message. Businesses often use formal written communication in order to document important transactions and preserve the information for future reference. Verbal communication involves speaking. Lateral communication is between people on the same level. Upward communication is from employees to supervisors or managers. SOURCE: CO:016 SOURCE: Inc. (2016). Written communication. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.inc.com/encyclopedia/written-communication.html Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 11, "question": "What is one reason why businesses write informational messages? ", "choices": ["A. To analyze sales proposals", "B. To develop research reports", "C. To explain new policies", "D. To obtain positive feedback"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To explain new policies. One of the main functions of an informational message is to provide information to readers in such a way that they understand the message. A type of written information that businesses often provide to customers is an explanation of new policies and how those policies will affect customers. For example, if a business is changing its credit policy, it wants to inform customers about the change and let them know that the change will benefit them. Research reports are an in-depth study of a specific business problem or situation. Businesses write informational messages to inform rather than to obtain feedback. Analyzing sales proposals involves reviewing information. SOURCE: CO:039 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 230-233]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 12, "question": "Because Caroline does not have enough time to read an entire 400-page business report, what section of the report should she review to obtain an overview of the most important content? ", "choices": ["A. Appendices", "B. Table of contents", "C. Executive summary", "D. Conclusions"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Executive summary. The executive summary provides an overview of the entire report and contains the most important information included in the body of the report. When businesspeople have time constraints, they often read the executive summary of a lengthy report. The table of contents is the portion of the report in which the various report sections are listed with their page numbers for easy access. The appendices are segments that are added to the end of the report and provide supporting information. The conclusion section of the report summarizes results and in some reports, this section includes recommendations for a certain course of action. SOURCE: CO:091 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 456, 461, 474]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 13, "question": "Which of the following is a type of simple written report that usually is distributed to employees within a business: ", "choices": ["A. Newsletter", "B. Proposal", "C. Handbook", "D. Memorandum"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Memorandum. Memorandums are a frequently used form of brief, written communication exchanged by people within a business. Memorandums often are distributed to employees within a business to update them on the progress of various projects, or inform them of changes in policies and procedures. They are informal and simple because they are intended only for the use of the business's employees. A proposal usually is a complex written report that is formal and may be distributed to those outside the business. Handbooks and newsletters are internal company publications, but they are not memorandums. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri, C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [p. 451]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co. "}, {"number": 14, "question": "When taking notes during a seminar, a businessperson should write down ", "choices": ["A. all details.", "B. information of interest.", "C. inaccurate statements.", "D. key points."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Key points. Effective note-taking involves writing down the most important information or key points for future reference. A person generally speaks faster than another person writes, so it would be difficult for a person to write down every detail or word the speaker says. The key points cited during a seminar may or may not be of interest to the businessperson. Inaccurate statements should not be cited during a seminar. SOURCE: CO:085 SOURCE: Sauk Valley Community College. (n.d.). Effective note-taking methods. Retrieved September 30, 2016, from https://www.svcc.edu/students/success/workshops-pdf/note-taking.pdf "}, {"number": 15, "question": "A customer has purchased an item from you and is now faced with carrying six packages. You can use a practical idea to create positive customer relations by ", "choices": ["A. wishing the customer luck in carrying all the packages.", "B. thanking the customer for making so many purchases.", "C. offering to place all the packages in one large bag.", "D. complimenting the customer for getting a lot accomplished."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Offering to place all the packages in one large bag. Offering assistance that will make the customer's shopping easier is a practical technique for creating positive relationships with customers. Thanking the customer, extending a compliment, or wishing the customer luck are positive approaches, but they do not provide the practical help the customer needs. SOURCE: CR:003 SOURCE: Help Scout. (2016). 15 customer service skills that every employee needs. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from https://www.helpscout.net/blog/customer-service-skills/ Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 16, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an employee using nonverbal communication effectively to reinforce his/her service orientation: ", "choices": ["A. When Mrs. Jones complained that her steak was not cooked the way she wanted it, Leah rolled\nher eyes.", "B. Molly nodded and maintained eye contact as Ms. West explained the problem with her computer.", "C. Tristan answered his office telephone and said, \u201cBlanton Industries. How can I help you?\u201d", "D. Paul crossed his arms and tapped his foot impatiently as Mr. Cook asked about a charge on his"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Molly nodded and maintained eye contact as Ms. West explained the problem with her computer. Having a service orientation involves expressing a positive, helpful attitude with the business's customers. Employees' gestures and facial expressions convey their attitudes, which customers often believe is a reflection of the business's attitudes. Because Molly nodded and maintained eye contact with Ms. West while she was explaining a computer problem, Molly was indicating that she was listening and willing to help her customer. Employees are not exhibiting a service orientation by behaving rudely, which may include rolling their eyes, crossing their arms, and being impatient with customers. Tristan was demonstrating a service orientation through his verbal rather than his nonverbal communication. SOURCE: CR:005 SOURCE: Skills You Need. (2016). Non-verbal communication. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.skillsyouneed.com/ips/nonverbal-communication.html "}, {"number": 17, "question": "A grocery store keeps track of customers' purchases through their loyalty cards. This is an example of ", "choices": ["A. data encryption.", "B. illegal data collection.", "C. data security.", "D. big data."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Big data. A grocery store keeping track of customers' purchases through their loyalty cards is an example of big data. Big data are large amounts of information automatically collected through electronic sources. Collecting data this way is not illegal. This is not an example of data security (keeping information safe and private) or data encryption (transforming information into a secret code). SOURCE: CR:017 SOURCE: CR LAP 17\u2014Trust Is a Must (Ethics in Customer Relationship Management) "}, {"number": 18, "question": "When a manufacturer asks a business to collect information from customers concerning how to improve a product, which type of utility is most likely to be affected? ", "choices": ["A. Possession", "B. Place", "C. Time", "D. Form"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Form. Form utility is the usefulness created by changing the shape of a good to make it more useful to customers. Manufacturers can create form utility by changing their products according to the marketresearch information from customers. Place utility is usefulness created by making sure that goods and services are available at a place where they are needed or wanted by customers. Time utility is usefulness created when products are made available at the time they are needed or wanted by customers. Possession utility is usefulness created when ownership of a product is transferred from seller to user. SOURCE: EC:004 SOURCE: EC LAP 13\u2014Use It (Economic Utility) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "In a market economic system, who owns most of the means of production of goods and services? ", "choices": ["A. Entrepreneurs", "B. Political parties", "C. Businesses and individuals", "D. Government"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Businesses and individuals. They decide what and how products will be produced. The government has regulatory powers to make sure that products are safe. Political parties support candidates for public office. Entrepreneurs are individuals who assume the risk of starting and operating a business. SOURCE: EC:007 SOURCE: EC LAP 17\u2014Who's the Boss? (Economic Systems) "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Research and development speed up production by ", "choices": ["A. providing employees with adequate job training.", "B. simplifying existing products.", "C. limiting inflation.", "D. reviewing company goals with employees."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Simplifying existing products. Researchers can speed up production by simplifying existing products, developing new products, and determining better processes. Management should provide employees with adequate job training. Overall, national productivity can limit inflation. Communication between management and labor involves reviewing company goals with employees. SOURCE: EC:013 SOURCE: EC LAP 18\u2014Make the Most of It (Productivity) "}, {"number": 21, "question": "If total cost is $3,000 with zero quantity produced and $6,500 with 1,000 items produced, what is the marginal cost of producing each item? ", "choices": ["A. $3.50", "B. $3.00", "C. $6.50", "D. $1.00"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "$3.50. Marginal cost is the change in cost involved in increasing or decreasing production. It is often used to calculate the extra cost of producing one more item. In this situation, total cost of operating the business is $3,000 before any items are produced. Once production begins, there are additional costs. To determine the marginal cost of producing each additional item, first calculate the change in total cost by subtracting the total cost before production from the total cost once production begins ($6,500 - $3,000 = $3,500). The change in total cost is $3,500 from zero production to producing 1,000 items. To calculate marginal cost, divide the change in total cost by the number of items produced ($3,500 \u00f7 1,000 = $3.50). SOURCE: EC:023 SOURCE: EC LAP 31\u2014Know Your Limits (Law of Diminishing Returns) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 22, "question": "According to the Keynesian theory of unemployment, the best solution for unemployment is to ", "choices": ["A. keep prices the same.", "B. cut wages.", "C. increase demand.", "D. increase inflation."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Increase demand. According to the Keynesian theory of unemployment, the best solution for unemployment is to increase demand and encourage spending. This will increase businesses' production and allow them to retain and hire more workers. For Keynesian economists, keeping prices the same, increasing inflation, and cutting wages are not preferred solutions for unemployment. SOURCE: EC:082 SOURCE: EC LAP 29\u2014Help Wanted? (Impact of Unemployment Rates) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Which of the following is considered an external cause of business cycles: ", "choices": ["A. Climatic changes", "B. Aggregate demand", "C. Money supply", "D. Inventory levels"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Climatic changes. Some factors are considered external causes of business cycles because they occur outside the economic system. Many jobs in agriculture and construction vary according to climatic conditions. Droughts, floods, and blizzards can negatively affect many economic activities. Other external factors are political changes, psychological changes, international relations, and discoveries and innovations. Aggregate demand, money supply, and inventory levels are considered internal causes of business cycles because they take place within the economic system. SOURCE: EC:018 SOURCE: EC LAP 9\u2014Boom or Bust (Impact of Business Cycles) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "Levels of inflation and unemployment are factors that affect __________ in the world market. ", "choices": ["A. communication", "B. specialization", "C. satisfaction", "D. competition"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Competition. Global competition is the rivalry between nations to attract a share of the world market. Levels of inflation and unemployment are factors that make the products of nations more or less competitive with each other. Communication between countries is not affected by inflation and unemployment. Specialization is making the best use of resources in the production of goods and services. Satisfaction is a state of contentment. SOURCE: EC:016 SOURCE: EC LAP 4\u2014Beyond US (Global Trade) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "A nation's currency exchange rate is likely to increase when ", "choices": ["A. the labor force shrinks.", "B. consumer confidence is high.", "C. an economic contraction occurs.", "D. stock values fluctuate."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Consumer confidence is high. When consumers have confidence in a nation's economy, the currency exchange rate is likely to increase. During an economic contraction, unemployment increases, and consumer confidence and the strength of the economy decrease. Quick, dramatic changes in stock values can affect a nation's currency exchange rate; however, stock values tend to fluctuate slightly in a strong economy, so this may not have a great impact on the currency exchange rate. SOURCE: EC:100 SOURCE: Van Bergen, J. (2016, February 25). 6 factors that influence exchange rates. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.investopedia.com/articles/basics/04/050704.asp "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Knowing your personal strengths and weaknesses helps you to ", "choices": ["A. ask others for input about your strengths and abilities.", "B. identify potential strengths and weaknesses in others.", "C. make informed decisions about your future.", "D. perform well on a skills assessment test."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Make informed decisions about your future. By knowing your strengths\u2014things you enjoy and do well\u2014 as well as your weaknesses, you can make better decisions about your future. For example, you might determine that you are artistic and enjoy drawing but have a hard time with math. When it is time to determine your career path, you might decide to become a graphic artist rather than a financial planner. By knowing yourself, you select a career that focuses on your strengths rather than your weaknesses, indicating that you are making a thoughtful, informed decision about your future. Identifying others' strengths and weaknesses does not help you identify your own strengths and weaknesses. Asking others for input about your abilities is one way in which you can identify your strengths and weaknesses. A skills assessment test is not about performing well or getting a good grade; rather, it is another way in which you can identify your strengths and weaknesses. SOURCE: EI:002 SOURCE: EI LAP 17\u2014Assess for Success (Assessing Personal Strengths and Weaknesses) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "A responsible employee is one who is able to __________ his/her mistakes. ", "choices": ["A. conceal", "B. avoid", "C. admit", "D. maximize"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Admit. A responsible employee recognizes his/her mistakes and readily admits them. Concealing a mistake may compound the problem. Some mistakes cannot be avoided, but they should not be maximized. SOURCE: EI:021 SOURCE: EI LAP 21\u2014Make the Honor Role (Acting Responsibly) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 28, "question": "Which of the following responses to a difficult situation would damage your professional image: ", "choices": ["A. Using inappropriate language", "B. Listening without interrupting", "C. Showing empathy toward others", "D. Controlling your facial expression"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Using inappropriate language. Using any type of bad language is not only likely to offend the person to whom you are speaking, it will also damage your professional image. All of the other alternatives are ways in which you can exhibit self-control. SOURCE: EI:025 SOURCE: EI LAP 14\u2014Control Yourself! (Demonstrating Self-Control) "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Businesses should view negotiation as a way to ", "choices": ["A. get the action they want.", "B. get something done.", "C. build strong relationships.", "D. keep negative people quiet."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Build strong relationships. Negotiation can be a means of strengthening long-term relationships with customers, suppliers, coworkers, and other businesses. Negotiation demands a spirit of cooperation. Entering negotiation with the idea of getting a certain action, keeping negative people quiet, or getting something done will not produce a situation that allows everyone to feel they have gained through the process. SOURCE: EI:062 SOURCE: EI LAP 8\u2014Make It a Win-Win (Negotiation in Business) "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Which of the following could make it difficult for you to believe that your needs are as important as the needs of others: ", "choices": ["A. You have developed a lot of self-respect.", "B. You choose your own behavior.", "C. You are an assertive person.", "D. You are often around aggressive people."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "You are often around aggressive people. Aggressive people can make it difficult for you to believe that your needs are as important as the needs of others because aggressive people believe their needs are more important than anyone else's. Being assertive, choosing your own behavior, and having a lot of self-respect should help you to believe in the importance of your own needs. SOURCE: EI:008 SOURCE: EI LAP 18\u2014Assert Yourself (Assertiveness) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Matthew and Miranda are equal partners in a small consulting firm. They have allocated eight percent of last year's profits to make business improvements. Matthew wants to purchase a new copy machine, while Miranda would rather paint the building and make it look more inviting to their clients. What is the reason for Matthew and Miranda's conflict? ", "choices": ["A. Inconsistent behavior", "B. Unclear boundaries", "C. Limited resources", "D. Authority"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Limited resources. In this situation, Matthew and Miranda were disagreeing about how to spend a set amount of money, which is a limited resource. Matthew and Miranda are equal partners in the firm, so the disagreement did not involve questioning or wanting authority. There is no indication of inconsistent or unclear boundaries. SOURCE: EI:015 SOURCE: EI LAP 7\u2014Stop the Madness (Conflict Resolution in Business) "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Which of the following coaching characteristics means that you are willing to admit your mistakes: ", "choices": ["A. Approachability", "B. Dependability", "C. Patience", "D. Humility"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Humility. Humility is a coaching characteristic that includes a willingness to admit your mistakes. A humble attitude earns respect and trust from people being coached. Dependability means being the type of person others can count on. Patience means that you don't get frustrated or give up on your coachee. Approachability means that you have the type of attitude and demeanor that lets people know you're always there to help. SOURCE: EI:041 SOURCE: EI LAP 24\u2014Bring Out the Best (Coaching Others) "}, {"number": 33, "question": "Shayla has a coworker who is from another country. Shayla and her coworker also have different religious backgrounds. Which of the following actions should Shayla take: ", "choices": ["A. Accept her coworker and learn about the coworker's religion.", "B. Focus on the differences, not the similarities, between them.", "C. Avoid talking to the coworker so as not to offend her.", "D. Take a negative attitude toward their differences."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Accept her coworker and learn about the coworker's religion. Valuing differences means accepting people who are different and learning from them. Shayla can accept her coworker and use this as an opportunity to learn about the coworker's religion. Shayla should not avoid talking to the coworker\u2014this is disrespectful. She should take a positive, not negative, approach to their differences. SOURCE: EI:036 SOURCE: EI LAP 36\u2014Everyone's Worthy (Treating Others With Dignity and Respect) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 34, "question": "When employees' personal interests become more important than achieving the company's overall goals, informal political relationships might form, which often cause organizational ", "choices": ["A. integration.", "B. unity.", "C. utility.", "D. conflict."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Conflict. A conflict is a disagreement. It is common for informal relationships (e.g., friendships) to form among coworkers and management in the workplace. Problems can occur when employees become more interested in personal interests, such as getting promotions or making certain changes, and lose focus of the company's overall goals. When these situations occur, informal relationships become more important because the employees often seek support from like-minded coworkers, which can decrease corporate unity and create conflict within the entire organization. Utility is the usefulness of something or the capability of something to satisfy wants and needs. Integration means to bring two different groups or things together. SOURCE: EI:034 SOURCE: How Stuff Works. (2016). How office politics work. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://money.howstuffworks.com/office-politics.htm "}, {"number": 35, "question": "John recently expanded his business into another country to reach more of his target market. He was initially thrilled with his company's profits following the expansion\u2014until he converted the money back to his domestic currency. At that point, he realized that the company made much less than he originally thought. What risk involved with international business did John experience? ", "choices": ["A. Political unrest in foreign countries", "B. International trade agreement changes", "C. Foreign exchange rate fluctuations", "D. The cost of international unionized labor"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Foreign exchange rate fluctuations. Foreign exchange rate risk occurs when the value of an investment fluctuates due to changes in a currency's exchange rate. When a domestic currency appreciates against a foreign currency, profits earned in the foreign country will decrease after being exchanged back to the domestic currency. John's profits were greater in the foreign currency than in domestic currency because of fluctuations in the exchange rate between the two currencies. International trade agreements, political unrest, and the cost of international unionized labor are all factors that business owners should consider before engaging in international business, but John did not experience them in this situation. SOURCE: EN:041 SOURCE: Sargeant, N. (2016). What risks do organizations face when engaging in international finance activities? Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/06/internationalfinancerisks.asp "}, {"number": 36, "question": "What form of currency is issued by the federal government? ", "choices": ["A. Corporate bonds", "B. Brokerage bills", "C. Paper money", "D. Certified notes"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Paper money. Currency is the paper or metal (coin) money that individuals and businesses use to buy and sell goods and services. Paper money and coins are issued by a country's government. Corporate bonds are bonds issued by corporations to fund operating expenses. Governments do not issue brokerage bills, and certified notes are not forms of currency. SOURCE: FI:059 SOURCE: Giese, B. (2013, July 15). World paper money: How many countries currently issue paper money? Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://stason.org/TULARC/recreation/papermoney/4-6-World-Paper-Money-How-many-countries-currently-issue-p.html "}, {"number": 37, "question": "An advantage to retailers of offering credit is that credit customers ", "choices": ["A. spend more time deciding to buy.", "B. have little effect on store profits.", "C. always pay their accounts promptly.", "D. often buy impulse items more freely."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Often buy impulse items more freely. Credit encourages customers to buy more freely. Credit customers like being able to buy without worrying about whether they have the cash on hand to pay for their purchases. As a result, they may buy impulse items that catch their attention. Store profit is affected by credit customers, who often spend less time making buying decisions than other customers. Credit accounts are not always paid on time, and, for the retailer, collecting past-due accounts is a disadvantage of the credit system. SOURCE: FI:002 SOURCE: FI LAP 2\u2014Give Credit Where Credit Is Due (Credit and Its Importance) "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Each year, Marla must pay a certain percentage of the value of her home to the local government. Which of the following is the tax liability Marla is responsible for paying: ", "choices": ["A. Sales", "B. Excise", "C. Property", "D. Income"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Property. Tax liability is the amount of money that people owe and must pay to the government. Property taxes are monies that local governments collect from homeowners. The value of the home and the property the home sits upon is a consideration when determining the homeowner's property tax liability. Excise taxes are sales taxes on specific goods such as gasoline, cigarettes, and alcohol. Governments collect sales tax for purchases and income tax on money that a person earns. SOURCE: FI:067 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., & Hughes, R.J. (2009). Personal finance (9th ed.) [p. 104]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 39, "question": "A manager looks at financial information to see if the company can afford to purchase a popular new item it wants to add to its shelves. This is an example of using financial information to ", "choices": ["A. manage debt.", "B. increase sales.", "C. check up on the competition.", "D. reduce expenses."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Increase sales. Businesses often want to add new products to their offerings as a way to increase sales. They need to study financial information to make sure they can afford to do so. Adding new products is not managing debt, checking up on the competition, or reducing expenses. SOURCE: FI:579 SOURCE: FI LAP 9\u2014By the Numbers (The Need for Financial Information) "}, {"number": 40, "question": "Accounting computer software programs increase the efficiency of accounting activities because they are used to ", "choices": ["A. track payroll activities and develop annual reports.", "B. create invoices and record customer payments.", "C. monitor market share and summarize accounts payable data.", "D. organize tax records and produce presentations."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Create invoices and record customer payments. Accounting software programs perform a variety of accounting activities that streamline accounting processes, which makes them more efficient. Accounting software allows businesses to create invoices, record customer payments, track payroll activities, summarize accounts payable, and organize tax records. Businesses use word-processing software to produce annual reports and presentation software to produce visual aids for presentations. Businesses do not use accounting software to monitor market share. SOURCE: FI:352 SOURCE: Garen, K. (2010, December 3). Top 11 accounting technology productivity features. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.accountingweb.com/technology/accountingsoftware/top-11-accounting-technology-productivity-features "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Which of the following is categorized as owner's equity on a company's balance sheet: ", "choices": ["A. Inventory", "B. Accounts receivable", "C. Retained earnings", "D. Capital equipment"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Retained earnings. A balance sheet is a financial statement that captures the financial condition of the business at that particular moment. Owner's equity is the amount an owner has invested in the business plus or minus profits and losses. Retained earnings are a component of owner's equity because they are the income left after paying dividends to stockholders. Inventory and accounts receivable are categorized as current or short-term assets on a balance sheet because the levels of inventory and income from sales tend to fluctuate. Capital equipment, buildings, and vehicles are listed as long-term assets on a balance sheet because they are assets that generate revenue for more than a year. SOURCE: FI:093 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 73). South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 42, "question": "A commission or bonus is an example of a form of ", "choices": ["A. compensation.", "B. assistance program.", "C. benefit.", "D. employee contract."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Compensation. A commission or bonus is an example of a form of compensation. Compensation is pay for work completed. It comes in different forms for different employees. Some make an hourly wage; others, a yearly salary. Compensation may also include certain financial incentives, such as commissions or bonuses. HR management oversees compensation and benefits for all employees. Benefits are advantages employees receive in addition to their monetary compensation, such as health insurance, retirement accounts, paid vacation and sick time, etc. Employee contracts may include terms involving commission or bonuses, but these forms of compensation are not types of contracts. Employeeassistance programs do not involve compensation. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: HR LAP 35\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Which of the following is a product strategy that marketers devise using available data: ", "choices": ["A. What level of customer service to provide", "B. Where to sell the product", "C. What advertisements to run", "D. How much to charge"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "What level of customer service to provide. There are many decisions that marketers must make about products, including choosing what products to offer, what new products to develop, and what level of customer service to provide with each product. Where to sell the product is a place decision. What advertisements to run is a promotional decision. How much to charge is a pricing decision. SOURCE: IM:012 SOURCE: IM LAP 12\u2014Data Do It (Need for Marketing Data) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Which of the following is the most important reason for creating a written plan for a marketing-research project: ", "choices": ["A. To make it easy to analyze the data collected", "B. To implement the marketing concept", "C. To keep the project from going over budget", "D. To keep the project on track"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To keep the project on track. Creating a written plan for the research helps to keep the project on track as to types and amounts of data to be collected. A written plan also ensures that both the business and the research have the same information. The amount budgeted for research should be stated in the written plan, but that is not the most important reason for putting the plan in writing. A written plan does not affect data analysis or help the business to implement the marketing concept\u2014a philosophy of doing business that is based on satisfying customer wants and needs while achieving company goals. SOURCE: IM:010 SOURCE: IM LAP 10\u2014Seek and Find (Marketing Research) "}, {"number": 45, "question": "A marketer is having difficulty finding data about a competitor because the competitor's financial records have not been made public. Which disadvantage of secondary research does this situation illustrate? ", "choices": ["A. It can be incomplete.", "B. It can be out of date.", "C. It can be costly.", "D. It can be time-consuming."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "It can be incomplete. Secondary research can be incomplete. In this case, the marketer is unable to find all the data s/he wants about a competitor because the full picture simply isn't available. Secondary data can be out of date, but that isn't the disadvantage being illustrated in this example. Secondary research is neither costly nor time-consuming\u2014those are disadvantages of primary research. SOURCE: IM:281 SOURCE: IM LAP 15\u2014What's the Source? (Obtaining Marketing-Research Data) "}, {"number": 46, "question": "A company wants to collect information from various sources to determine if it should consider expanding to international markets. What research method should the company use, if it does not want to spend a lot of time or money to obtain the information? ", "choices": ["A. Interview", "B. Causal", "C. Experimental", "D. Exploratory"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Exploratory. Exploratory research involves collecting information to help the business define its issue, situation, or concern, and decide how to proceed with its research. Causal or conclusive research focuses on cause and effect and tests \u201cwhat if\u201d theories. Interviews are conversations in which a researcher surveys an individual to obtain research data. An experiment is a research method that tests \u201ccause and effect\u201d by test marketing new products or comparing test groups with control groups. SOURCE: IM:284 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 50-54]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Simon wants to know how well his company did last quarter in relation to other companies in its industry. He needs to conduct a ", "choices": ["A. sales volume analysis.", "B. market share analysis.", "C. SWOT analysis.", "D. customer analysis."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Market share analysis. If Simon wants to know how well his company did last quarter in relation to other companies in its industry, he needs to conduct a market share analysis. This tool uses sales data to measure a company's sales performance against that of its competitors. Sales volume analysis uses sales data to measure actual sales against any number of different criteria. SWOT analysis measures a company's strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats. A customer analysis would focus on customers or potential customers, not sales. SOURCE: IM:184 SOURCE: IM LAP 184\u2014Data Diving (Identifying Marketing Data) "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Which of the following is a form of qualitative research: ", "choices": ["A. Sampling", "B. Online survey", "C. Experiment", "D. Focus group"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Focus group. Qualitative research involves collecting data that include opinions and personal interpretations. A focus group is a method that researchers use to collect qualitative data. Businesses often hold focus groups to obtain customers' opinions about their goods and services. Online surveys and experiments are methods of collecting quantitative data. Sampling is the process of choosing a representative group of consumers to survey. SOURCE: IM:289 SOURCE: Power Decisions Group. (2016). Qualitative marketing research versus quantitative methods and tools. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.powerdecisions.com/FAQ-qualitativemarket-research.shtml "}, {"number": 49, "question": "The process of coding is part of which step of the marketing research process? ", "choices": ["A. Analysis", "B. Collection", "C. Presentation", "D. Preparation"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Analysis. Coding is a process which assigns a score to each response within a data set. This is done to make analysis easier. Collecting data includes processes like conducting surveys. Presentation is the step where the conclusions of the research are presented to the business so that the business can act upon the results of the research. Preparation is the step where questions for the surveys are chosen, the sample size is chosen, and the method of data collection is decided upon. SOURCE: IM:062 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [p. 491]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 50, "question": "The following appeared on a recent survey: \"Do you agree that the government wastes taxpayers' money by supporting unnecessary programs?\" This is an example of a(n) ", "choices": ["A. indifferent statement.", "B. leading question.", "C. open-ended inquiry.", "D. unstated alternative."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Leading question. Leading questions tend to influence the respondents' answers and create bias, which skews results. Because words such as \"wastes\" and \"unnecessary programs\" tend to generate strong emotional reactions and overall negative views about the topic, the survey question is biased. The question is a closed-ended question because it requires a \"yes\" or \"no\" answer. The situation does not exemplify an indifferent statement, an open-ended inquiry, or an unstated alternative. SOURCE: IM:293 SOURCE: Churchill, G.A., Brown, T.J., & Suter, T.A. (2010). Basic marketing research (7th ed.) [pp. 302-303]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 51, "question": "What is the benefit of clearly stating a research problem or issue? ", "choices": ["A. It determines the sample size needed for the marketing research project.", "B. It helps to keep marketing research focused and relevant.", "C. It determines the findings of the marketing research project.", "D. It helps the researcher to determine whether a short- or long-term study is needed."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It helps to keep marketing research focused and relevant. A clear definition as to the research objective or problem is essential. Stated clearly, it serves as a guide to keeping marketing research focused and relevant. Without a clearly defined objective or problem, any research done will have unnecessary waste and unclear results. The problem or objective does not determine the needed sample size or the study's length. The research findings should result from implementation of the scientific method in the research process. Pre-determining the findings violates proper research methodology. SOURCE: IM:428 SOURCE: Kinard, D. (2009, February 22). Marketability. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://davidkinard.blogspot.com/2009/02/7-characteristics-of-good-marketing.html "}, {"number": 52, "question": "When all employees are on the \u201csame page\u201d and working toward a common goal, businesses tend to be more ", "choices": ["A. negative.", "B. ethical.", "C. popular.", "D. efficient."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Efficient. When all employees are on the \"same page\" and working toward a common goal, businesses tend to be more efficient. This is a positive result that occurs when positive actions, such as communicating honestly, are taken. These actions do not necessarily result in a more ethical, negative, or popular business. SOURCE: MK:019 SOURCE: MK LAP 3\u2014Just Do It...Right (Company Actions and Results) "}, {"number": 53, "question": "Jackie is interested in predicting what special events result in higher demand for chocolate candy. She should conduct behavioral segmentation based on ", "choices": ["A. benefits derived.", "B. rate of use.", "C. occasion response.", "D. loyalty response."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Occasion response. Dividing customers into groups based on their responses to a product is behavioral segmentation. Customers are grouped into categories according to what they are looking for in a product and why they buy the product. By studying the occasion responses of customers (when they purchase a product, especially for an event such as a wedding, birthday, graduation, etc.), marketers can predict what special events result in demand for products. Segmentation on the basis of usage rate classifies customers as heavy, moderate, light, or nonusers of a product. Customers can also be classified based on the benefits they desire from a product or the devotion and loyalty they feel for a product. SOURCE: MP:003 SOURCE: MP LAP 3\u2014Have We Met? (Market Identification) "}, {"number": 54, "question": "If a situation analysis reveals that the company has a comprehensive, current, and flexible database system, it has identified a(n) ", "choices": ["A. product benefit.", "B. external asset.", "C. internal strength.", "D. technological flaw."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Internal strength. A situation analysis is a determination of a company's current business situation and the direction in which it is headed. A comprehensive situation analysis involves evaluating the internal and external circumstances that are currently affecting the business environment. Conducting a situation analysis helps the company make business decisions that make the most of its strengths, such as maintaining a comprehensive, current, and flexible database. Companies can also use the situation analysis to improve internal weaknesses and adjust to external challenges. A comprehensive, current, and flexible database system is not an external asset, product benefit, or technological flaw. SOURCE: MP:008 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [pp. 43-44]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement regarding how economic conditions may affect a business's sales forecast: ", "choices": ["A. Economic conditions have very little impact on sales forecasts.", "B. A poor economy will hurt sales for some businesses but will help others.", "C. A poor economy will decrease sales for all types of businesses.", "D. A strong economy will increase sales for all types of businesses."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "A poor economy will hurt sales for some businesses but will help others. It isn't true that a poor economy decreases sales for all types of businesses. For some businesses, such as those that sell do-it-yourself supplies, a poor economy can actually boost sales. A strong economy doesn't necessarily increase sales for every type of business. Economic conditions have a considerable impact on sales forecasts. SOURCE: MP:013 SOURCE: MP LAP 5\u2014Futurecast (The Nature of Sales Forecasts) "}, {"number": 56, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement regarding information management: ", "choices": ["A. It's used primarily for decision making.", "B. It's necessary for making even small business decisions.", "C. It's the same thing as MIS.", "D. It's the same thing as data processing."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It's necessary for making even small business decisions. Information management is important for business decision making, even for small decisions. It isn't used primarily for decision making, though\u2014 there are many other uses for information management. Information management is not the same thing as MIS or data processing. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: NF LAP 110\u2014In the Know (Nature of Information Management) "}, {"number": 57, "question": "Which of the following is an important component of computer systems: ", "choices": ["A. Website", "B. Internet", "C. Software", "D. E-commerce"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Software. Software instructs computers to perform specific operations. The various types of software are important components of computer systems because they allow computers to do the work that businesses want them to do. For example, spreadsheet software programs enable computers to analyze financial data, calculate budget information, and create charts and graphs of numeric data. The Internet, websites, and e-commerce are not components of computer systems. SOURCE: NF:084 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 254). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Which of the following is a computer-based time-management tool that helps employees keep track of their appointments and activities: ", "choices": ["A. Alarm clock", "B. Perpetual calendar", "C. Instant-messaging program", "D. Electronic task organizer"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Electronic task organizer. Electronic task organizers and calendars help employees keep track of their appointments and tasks, which help them be more efficient, organized, and productive workers. Spreadsheet software programs record and calculate numerical data. Instant-messaging programs allow Internet users to communicate in real time. Perpetual calendars and alarm clocks may not be computerbased. SOURCE: NF:005 SOURCE: Hein, R. (2013, April 18). 9 top iPhone and iPad productivity and time management apps. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.networkworld.com/article/2357942/smb/96495- 9-Top-iPhone-and-iPad-Productivity-and-Time-Management-Apps.html "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following types of software programs would an employee use to prepare a form letter informing the company's clients of a change in product pricing: ", "choices": ["A. Database", "B. Spreadsheet", "C. Presentation", "D. Word processing"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Word processing. Word-processing software programs are used to create documents that are primarily text but may contain some graphics. Database and spreadsheet programs are used to organize and analyze different types of data. Presentation software programs are used to develop visual presentations. SOURCE: NF:007 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 199). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 60, "question": "When creating web pages, a business should be sure to include a __________ the home page. ", "choices": ["A. reason for", "B. picture on", "C. summary of", "D. link to"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Link to. A business's website usually contains several pages so specialized information can be explained in more detail. For example, many businesses have pages that describe the history of the company, list the key employees, explain products, offer customer service, etc. It is important that each page include a link to the home page so users can return to the main page easily. Users often want to access each page, and it is easier to do so if they can quickly link to the home page. It is not necessary to include a summary of the home page or a reason for the home page. Businesses often include illustrations or pictures on the home page, although that is not necessary. SOURCE: NF:042 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 164]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 61, "question": "An ongoing trend that affects how efficiently businesses operate is ", "choices": ["A. technology improvements.", "B. stable economic conditions.", "C. predictable buying motives.", "D. product classification methods."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Technology improvements. A trend is the general direction in which people or events are moving. To compete in the marketplace, businesses must use technology. Technology can improve a business's efficiency and productivity levels by making use of technological tools, such as machinery, computer networks, and the media. Because technology is always changing, businesses must also change to remain competitive. Economic conditions (e.g., unemployment rates, inflation, interest rates, business growth) fluctuate and change and do not remain stable. Business and consumer buying motives are not always predictable. Product classification is not a business trend that affects a business's efficiency and productivity levels. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Ray, R. (2009, January 13). Top ten technology trends for small businesses-2009. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://smallbiztrends.com/2009/01/top-ten-technology-trends-forsmall-businesses-2009.html/ "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Which of the following elements is part of a business's external environment? ", "choices": ["A. Tax code", "B. Research and development", "C. Marketing", "D. Personnel"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Tax code. The tax code is part of a business's external environment. It's determined by outside forces and can't be changed. Research and development, marketing, and personnel are all part of a business's internal environment. These are all elements that can be controlled or changed by a business. By using environmental scanning to look at the external environment, a business is able to change its internal environment so that it can be prepared to meet upcoming threats and opportunities. SOURCE: NF:015 SOURCE: NF LAP 2\u2014Get the 411 (Environmental Scanning) "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Which of the following is not a cause of accidents on the job: ", "choices": ["A. Compliance with rules", "B. Lifting with the back muscles", "C. Lack of knowledge", "D. Horseplay among workers"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Compliance with rules. Following company safety rules can help to prevent accidents. Horseplay, improper lifting techniques, and not knowing how to use machines and equipment can all cause accidents. SOURCE: OP:007 SOURCE: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. (2016). Office environment. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.cdc.gov/niosh/topics/officeenvironment/ "}, {"number": 64, "question": "One of the most important aspects of project management involves ", "choices": ["A. training employees.", "B. setting goals.", "C. buying supplies.", "D. identifying mistakes."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Setting goals. Project management involves planning, scheduling, and monitoring the progress of the project to achieve a specific goal. Therefore, one of the most important aspects of project management is developing a clear understanding of the project objectives, or goals. Once the goal has been set, the project manager guides the group to complete the project and accomplish the goal. Project managers seek employees who have the training and ability to participate in the project. It is not always necessary to buy supplies to complete a project. If mistakes occur, the project manager helps the group to correct the mistakes and continue the project. SOURCE: OP:158 SOURCE: OP LAP 6\u2014Projected to Win (Nature of Project Management) "}, {"number": 65, "question": "People are usually the most important resource because they are the ones who will ", "choices": ["A. do the work.", "B. use the tools.", "C. solve the problems.", "D. lead the project."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Do the work. One of the most important resources is people, the ones who will do the work. Some projects need the help of many people. It is important to identify the people who have the ability to help with a project. Without people, it will probably not be possible to complete the project. As part of working on a project, people often use tools, solve problems, and help lead the project. SOURCE: OP:003 SOURCE: Osunlaja, T., Kilinc, G., & Sen, E. (2008, November 20). Managing project resources. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.slideshare.net/talk2metboy/managing-projectresources-presentation Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 66, "question": "A project's quality-management plan includes strategies to ensure the quality of the deliverables as well as the quality of ", "choices": ["A. the project's purpose.", "B. the project itself.", "C. employee education.", "D. organizational investors."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "The project itself. A project's quality-management plan includes strategies to ensure the quality of the deliverables as well as the quality of the project itself. At the end of the project, managers want to look back and say that it ran smoothly. A project's quality-management plan cannot ensure the quality of the project's purpose\u2014those who are assigning the project are responsible for that. It also cannot ensure the quality of employee education or organizational investors. SOURCE: OP:001 SOURCE: OP LAP 7\u2014Chart Your Course (Developing a Project Plan) "}, {"number": 67, "question": "What production activity evaluates products to make sure that the products the business produces meet certain quality standards? ", "choices": ["A. Form utility", "B. Automation", "C. Follow-up", "D. Standardization"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Follow-up. The last production activity is following up to make sure production was carried out according to plan and that the products produced met company standards for quality. This may include inspecting the materials used in making the products as well as examining the finished products. Standardization is the process of setting criteria for products so that they will be uniform. Automation is the use of robots or other automatic equipment to do certain tasks. Form utility is usefulness created by altering or changing the form, or shape, of a good to make it more useful to the consumer. SOURCE: OP:017 SOURCE: OP LAP 17\u2014Can You Make It? (Nature of Production) "}, {"number": 68, "question": "\u201cBig Q\u201d is also known as ", "choices": ["A. lean production.", "B. total quality management.", "C. robust design.", "D. concurrent engineering."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Total quality management. \u201cBig Q\u201d is a strategic way of thinking about quality management. It focuses on ingraining quality into every aspect of the organization. It is sometimes referred to as TQM, or total quality management. Lean production is maximizing customer value while minimizing waste. Robust design, or the Taguchi method, focuses on product design and development, rather than manufacturing. Concurrent engineering is performing the various stages of product design and development simultaneously, rather than one after another. SOURCE: OP:163 SOURCE: OP LAP 8\u2014Take Control (Quality-Control Measures) "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Which of the following actions by employees might result in additional expense for a business: ", "choices": ["A. Reporting incidents of shoplifting", "B. Taking the initiative to find work", "C. Making personal use of company property", "D. Giving appropriate discounts to customers"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Making personal use of company property. Employees can help reduce expenses by respecting company property. One way that employees can do this is by not taking anything belonging to the business for their personal use. This can range from not making personal use of company vehicles to not taking home pens and pencils. Businesses must replace the company property that employees take for their own use, which results in additional expense for the business. Taking the initiative to find work, reporting incidents of shoplifting, and giving appropriate discounts to customers are ways that employees can help control expenses. SOURCE: OP:025 SOURCE: OP LAP 5\u2014Buck Busters (Employee Role in Expense Control) "}, {"number": 70, "question": "In the time-management process, what should you do when you are identifying your objectives? ", "choices": ["A. Update the plan.", "B. Schedule daily activities.", "C. Ask for advice.", "D. Write them down."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Write them down. The first step in the time-management process is identifying objectives you need to accomplish. Once you've identified your objectives, write them down. This will help to focus your attention on important activities and help you to decide which ones should be accomplished first. Scheduling daily activities, asking for advice, and updating the plan are things you might do after you've identified your objectives and written them down. SOURCE: PD:019 SOURCE: PD LAP 1\u2014About Time (Time Management) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 71, "question": "A technique that is helpful in developing self-understanding is keeping a personal diary. You should use the diary to ", "choices": ["A. review your progress on a daily basis.", "B. record the events of your life in detail.", "C. record your observations about others.", "D. identify the patterns of your behavior."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Identify the patterns of your behavior. You should record the significant things that happen each day and your reactions to them. Eventually, the diary will show you that there are certain patterns to your behavior. You should not review your progress on a daily basis or record the events of your life in minute detail. Some observations about others are likely to be included, but that should not be the major purpose of keeping a personal diary. SOURCE: PD:013 SOURCE: Forbes.com. (2012, July 18). 6 ways keeping a journal can help your career. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.forbes.com/sites/dailymuse/2012/07/18/6-ways-keeping-ajournal-can-help-your-career/#1a0e6344396f "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Even though there is a significant chance that his business will fail, Sidney intends to open a sports memorabilia shop. What entrepreneurial trait is Sidney exhibiting? ", "choices": ["A. Creativity", "B. Organization", "C. Willingness to take risks", "D. Open-mindedness"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Willingness to take risks. Starting a small business is extremely risky, yet Sidney plans to open his own store. He is willing to risk failure because he is optimistic that his business will succeed. While Sidney hopefully possesses other entrepreneurial characteristics, such as organization, creativity, and openmindedness, he is not exhibiting those traits in this example. SOURCE: PD:066 SOURCE: PD LAP 66\u2014Own Your Own (Career Opportunities in Entrepreneurship) "}, {"number": 73, "question": "Which of the following would help a job applicant to fill out job application forms easily: ", "choices": ["A. Having a personal data sheet", "B. Having computer experience", "C. Keeping a file of job leads", "D. Knowing someone at the business"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Having a personal data sheet. A personal data sheet is a list of information such as the applicant's Social Security number; the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of references; dates of previous employment; grade-point average; and any other data that might be asked for on a job application. Job applicants who prepare and use a personal data sheet can fill out job applications quickly, easily, and accurately because they have all the data they need on the sheet. Job applications are generally filled out by hand, not by computer. Keeping a file of job leads helps the applicant to organize his/her search for a job. Knowing someone at the business would not necessarily help a job applicant to complete a job application. SOURCE: PD:027 SOURCE: WikiHow. (2016). How to make a personal data sheet. Retrieved August 24, 2016, from http://www.wikihow.com/Make-a-Personal-Data-Sheet "}, {"number": 74, "question": "Which of the following should you do when preparing your letter of application: ", "choices": ["A. Write a letter that is at least one page long.", "B. Mention any mutual contacts you have.", "C. Repeat everything that is on your r\u00e9sum\u00e9.", "D. Proofread quickly so you can send the letter sooner."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Mention any mutual contacts you have. If you can, you should name someone you and the reader of your application letter both know. Of course, this isn't always possible, but it's a great way to get attention. Your letter should not be more than a page long. You shouldn't repeat everything that's on your r\u00e9sum\u00e9; your letter of application is intended to tell the reader things that aren't necessarily on the r\u00e9sum\u00e9. You should always proofread carefully, not quickly. Your letter of application is often the first impression a company gets of you, so you want it to be perfect. SOURCE: PD:030 SOURCE: Adams, Susan. (2011). How to write a cover letter. Retrieved on August 24, 2016, from http://www.forbes.com/sites/susanadams/2011/03/24/how-to-write-a-cover-letter/ "}, {"number": 75, "question": "Trade publications are used by businesses for which of the following reasons: ", "choices": ["A. To determine quantities to buy", "B. To obtain up-to-date information", "C. To set up an operating budget", "D. To appeal to the general public"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "To obtain up-to-date information. Trade publications contain information about new products, available resources, particular successes of other businesses, research, current trends, and legislation. They do not, however, recommend quantities to be purchased, appeal to the general public, or help the business establish an operating budget. SOURCE: PD:036 SOURCE: CD LAP 1\u2014Trade Associations/Professional Organizations Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 76, "question": "What are salespeople expected to be able to do in order to sell goods and services to customers? ", "choices": ["A. Arrange displays", "B. Control expenses", "C. Answer questions", "D. Develop brochures"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Answer questions. Professional salespeople are expected to be able to answer questions and provide further information in order to sell goods and services to customers. To do this successfully, they must be experts in the goods or services they sell and be able to develop long-term relationships with customers. Salespeople are not expected to develop brochures, although they may use them as a selling tool. Salespeople do not need to control expenses in order to sell. Arranging displays is the responsibility of the visual merchandising department. SOURCE: PD:024 SOURCE: PD LAP 21\u2014Career Opportunities in Marketing "}, {"number": 77, "question": "If a pharmaceutical company sets an unnecessarily high price for a lifesaving drug, it is behaving in a(n) __________ manner. ", "choices": ["A. conscientious", "B. economically justifiable", "C. socially irresponsible", "D. charitable"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Socially irresponsible. It is socially irresponsible to price a lifesaving product so that the people who need it cannot afford it. In some jurisdictions, it is considered price gouging, which is illegal. This action is not economically justifiable, charitable, or conscientious. SOURCE: PI:015 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 139-140, 537). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 78, "question": "Businesses may price goods with a higher-than-average markup when ", "choices": ["A. the risk of markdown is great.", "B. customers are given little service.", "C. handling expenses are low.", "D. stock turnover is high."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The risk of markdown is great. This would include fads and seasonal items that might need to be marked down significantly in order to sell. A lower-than-average markup is generally used when handling expenses are low, customers are given minimum service, and stock turnover is high. SOURCE: PI:002 SOURCE: PI LAP 3\u2014Make Cents (Factors Affecting Selling Price) "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Why must a business be very careful about eliminating products? ", "choices": ["A. To prevent damaging the company's image", "B. To comply with government regulations", "C. To make higher prices acceptable", "D. To avoid the need for commercialization"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To prevent damaging the company's image. Elimination of products must be done carefully to prevent damaging the company's image. Some weak products can be dropped immediately, but others should be eliminated slowly so that customers have time to find replacements. Some companies continue to provide service for a discontinued product in order to retain customer goodwill. Eliminating weak products is not governed by law. A weak product has already been through commercialization and has failed to be profitable. Eliminating weak products will not make higher prices acceptable to consumers. SOURCE: PM:001 SOURCE: PM LAP 17\u2014Rapping Up Products (Nature of Product/Service Management) "}, {"number": 80, "question": "Which of the following marketing strategies is appropriate for the decline stage of the product life cycle: ", "choices": ["A. Increasing promotion expenditures", "B. Marketing to early adopters", "C. Expanding the product line", "D. Selling the product online"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Selling the product online. Selling the product online is an appropriate marketing strategy for the decline stage of the product life cycle. Sometimes, marketers can have success distributing a product through non-traditional channels. Marketing to early adopters would be a strategy appropriate for the introduction stage. Expanding the product line is something that happens during the growth stage. Marketers usually decrease promotion expenditures during the decline stage. SOURCE: PM:024 SOURCE: PM LAP 18\u2014Get a Life (Cycle) (Product Life Cycles) "}, {"number": 81, "question": "Which of the following is an idea-generation technique that uses programmed thinking: ", "choices": ["A. Synectics", "B. Mind mapping", "C. Forced questioning", "D. Attribute listing"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Attribute listing. Programmed thinking is a process that involves generating ideas in logical, analytical, and organized ways. Attribute listing is an idea-generation technique that involves listing the characteristics or attributes of something and then finding ways to improve these attributes. For example, suppose that a business wants to improve a bike. The business would begin by listing attributes of the bike\u2014the wheels, seat, frame, gears, chain, etc. When listing the attributes, the business might decide that it could improve the seat by using different padding or by changing the shape of the seat to make it more comfortable for the rider. Mind mapping, forced questioning, and synectics are idea-generation techniques that use lateral thinking, which is a process that involves generating ideas in purposely illogical ways. SOURCE: PM:127 SOURCE: PM LAP 127\u2014Unleash Your Mind (Techniques for Generating Product Ideas) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 82, "question": "While facilitating a brainstorming session to generate product ideas, Gavin told Amy that her idea would be too expensive to implement. What did Gavin do wrong while facilitating the brainstorming session? ", "choices": ["A. Ignoring a group member", "B. Evaluating the idea", "C. Asking for opinions", "D. Exceeding the time limit"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Evaluating the idea. Brainstorming is a creative-thinking activity that businesses often use to generate product ideas. Many businesses find that it is beneficial to have several employees involved in the process because that helps generate a lot of different ideas. The facilitator is a person who guides the brainstorming session. The facilitator helps keep the members of the group brainstorming session on track. This person keeps order, encourages participation, fosters a creative environment, and documents the ideas for further review. The facilitator should not evaluate the ideas or initiate debate during a brainstorming session. These actions may hinder the creative-thinking process and discourage group members from participating. Gavin did not ignore Amy, but provided his opinion of her idea. There is not enough information provided to determine if Gavin exceeded the brainstorming time limit or asked others for their opinions. SOURCE: PM:128 SOURCE: Mind Tools. (1996-2016). Brainstorming: Generating many radical, creative ideas. Retrieved August 25, 2016, from http://www.mindtools.com/brainstm.htm "}, {"number": 83, "question": "The receptionist at a medical practice schedules patients' appointments for Dr. Langdon. Typically, Dr. Langdon needs 15 minutes for a sick-patient visit and 30 minutes for a well-patient's annual check-up. This is an example of a service standard related to ", "choices": ["A. regulations.", "B. quality.", "C. cost.", "D. time."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Time. Time standards are often tied to various types of services that a business might offer, such as medical and dental services. Doctors usually allocate a certain amount of time for a patient based on the patient's needs. A sick patient with a common ailment (cold) can usually explain specific symptoms, allowing the doctor to focus on those symptoms and provide a diagnosis fairly quickly. An annual checkup usually involves more discussion with the patient and multiple examination procedures, so this type of visit requires more of the doctor's time. Cost standards are used to specify project or product costs. Quality standards involve the degree of excellence expected from a product. Regulations often influence various types of business standards, but they are not types of standards. SOURCE: PM:019 SOURCE: PM LAP 8\u2014Raise the Bar (Grades and Standards) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Giving customers a list of locations at which they can obtain repair or replacement as part of a warranty or guarantee provides the customer benefit of ", "choices": ["A. increased profits.", "B. service information.", "C. legal recourse.", "D. reduced anxiety about purchases."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Service information. Service information is a customer benefit from warranties and guarantees which could include giving customers a list of locations at which they can obtain repair or replacement. Legal recourse concerns customer rights when a company does not fulfill its obligations under a warranty or a guarantee. Reduced anxiety about purchases refers to a customer benefit concerning problems that will be taken care of by a warranty, thereby relieving a customer's anxiety about spending money. Increased profits is a business benefit of warranties and guarantees. SOURCE: PM:020 SOURCE: PM LAP 4\u2014Promises, Promises (Warranties and Guarantees) "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Which of the following is not a reason to use contraction as a product mix strategy: ", "choices": ["A. To avoid conflict with another product in the product mix", "B. To make room for other products", "C. To protect the company from a legal liability", "D. To attract a new target market"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To attract a new target market. Contraction is the deletion or removal of a product or product line from a company's product mix. A business would need to add to its product mix, not delete from it, in order to attract a new target market. Products or product lines may be deleted in order to make room for others the company wishes to add. A product or product line may be deleted because it is in conflict with other products offered. A company may decide to drop a product or product line because of the potential liability associated with the products. SOURCE: PM:003 SOURCE: PM LAP 3\u2014Mix and Match (The Nature of the Product Mix) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 86, "question": "Product bundling is an effective method to sell goods and services because it ", "choices": ["A. provides new products with better exposure than advertising.", "B. allows businesses to sell unrelated items at the same time.", "C. creates a sense of value for the customer.", "D. encourages customers to comparison shop."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Creates a sense of value for the customer. Product bundling is the practice of selling multiple, related goods/services together as a one-price package. Bundled products are priced so that the customer pays less for the bundled products than they would pay for the products if the customer purchased each product individually. In some situations, the bundled product may not provide a great savings over individually purchased items, but just enough for the customer to feel that s/he is getting a deal or a good value. Product bundling is often used to get customers who happen to see the bundled package to try a new product; however, the business may also need to promote (e.g., advertise) the new product to let the masses know that the new product exists. Customers are less likely to comparison shop for less expensive goods when the items are bundled. SOURCE: PM:041 SOURCE: Kokemuller, N. (2016). Product bundling strategy. Retrieved August 25, 2016, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/product-bundling-strategy-41789.html "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Colors, logos, and images are all elements that make up a company's ", "choices": ["A. distributor brand.", "B. brand values.", "C. brand promise.", "D. brand identity."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Brand identity. A brand identity consists of those elements that are instantly recognized as representing a particular business or product, including logos, colors, names, images/graphics, and design. Brand values are beliefs or qualities that a corporate brand stands for and is built around. A brand promise is a business's spoken or unspoken agreement with customers that it will consistently meet their expectations and deliver on its brand characteristics and values. A distributor brand is owned by the retailer or wholesaler that sells the brand, rather than the manufacturer. SOURCE: PM:206 SOURCE: PM LAP 20\u2014Corporate Identity (Nature of Corporate Branding) "}, {"number": 88, "question": "Which of the following best describes the relationship of promotion and marketing: ", "choices": ["A. Interrelated", "B. Subsidiary", "C. Dependent", "D. One to one"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Interrelated. Promotion is one of the marketing functions known as the four 'P's of marketing. The other three are price, place, and product. Successful marketing depends upon offering the right product, at the right time, in the right place, with the right promotion. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: PR LAP 2\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Nature of Promotion) "}, {"number": 89, "question": "When a business sets up a Facebook account to communicate with its existing and potential customers, what technological tool is it using? ", "choices": ["A. Just-in-time marketing", "B. Broadcast media", "C. Social networking", "D. Affiliate advertising"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Social networking. Many businesses are establishing a marketing presence on various social-networking websites. As the popularity of social networking (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, MySpace, Linkedin) continues to grow, these types of websites provide businesses with additional touch points in which to connect with existing or new markets. For example, a business might inform its \"friends\" or \"fans\" about a special event, provide product coupons, or post entertaining videos to generate interest. Businesses may also solicit and receive feedback about their goods and services. Broadcast media uses radio waves (i.e., television, radio) to reach their audiences. Just-in-time is an inventory method that orders goods just in time for them to be used or sold. Affiliate advertising is the process of promoting and selling another business's products on a website in exchange for a sales commission. SOURCE: PR:100 SOURCE: Montealegre, A. (2010, July 29). Facebook-an advantage or not? Retrieved August 25, 2016, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Facebook\u2014-An-Advantage-Or-Not?&id=4760027 "}, {"number": 90, "question": "The main reason that a sportswear retailer decided to use direct-mail promotion was because it would reach the store's ", "choices": ["A. current customers.", "B. target market.", "C. former employees.", "D. local competitors."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Target market. Direct mail is a promotional medium that comes to consumers' homes or e-mail addresses in the form of letters, catalogs, postcards, folders, and messages. The advantage of direct mail in apparel promotion is that it can be sent only to those customers who have been identified as potential buyers of the clothing and accessories. A retailer would not wish to spend additional money sending promotional materials to a wide range of people who may not be interested in the specific type of apparel. The target market includes not only current customers but also those people who have been identified as potential customers. Reaching former employees and local competitors is not the purpose of direct-mail promotion. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: PR LAP 3\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Advertising Media) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 91, "question": "Alexandria has been using Look-So-Good cosmetics for several years and would not consider changing brands. In fact, Alexandria likes the cosmetics so much that she has become an advocate for the cosmetic company. She tells everyone about the features and benefits of Look-So-Good products, and encourages them to try the cosmetics. What type of word-of-mouth marketing is Alexandria using? ", "choices": ["A. Shill marketing", "B. Mobile marketing", "C. Organic marketing", "D. Virtual marketing"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Organic marketing. Word-of-mouth promotion occurs when customers tell others about their satisfaction with the business. Organic word-of-mouth promotion occurs naturally. Because customers are satisfied with the business and its products, they enthusiastically tell others about their satisfaction in the course of normal conversation. In some situations, customers trust and like the product so much that they become product advocates\u2014putting in a good word whenever and wherever they can. Virtual marketing involves communicating product information via the Internet. Mobile marketing involves communicating information via mobile devices and networks (e.g., smartphones). Shill marketing involves employing people to pose as customers who are satisfied with a business's product using word-of-mouth techniques. Shill marketing is unethical behavior, and in some jurisdictions, it is an illegal practice. SOURCE: PR:247 SOURCE: WordofMouth.org (2008, September 30). Organic vs. amplified word of mouth. Retrieved August 25, 2016, from http://wordofmouth.org/blog/guest-genius/organic-vs-amplified-wordof-mouth "}, {"number": 92, "question": "An athletic facility purchases a sports equipment distributor's directory for direct advertising purposes. The purchased information is often called a(n) ___________ list. ", "choices": ["A. internal-brokerage", "B. compiled", "C. house", "D. mail-response"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Mail-response. Companies develop mailing lists in different ways. Mail-response lists are those that businesses develop by purchasing other businesses' house lists. A house list is developed from a company's own database consisting of past and current customers. A compiled list is one that a company purchases from a seller who originally used the information for other purposes. Compiled lists often consist of several lists from several sources. Internal indicates that the list is generated within the company, making it a house list. A brokerage firm is a list seller. Therefore, internal-brokerage lists are nonexistent. SOURCE: PR:089 SOURCE: Cober, M. (2016). Response lists vs. compiled lists: which is right for your business? Retrieved August 25, 2016, from http://www.usdatacorporation.com/info/2012/06/responselists-vs-compiled-lists-which-is-right-for-your-business/ "}, {"number": 93, "question": "Which of the following is a type of sales promotion that provides customers with immediate rewards: ", "choices": ["A. Product displays", "B. Mail-in rebates", "C. Loyalty programs", "D. Price-off deals"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Price-off deals. Price-off deals involve discounting the prices of goods and services for a short period of time. Because customers save money by buying the products during the sale, they receive an immediate reward\u2014a good or service that they want or need at a discounted price. A rebate is a return of part of the price a customer pays for a good or service and usually is offered by the product's manufacturer. Loyalty programs reward repeat customers by offering incentives (e.g., free item) to maintain their loyalty to the business. Although rebates and loyalty programs provide rewards, customers must usually wait to receive them. Product displays exhibit merchandise and do not provide rewards. SOURCE: PR:249 SOURCE: Clow, K.E, & Baack, D. (2010). Integrated advertising, promotion, and marketing communications (4th ed.) [pp. 337-338]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 94, "question": "All of the components of a well-designed print advertisement should present a ", "choices": ["A. powerful opinion.", "B. formal appearance.", "C. humorous scenario.", "D. unified message."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Unified message. Each component of an effective advertisement should work together to communicate a unified message. For example, if the graphic element does not relate to the copy or headline of an advertisement, the meaning of the ad becomes unclear and confusing for the audience. The use of humor, level of formality, and inclusion of an opinion depend on the nature or goal of the advertisement. SOURCE: PR:251 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 477-478). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 95, "question": "In determining its selling policies, a business would have little or no control over ", "choices": ["A. corporate goals and objectives.", "B. human and financial resources.", "C. research and development.", "D. customer wants and needs."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Customer wants and needs. There are many forces operating in the business environment over which the business has little or no control. These external factors include customer wants and needs, actions of competitors, availability of raw materials, and social concerns. The other alternatives are internal factors. SOURCE: SE:932 SOURCE: SE LAP 121\u2014Sell Right (Selling Policies) Test 1141 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 96, "question": "Which of the following is an example of unethical selling behavior that directly affects employee-toemployee relationships: ", "choices": ["A. A salesperson does not want to lose a sale, so s/he withholds information from a prospect after\nbeing questioned about the product's performance.", "B. A buyer awards a major contract to a construction company after the company's vice president\ngave the buyer Super Bowl tickets.", "C. The sales staff's commissions are lower after a manager restructures the company's sales\nterritories and sets high quotas.", "D. To win a departmental sales contest, a salesperson claims to have processed a sales transaction"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To win a departmental sales contest, a salesperson claims to have processed a sales transaction before it has been formalized. Selling ethics can be compromised in many ways\u2014with vendors, subordinates, customers, and coworkers. An example of unethical selling behavior that affects coworkers may occur when a salesperson states that a sale has been made to win a contest, when, in fact, the order has not been finalized. This is dishonest behavior that robs a coworker from winning the contest that s/he worked hard to earn. Awarding a contract after receiving Super Bowl tickets may be viewed as bribery between a business and its vendor. A manager who restructures territories and sets unachievable quotas for sales staff to reduce commissions is negatively impacting the manager-employee relationship. Withholding information from a customer to make a sale is unethical behavior that impacts the buyer-seller relationship. SOURCE: SE:106 SOURCE: SE LAP 129\u2014Keep It Real-In Sales (Legal and Ethical Considerations in Selling) "}, {"number": 97, "question": "A consumer advantage of cooling-off laws is that it allows ", "choices": ["A. buyers a limited amount of time to withdraw from a purchase agreement without penalty.", "B. sellers an unlimited time frame to file a lawsuit if the buyers back out of the sales contract.", "C. buyers to withdraw from the purchase agreement but must pay high fines to the sellers.", "D. sellers to withdraw from the purchase agreement but must pay high fines to the government."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Buyers a limited amount of time to withdraw from a purchase agreement without penalty. Cooling-off laws protect consumers who purchase products as a result of high-pressure or fear-based sales tactics. Such laws provide buyers with a set amount of time to think about their purchases and allow the buyers an opportunity to withdraw from the purchase agreement without penalty. SOURCE: SE:108 SOURCE: Tanner, J.F., Honeycutt, E.D., & Erffmeyer, R.C. (2009). Sales management: Shaping future sales leaders (p. 79). Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Manufacturers often provide special instructions on product labels that salespeople can use to ", "choices": ["A. explain care techniques to customers.", "B. show customers how to return products.", "C. promote products to competitors.", "D. develop visual merchandising displays."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Explain care techniques to customers. Label information often includes care and maintenance instructions for the product in an attempt to ensure its satisfactory use. The salesperson should be familiar with the information provided on the labels of the products s/he sells in order to explain care techniques to customers during the selling process. Product labels are not intended to facilitate returns or be used for developing visual merchandising displays. Salespeople do not promote products to competitors. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri, C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [pp. 422, 524-535]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co. "}, {"number": 99, "question": "When a customer asks how long a product will last, s/he is interested in its ", "choices": ["A. durability.", "B. uses.", "C. origin.", "D. features."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Durability. When a customer asks how long a product will last, s/he is interested in its durability. How long a product will last and give dependable service is essential information which you should be prepared to give customers or clients. Product uses relate to what the product will do and how it can be used. Features are a product's specific characteristics. Origin refers to where or by whom the product is produced. SOURCE: SE:109 SOURCE: SE LAP 113\u2014Find Features, Boost Benefits (Feature-Benefit Selling) "}, {"number": 100, "question": "A plant manager or a department head would be an example of which level of management? ", "choices": ["A. Middle", "B. Operating", "C. Top", "D. Supervisory"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Middle. This level of management is responsible for the daily functioning of the business. It also serves as a liaison between top-level and supervisory management. Top management develops broad company plans, while supervisory, or operating, management is the management level that implements management plans through direct supervision of workers. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: SM LAP 3\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}], "1150-MKT": [{"number": 1, "question": "Samantha agrees to buy a bicycle from Tony for $225. This is an example of a(n) ", "choices": ["A. renegotiated agreement.", "B. unilateral contract.", "C. bilateral contract.", "D. nonverbal agreement."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Bilateral contract. In bilateral contracts, both parties promise to do something. In the example, Samantha promises to pay $225 to Tony. In exchange, Tony promises to give Samantha the bike. Unilateral contracts are contracts that involve promises made by one party. For example, a pet owner offers to pay a reward for a lost animal. In this situation, the pet owner is the only party making a promise. There is not enough information to determine if Samantha and Tony made a verbal or nonverbal agreement or if they renegotiated terms. SOURCE: BL:002 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2016). Bilateral contract. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/bilateral-contract.asp "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Certain environmental regulations require businesses to develop operating and production systems that are intended to ", "choices": ["A. collect samples.", "B. create waste.", "C. consume resources.", "D. control pollution."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Control pollution. Pollution is a growing problem that affects many large cities as well as small communities throughout the world. In an effort to control pollution, many countries have established environmental regulations that require businesses to develop clean and fuel-efficient operating and production systems. These systems protect the environment from industrial pollution and help to preserve natural resources. Many of these regulations also require businesses to control the amount of waste and dispose of it properly. Environmental regulations are intended to conserve resources. A business's operating and production systems are not intended to collect samples. SOURCE: BL:073 SOURCE: US Environmental Protection Agency. (2016). Our mission and what we do. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from https://www.epa.gov/aboutepa/our-mission-and-what-we-do "}, {"number": 3, "question": "A local dry cleaner develops, prints, and sends a direct-mail letter to select customers without using an outside advertising agency. This is an example of distribution. ", "choices": ["A. direct", "B. intermediate", "C. indirect", "D. service"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Direct. Direct distribution is a channel of distribution in which goods and services move directly from the producer to the consumer. In the example of the dry cleaner, the \"good\" is the direct-mail letter, which did not go through other channels to get to the consumer. Indirect distribution is the channel of distribution in which goods and services move from the producer to channel members and then to consumers. If the letter is developed, printed, and mailed by an advertising agency, the method of distribution is indirect. The advertising agency is an additional channel, the channel that develops the letter. The agency might also arrange printing and mailing with those agencies that specialize in printing and fulfillment, which would include two more channels used to distribute the literature. Intermediate and service are not forms of distribution. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: CM LAP 3\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "What is one of the advantages to businesses of using electronic data processing and computerized inventory systems in the distribution function? ", "choices": ["A. Increases overhead", "B. Reduces turnover", "C. Saves time", "D. Increases average stock on hand"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Saves time. The advantage of using new technology in the distribution function is that it saves time. The use of computerized inventory systems allows businesses to keep track of exactly how much inventory is in stock at any one time, and the use of electronic data processing allows businesses to place orders electronically, which shortens the order cycles. The new technology allows businesses to communicate instantly, place orders when needed, and receive the goods quickly. This reduces the amount of inventory they need to carry because they can quickly obtain whatever they need. The technology also helps to increase turnover by identifying excess inventory that should be marked down in order to sell. Increased overhead would be a disadvantage to businesses. SOURCE: CM:004 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 567). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 5, "question": "What is one reason a supermarket might implement slotting allowances to distribute products? ", "choices": ["A. To decrease the number of members in the distribution channel", "B. To reduce conflict among distribution channel members", "C. To increase the number of brands that the store carries", "D. To lower the risks associated with stocking new products"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To lower the risks associated with stocking new products. A slotting allowance refers to a fee paid by a manufacturer or vendor to a customer, usually a retailer. This fee is charged to cover the costs for placing a new product on the retailer's shelves. By charging a slotting allowance, the customer is trying to cover the costs of stocking and maintaining the product. If a new product does not sell well, the fees can help to cover the time on the shelf that could have been used for a higher moving item. Since there is only a limited amount of shelf space in a supermarket, the implementation of a slotting allowance does not necessarily increase a store's product line. Therefore, slotting allowances are not implemented to decrease intermediaries in the supply chain. Slotting allowances are not implemented to reduce conflict among distribution channel members. SOURCE: CM:006 SOURCE: Edwards, P. (2016, November 22). The hidden war over grocery shelf space. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.vox.com/2016/11/22/13707022/grocery-store-slottingfees-slotting-allowances "}, {"number": 6, "question": "To make sure products are available when customers want them, a business should coordinate promotion with ", "choices": ["A. segmentation.", "B. transportation.", "C. distribution.", "D. communication."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Distribution. Promotion helps to create demand for products, while distribution makes those products available. Businesses coordinate distribution with promotional activities to make sure that sufficient quantities of advertised products are available when customers want to buy them. If a business plans to promote a certain item, the business must make sure that an adequate supply will be on hand to meet customer demand. Businesses may lose customers if they promote certain items that are not available because they failed to make the necessary distribution arrangements. Transportation is the act of moving items from one place to another and is only one aspect of distribution. Segmentation involves dividing something, such as a total market, into smaller, more specific groups. Communication is an exchange of information in which the words and gestures are understood in the same way by both the speaker and the listener. SOURCE: CM:007 SOURCE: KnowThis.com. (2016). What is promotion? Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.knowthis.com/promotion-decisions/what-is-promotion "}, {"number": 7, "question": "To minimize conflict among distribution channel members, channel relationships should be viewed as ", "choices": ["A. non-binding contracts.", "B. friendly rivalries.", "C. employees.", "D. partnerships."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Partnerships. There are often many businesses or individuals that move products from the producer to the end user. These businesses and individuals are a distribution chain's channel members. The more channel members that a supply chain has, the higher the risk of conflict or disagreement among the members. Channel conflict occurs for a variety of reasons, such as bypassing one channel member in the process or disagreeing about sales terms. To reduce the risk of intense channel conflict, all channel members need to consider their relationships with each other as partnerships working toward the same goal\u2014satisfying the end user. Viewing channel relationships as friendly rivalries, employees, or nonbinding contracts will not minimize conflict. SOURCE: CM:008 SOURCE: Mack, S. (2016). Horizontal & vertical marketing conflicts. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/horizontal-vertical-marketing-conflicts-65325.html "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Loretta says the following to a group of researchers to whom she is speaking: \u201cTo back up my theory, studies presented in the Wickham Journal of Health and Wellbeing reveal that the survival rate for this particular disease increases by 38% when patients follow treatment option ", "choices": ["A.\u201d\nIn this situation, Loretta is defending her position objectively by\nA. providing supporting information.", "B. stating a well-known fact.", "C. using emotional appeals.", "D. communicating a goal."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Providing supporting information. By providing supporting data, facts, or knowledge, Loretta may increase or establish her credibility with the audience. If Loretta is successful in establishing credibility, she is more likely to get the audience to accept her idea or support her position. There is not enough information to determine if the audience knows about the study that Loretta is describing. Loretta is not using emotional appeals or communicating a goal. SOURCE: CO:061 SOURCE: Leadership Now. (2011, September 14). Advocacy: How to champion ideas and influence others. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.leadershipnow.com/leadingblog/2011/09/advocacy_how_to_champion_ideas.html Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about listening skills while handling telephonecalls: ", "choices": ["A. If you listen very carefully, you will not have to ask questions.", "B. It is easy to listen while carrying on other activities.", "C. Listening is a natural skill that doesn't require practice.", "D. Being a good listener requires active listening skills."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Being a good listener requires active listening skills. In order to be a good listener while handling telephone calls, you need to learn to shut out distractions, put aside what you are working on, and focus on what the speaker is saying. This is not a natural skill, but it is one that can be learned through practice. There will still be times when, no matter how carefully you listen, you will have to ask questions. SOURCE: CO:114 SOURCE: MindTools. (2016). Active listening. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from https://www.mindtools.com/CommSkll/ActiveListening.htm "}, {"number": 10, "question": "Writing key points on notecards and then placing the cards in order of their importance is one way to ", "choices": ["A. revise facts. ", "B. access files. ", "C. organize information. ", "D. verify accuracy."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Organize information. Organizing information helps you to communicate your message to your audience in a meaningful way. One way to organize information is to write down key points on notecards (index cards). Then, you can place the cards in the order of their importance or categories. The advantage to using notecards to organize information is that you can move them around and reorganize as needed. When you have the information in the order that you want it in, you can efficiently write an outline, report, manual, or article, or prepare a presentation. Placing key points on notecards and placing the cards in a certain order will not help you access files, revise facts, or verify the information's accuracy. SOURCE: CO:086 SOURCE: eHow.com. (1999-2016). How to organize a research paper. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.ehow.com/how_138072_organize-research-paper.html "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Deanna just finished writing an article that will be published in an industry-related magazine. Before she submits the article to the publisher, Deanna should ", "choices": ["A. develop a comprehensive outline of key points.", "B. proofread it and correct grammatical errors.", "C. determine if the topic will be of interest to the audience.", "D. prepare the table of contents and a glossary of terms."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Proofread it and correct grammatical errors. Written work that contains errors is unprofessional and hurts the credibility of the writer. Therefore, Deanna needs to proofread her work to correct grammar, spelling, and punctuation errors before she sends the article to the publisher. In addition, Deanna might ask another person to review her article to look for errors that she did not find. Deanna should determine if the topic will interest the audience and develop an outline before she starts writing her article. Magazine articles do not include a table of contents or a glossary of terms. SOURCE: CO:016 SOURCE: Roberts, S.J. (2012). Fundamentals of business communication (pp. 164-167). Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Company, Inc. "}, {"number": 12, "question": "Mitchell is writing an email to a company asking for some information that he needs to complete a research project. What is the most effective way to close the message? ", "choices": ["A. I appreciate your help with this issue.", "B. I need this information ASAP.", "C. I wish you the best of luck.", "D. I apologize for the inconvenience."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "I appreciate your help with this issue. An inquiry is a request for information. Letters of inquiry are requests for information such as product specifications, prices, job openings, proposals, expertise or consultation, etc. Letting the message recipient know that you appreciate his/her time and effort is a cordial way to close the message. The message sender might state a time when s/he plans to follow up with the recipient. Closing the message by saying the information is needed ASAP is rude and unprofessional. Wishing the message recipient luck and extending an apology are inappropriate closings for the situation at hand. SOURCE: CO:040 SOURCE: WriteExpress Corporation. (n.d.). Write inquiries. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.writeexpress.com/inquiry.htm "}, {"number": 13, "question": "Which of the following might a manager send to corporate management on a regular basis to briefly summarize the work accomplished: ", "choices": ["A. Weekly activity report", "B. Project proposal", "C. Strategic plan", "D. Business plan"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Weekly activity report. This is a brief summary of work accomplished that is submitted periodically for management's review. Periodic reports usually are short and informal. A project proposal is usually a longer and more formal report. Business owners and/or the business's executive management develop business plans and strategic plans. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: SampleTemplates. (2016). 9+ sample weekly activity reports. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from https://www.sampletemplates.com/business-templates/weekly-activity-reporttemplate.html Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 14, "question": "The way you follow up with a customer when showing a customer-service mindset will vary according to ", "choices": ["A. the customer's level of frustration.", "B. the type of service you have provided the person.", "C. how far away the person is located.", "D. how much attention your supervisor paid to the customer."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "The type of service you have provided the person. You should follow up with customers to be certain that they have received satisfaction from the product or the company's services. For example, salespeople might call customers to find out whether they're enjoying their purchases. A customer-service representative might call to determine whether customers are pleased with solutions to problems. A shipping clerk might check the shipping log to make sure customers have received their orders. The way you follow up with customers should not be based on levels of frustration, supervisory attention, or distance. All customers are important. Following up suggests to customers that you care about their continued satisfaction. SOURCE: CR:004 SOURCE: CR LAP 4\u2014Set Your Mind to It (Customer-Service Mindset) "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Mark is unhappy with the way his new shirt wrinkles, and he shows it to the salesperson. Mark's complaint is an example of a ", "choices": ["A. true complaint.", "B. false accusation.", "C. difficult customer.", "D. hidden complaint."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "True complaint. True complaints are honestly felt dissatisfactions by the customer. In this case, Mark dislikes the wrinkled fabric and explains that to the salesperson. Hidden complaints are the concealment of true complaints with believable but secondary reasons for dissatisfaction. Mark's complaint isn't a false accusation, and he isn't necessarily a difficult customer just because he is dissatisfied. SOURCE: CR:010 SOURCE: CR LAP 10\u2014Righting Wrongs (Handling Customer Complaints) "}, {"number": 16, "question": "Italian designer suits sold in exclusive men's apparel shops would be classified as goods. ", "choices": ["A. Convenience ", "B. shopping ", "C. specialty ", "D. intangible"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Specialty. These are consumer goods with special or unique characteristics that consumers are willing to exert special efforts to obtain. Convenience goods are consumer goods purchased quickly and without much thought or effort. Shopping goods are consumer goods that are purchased after consumers compare goods and stores in order to get the best quality, price, and/or service. Suits are tangible rather than intangible goods. SOURCE: EC:002 SOURCE: EC LAP 10\u2014Get the Goods on Goods and Services (Economic Goods and Services) "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Business ethics involve considering issues about what is ", "choices": ["A. positive and negative.", "B. legal and illegal.", "C. safe and unsafe.", "D. right and wrong."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Right and wrong. Ethics are the basic principles that govern an individual's behavior. In business, ethics involves how a business behaves in its dealing with other businesses, customers, and employees. Businesses consider issues about what is right and wrong when they decide how to operate and how to treat others. To be ethical, they need to consider how their actions affect the welfare of others. It is a matter of considering what is the right way to act and what is the wrong way to act. It does not involve considering what is legal or illegal, although some actions that are unethical are also illegal. Business ethics does not involve considering issues about what is safe and unsafe, or what is positive and negative. SOURCE: EC:106 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 150). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 18, "question": "Which of the following is a general benefit profit provides: ", "choices": ["A. Better wages", "B. More products", "C. Higher prices", "D. Better supplies"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Better wages. Better wages is one of the general benefits profit provides. Other general benefits include meeting consumers' needs and wants, providing better employment opportunities, and strengthening the economy. General benefits do not necessarily include more products, higher prices, or better supplies. More products and higher prices may bring in more profit, however. Better supplies may increase the quality of the product. SOURCE: EC:010 SOURCE: EC LAP 2\u2014Risk Rewarded (Factors Affecting Profit) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 19, "question": "Coola Cola is a leading brand of soft drink in Istanbabwe. The leading brand of potato chips there is Crumbles. In preparing Coola Cola's new market-share strategy, what type of competition would management consider Crumbles to be? ", "choices": ["A. Franchise", "B. Direct", "C. Indirect", "D. Wholesale"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Indirect. Coola and Crumbles produce dissimilar merchandise. Indirect competition occurs among businesses that offer dissimilar goods or services. Direct competition occurs between or among businesses that offer similar types of goods or services. Since the businesses produce a different type of merchandise, they would not be direct competitors. Franchise and wholesale are not types of competition. A franchise is a contractual agreement between a parent company and a franchisee to distribute goods or services. Wholesale is the purchase of goods from an intermediary, usually purchased from a manufacturer and sold to a retailer. SOURCE: EC:012 SOURCE: EC LAP 8\u2014Ready, Set, Compete! (Competition) "}, {"number": 20, "question": "A real property tax is a tax that is levied on ", "choices": ["A. furniture and supplies.", "B. land and buildings.", "C. machinery and equipment.", "D. natural resources."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Land and buildings. There are usually two types of property tax: real property tax and personal property tax. A real property tax is a tax that is levied on real estate, which is land and buildings. Both businesses and individuals pay tax on the real estate they own. Personal property taxes are taxes levied on furniture and supplies, and machinery and equipment. A real property tax is not a tax levied on natural resources. SOURCE: EC:072 SOURCE: EC LAP 27\u2014Pay Your Share (Business Taxes) "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Inflation has driven up prices at Allen's business, forcing him to reprint all his price lists and sendnotices out to clients. These expenses are known as ", "choices": ["A. price indexes.", "B. commodities.", "C. sampling errors.", "D. menu costs."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Menu costs. The expenses associated with changing prices are known as menu costs. Hyperinflation can create additional menu costs for businesses, which are most often passed on to their customers. Price indexes are investment- and inflation-monitoring tools. Sampling errors are statistical mistakes within a research study. Commodities are raw materials needed to create products. SOURCE: EC:083 SOURCE: EC LAP 28\u2014Up, Up, and Away (Inflation) "}, {"number": 22, "question": "What is the resulting condition when countries depend upon each other for products they cannot produce alone? ", "choices": ["A. Trade surplus", "B. Economic interdependence", "C. Comparative advantage", "D. Trade deficit"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Economic interdependence. Countries are interdependent because they need imports essential to the welfare of their citizens, and they need exports to provide opportunities for employment. A comparative advantage results when one country has an advantage over others in the production of a good or service. When exports exceed imports, a country experiences a trade surplus; when imports are greater than exports, a country experiences a trade deficit. SOURCE: EC:016 SOURCE: EC LAP 4\u2014Beyond US (Global Trade) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Penny used her emotional intelligence to separate negative feelings from the positive action she could take in a situation. What benefit of emotional intelligence does this situation illustrate? ", "choices": ["A. The ability to be flexible", "B. The ability to respond to criticism", "C. The ability to communicate needs effectively", "D. The ability to solve problems"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "The ability to solve problems. In this example, Penny did not communicate her needs, persuade others, or display flexibility. She used her emotional intelligence to solve problems\u2014she acknowledged and separated her negative feelings from the positive action she could take to find a solution. SOURCE: EI:001 SOURCE: EI LAP 6\u2014EQ and You (Emotional Intelligence) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "The term that refers to your ability to guide or direct the actions of others is ", "choices": ["A. receptivity.", "B. leadership.", "C. initiative.", "D. dependability."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Leadership. Your ability to guide or direct the actions of others is leadership. This trait is highly desired by employers. It is important to develop your leadership skills. Receptivity means openness to change and input from others. Dependability is reliability. The willingness to act without having to be told to do so is initiative. SOURCE: EI:018 SOURCE: EI LAP 9\u2014You've Got Personality (Personality Traits in Business) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 25, "question": "Sasha goes above and beyond at her job. She takes on additional responsibilities and volunteers to complete tasks that need to be done, even if they aren't very fun. What personal trait does Sasha possess? ", "choices": ["A. A sense of humor", "B. Pessimism", "C. Initiative", "D. Inflexibility"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Initiative. Initiative is the willingness to act without having to be told to do so. People who demonstrate initiative are willing to accept and seek out additional or even unpleasant duties. When Sasha goes above and beyond at her job, she is showing initiative by seeing what needs to be done without someone else pointing it out. Sasha is not showing pessimism or inflexibility; these are negative traits that are not interdependent with initiative. Although a sense of humor can be helpful in the workplace, Sasha is not illustrating one in this example. SOURCE: EI:024 SOURCE: EI LAP 2\u2014Hustle! (Taking Initiative at Work) "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Enduring life's aggravations and difficulties without getting upset requires you to have ", "choices": ["A. patience.", "B. independence.", "C. empathy.", "D. ambition."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Patience. Patience is the ability to endure calmly, and it is an important part of self-control. None of the other alternatives would help you to endure life's aggravations and difficulties without getting upset. Independence is the ability to manage your own life. Ambition is the desire for success. Empathy is the ability to put yourself in another's place. SOURCE: EI:025 SOURCE: EI LAP 14\u2014Control Yourself! (Demonstrating Self-Control) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "If a leader wants people to believe what s/he says and follow him/her, s/he must demonstrate ", "choices": ["A. the ability to share a vision.", "B. decisiveness.", "C. competence.", "D. self-awareness."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Competence. For a leader to be considered credible (having people believe what s/he says and follow him/her), s/he must demonstrate competence, which means capability, or the ability to do what needs to be done. Basic competence is demonstrated by giving and receiving clear directions, by identifying and using resources, and by planning and managing projects. Good leaders have the ability to share a vision, are self-aware, and demonstrate decisiveness, but being competent is a specific way to prove credibility. SOURCE: EI:009 SOURCE: EI LAP 16\u2014Lead the Way (Concept of Leadership) "}, {"number": 28, "question": "To influence others to work toward a shared vision, a leader should possess a high level of credibilityand should be able to provide supporting ", "choices": ["A. facts.", "B. practices.", "C. skills.", "D. assumptions."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Facts. Vision is the future that you desire to create. To fulfill a vision, the leader may need to get others to embrace the vision and help him/her carry it out. Enlisting others' support might include using rational persuasion, which is the method of appealing to others' intellects and minds by providing supporting facts or evidence. By providing facts and evidence, the leader is giving reasons to support the vision. Practices are procedures or activities that are followed. Skills are abilities. Assumptions are thoughts or information that are taken for granted as being true, but may not be true. SOURCE: EI:060 SOURCE: EI LAP 13\u2014Vision Quest (Enlisting Others in Vision) "}, {"number": 29, "question": "You're working on a group project with a classmate you don't know. If you want to treat him/her with dignity, the first thing you should do is ", "choices": ["A. do your fair share of the workload and don't slack off.", "B. get to know him/her and learn to pronounce his/her name.", "C. avoid talking about controversial subjects, like politics.", "D. avoid harassing behavior that annoys or intimidates him/her."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Get to know him/her and learn to pronounce his/her name. The first step of respecting people is getting to know them. Getting acquainted doesn't mean that you need to establish personal friendships with everyone you meet. It does mean that you should speak to people when you encounter them, learn to pronounce their names correctly, and sometimes ask them how they are. You should also do your fair share of the workload, avoid controversial subjects, and avoid harassing your classmate, but getting acquainted with him/her comes first. SOURCE: EI:036 SOURCE: EI LAP 36\u2014Everyone's Worthy (Treating Others With Dignity and Respect) "}, {"number": 30, "question": "The primary reason that people lose or leave their jobs is that they have ", "choices": ["A. poor job performance.", "B. difficulty understanding their jobs.", "C. poor self-esteem.", "D. difficulty getting along with others."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Difficulty getting along with others. The primary reason that people lose or leave their jobs is that they have difficulty getting along with others. More people are fired because they can't get along with their coworkers than for any other reason. Businesses usually let such people go because of the problems they cause within the business. Help is usually offered to employees who need a better understanding of their jobs or have poor job performance. Poor self-esteem is a personal problem that the individual must work to correct. SOURCE: EI:037 SOURCE: EI LAP 37\u2014Can You Relate? (Fostering Positive Working Relationships) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Customers that use revolving credit accounts are required to pay an additional cost on any balance unpaid at the end of each payment period. Which of the following terms refers to this added cost: ", "choices": ["A. Installment payment", "B. Annual fee", "C. Interest rate", "D. Finance charge"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Finance charge. Finance charges are interest charges on accounts that are not paid in full at the end of each payment period. They are usually a percentage of the total amount due. Annual fees are yearly fees charged for the privilege of using a bank credit card. Interest rates are fees the lender charges the borrower for the use of money. Installment payments are set amounts paid by specific times to repay an installment loan or to pay for an installment credit purchase. SOURCE: FI:002 SOURCE: FI LAP 2\u2014Give Credit Where Credit Is Due (Credit and Its Importance) "}, {"number": 32, "question": "What do many individuals establish when planning for future financial needs? ", "choices": ["A. College fund", "B. Living will", "C. Emotional intelligence", "D. A work history"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "College fund. In many cases, paying for college is a future financial need for which many individuals and married couples plan. In order to make sure sufficient money will be available to pay for college, individuals often establish a college fund. This may be set up with a bank or an investment company. People often set aside a certain amount to invest on a monthly basis so the fund will have a certain value by the time it is needed to pay college expenses. A living will involves a person's wishes concerning medical issues. A work history is a list of jobs a person has had during his/her life. Emotional intelligence is the ability to recognize and manage emotions in ourselves and in others. SOURCE: FI:064 SOURCE: Savingforcollege.com. (2016). What is a 529 plan? Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.savingforcollege.com/intro_to_529s/what-is-a-529-plan.php "}, {"number": 33, "question": "What do managers use for financial planning purposes? ", "choices": ["A. Operating standards", "B. Business policies", "C. Accounting information", "D. Production schedules"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Accounting information. Managers use accounting information to make financial decisions that affect the business. They decide how to spend the business's money based on the accounting information. Schedules are useful in determining the most effective use of time. Standards may be used to ensure quality control. Policies are guidelines used in decision making. SOURCE: FI:085 SOURCE: FI LAP 5\u2014Show Me the Money (Nature of Accounting) "}, {"number": 34, "question": "An important aspect of upholding ethical accounting standards involves the ability to be ", "choices": ["A. resourceful.", "B. objective.", "C. intolerant.", "D. unconventional."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Objective. Accountants prepare the accounting information that businesses use to make financial decisions. Therefore, it is important for accountants to uphold the ethical standards of their profession by providing accurate, objective (unbiased) financial information. A person who uses unique processes or creativity to achieve a goal is being resourceful. Accountants need to follow the GAAP to perform their jobs rather than use unique processes. An intolerant person is prejudiced. An unconventional person is often viewed as unusual or eccentric. SOURCE: FI:351 SOURCE: Vitez, O. (2016). Ethics in the accounting profession. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/ethics-accounting-profession-3738.html "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Which of the following is true of working capital management: ", "choices": ["A. It determines which projects the business will invest in.", "B. It concerns long-term decisions.", "C. It decides how investments will be financed.", "D. It deals with accounts payable and receivable."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It deals with accounts payable and receivable. Working capital management focuses on a company's current balance of assets and liabilities. It involves the management of accounts payable and receivable, inventory, and cash. Capital investment decisions are made for the long term. Capital investment decisions also decide how investments will be financed and determine which projects a business should invest in. SOURCE: FI:354 SOURCE: FI LAP 7\u2014Money Matters (Role of Finance) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Is it unethical for a manager to promote an employee who is also the manager's friend? ", "choices": ["A. No, if the employee is not the same gender as the manager.", "B. No, if the appropriate procedures are followed, and the employee is the most qualified candidate.", "C. Yes, it is inappropriate to promote a friend.", "D. Yes, other employees will file discrimination claims, which will damage the company's reputation."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "No, if the appropriate procedures are followed, and the employee is the most qualified candidate. Employees often form friendships with their coworkers, managers, and subordinates. It is important, however, that the managers remain objective and place the company's best interest above their personal feelings or relationships when making job-related decisions. If a manager follows the company's interviewing and hiring protocol, and the employee is the most qualified candidate, then it is not unethical to offer the employee the promotion. Basing a decision on an employee's gender may be unethical and is considered a form of discrimination. It cannot be assumed that other candidates will file discrimination claims if one employee is promoted. SOURCE: HR:411 SOURCE: MindTools. (2016). Avoiding unconscious bias at work. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/avoiding-unconscious-bias.htm "}, {"number": 37, "question": "Which of the following is a way that marketers can use data to follow up on any problems or issues with a product: ", "choices": ["A. Providing salespeople with additional training", "B. Determining what new products to offer", "C. Deciding what wholesalers to use for distribution", "D. Budgeting for product development"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Providing salespeople with additional training. Data may show that salespeople need additional training for a certain product. This is something marketers want to provide so sales and profits can be as high as possible. Determining what new products to offer, deciding which wholesalers to use for distribution, and budgeting for product development are all activities that should take place before a product hits the market. SOURCE: IM:012 SOURCE: IM LAP 12\u2014Data Do It (Need for Marketing Data) "}, {"number": 38, "question": "What is a benefit of marketing research? ", "choices": ["A. Takes the place of data analysis", "B. Creates fair competition", "C. Provides data for a specific situation", "D. Increases the cost of goods and services"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Provides data for a specific situation. Marketing research is the systematic gathering, recording, and analyzing of data about a specific problem. Such data may be needed when the data in the marketinginformation management system do not apply to the circumstances or are insufficient. The data that are gathered must still be analyzed in order to be useful to the business. Marketing-research activities may increase the cost of goods and services, and that is a disadvantage rather than a benefit. Marketing research does not necessarily create fair competition, but it may help the business to be competitive. SOURCE: IM:001 SOURCE: Suttle, R. (2016). Key costs & benefits in marketing research. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/key-costs-benefits-marketing-research-26311.html "}, {"number": 39, "question": "How can businesses use computerized databases to sort and organize information about customers' purchases, brand preferences, and dollar amounts spent? ", "choices": ["A. To maintain sales strategies", "B. To prepare financial reports", "C. To develop inventory control plans", "D. To customize their marketing efforts"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To customize their marketing efforts. Many businesses use computerized databases to sort and organize information about customers' purchases, brand preferences, dollar amounts spent, etc. The benefit to the business is that it can use this information to customize its marketing efforts and appeal to specific customers. For example, a business might use a database to organize customers according to geographic location, and send different promotional pieces to each area. The database allows a business to target specific customers based on certain criteria. Businesses do not use this type of customer information to prepare financial reports, develop inventory control plans, or maintain sales strategies. SOURCE: IM:183 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 594-595). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 40, "question": "To determine how research data relate to the questions that have been raised, the researcher must the situation. ", "choices": ["A. analyze", "B. observe", "C. survey", "D. experiment with"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Analyze. The collected data must be analyzed, or interpreted, in order to be useful. Data by themselves are just a collection of facts, which might not be meaningful. Observation gathers data, surveying asks questions, and experimentation tests cause and effect. SOURCE: IM:010 SOURCE: IM LAP 10\u2014Seek and Find (Marketing Research) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Researchers are conducting focus groups as part of their current marketing-research project. The results of these focus groups are examples of ", "choices": ["A. primary data.", "B. relevant variables.", "C. secondary data.", "D. units of analysis."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Primary data. The focus group results are examples of primary data, or facts, figures, and statistics that have been collected specifically for the marketing research project being conducted. Secondary data are facts, figures, or statistics that already exist for other purposes. Relevant variables are the types of information studied in a marketing research project (e.g., brand awareness, customer satisfaction, etc.). Units of analysis are the entities or elements that are being studied in market research (e.g., individual, household, etc.). SOURCE: IM:282 SOURCE: IM LAP 282\u2014What's the Problem? (Marketing Research Problems) "}, {"number": 42, "question": "The method for selecting sampling units out of the target population is the ", "choices": ["A. sample design.", "B. stratum.", "C. sample size.", "D. skip interval."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Sample design. The method for selecting sampling units out of the population is the sample design. A stratum is a group of sampling units within the population. Sample size is the number of sampling units that will be drawn from the population. Skip interval is the number of spaces between each sampling unit drawn in systematic random sampling. SOURCE: IM:285 SOURCE: IM LAP 16\u2014Take Your Pick (Nature of Sampling Plans) "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Which method of data collection allows researchers to gather information about customers in a natural setting? ", "choices": ["A. Focus group", "B. Observation", "C. Experiment", "D. Personal interview"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Observation. The observation method of data collection allows researchers to watch people in a natural setting and record their behavior. Focus groups, personal interviews, and experiments are not natural settings. SOURCE: IM:289 SOURCE: IM LAP 17\u2014Hunting and Gathering (Data-Collection Methods) "}, {"number": 44, "question": "During which of the following steps do researchers transfer coded questionnaire data to thecomputer: ", "choices": ["A. Discarding", "B. Analyzing", "C. Reviewing", "D. Transcribing"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Transcribing. Transcribing involves taking the coded information and entering it into the appropriate computer fields so that businesspeople can analyze and review information. Researchers discard incomplete information before entering it into the computer. SOURCE: IM:062 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 505-510]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 45, "question": "What type of data do descriptive statistics summarize? ", "choices": ["A. Synectic ", "B. Subjective ", "C. Sample ", "D. Solitary"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Sample. Descriptive statistics are information that is presented in numerical form and is related to a specific issue, situation, or concern. Marketing researchers often collect this type of information by surveying a sample group\u2014a representative group of the target market. After collecting the information, marketing researchers assign numerical values to survey responses and compile the responses into descriptive statistics, which help the researchers summarize the information for analysis. The descriptive statistics should provide the researchers with objective information rather than subjective data. Synectics refer to a creative-thinking technique that businesses often use for product development. Descriptive statistics do not summarize solitary data. SOURCE: IM:191 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2016). Descriptive statistics. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/descriptive_statistics.asp?lgl=no-infinite "}, {"number": 46, "question": "What type of question should be avoided when designing a questionnaire? ", "choices": ["A. Structured", "B. Leading", "C. Unstructured", "D. Qualitative"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Leading. Marketing researchers should avoid the use of leading questions on their questionnaires because these tend to influence the respondents' answers and create bias, which skews results. An example of a leading question is, \"Don't you agree that teachers should earn more money for all that they do?\" The way that the question is worded is likely to make the respondent feel like s/he is not a proponent of education and the teaching profession if s/he answers \"no.\" Structured questions provide options from which the respondent can choose. Unstructured questions are open-ended questions that allow respondents to provide qualitative information and in-depth responses. Structured and unstructured questions are acceptable question formats to use on questionnaires. SOURCE: IM:293 SOURCE: Hair, J.F., Bush, R.P., & Ortinau, D.J. (2009). Marketing research in a digital information environment (4th ed.) [pp. 405-408]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Which of the following statements is true about the timeliness of research information: ", "choices": ["A. Older information that is obtained from secondary sources lacks credibility.", "B. Timely information is usually relevant to the problem or situation at hand.", "C. Timely information that is obtained from online sources is usually accurate.", "D. A company that uses out-of-date research data may make poor business decisions."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "A company that uses out-of-date research data may make poor business decisions. For example, suppose a business obtains older research stating that a large segment of the market wants product X. The business develops and markets product X, but the good or service doesn't sell because circumstances in the marketplace have changed. The business stands to lose a lot of money because it did not use current research data to make its decision to proceed with producing and marketing product X. Information may be timely or up-to-date, but it doesn't always relate to the business's problem or situation at hand. Information that a business obtains from online sources is not always accurate or correct. Older information that is obtained from secondary sources may be credible, if circumstances have not changed. SOURCE: IM:428 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [p. 29]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Hope's produce company accidentally sold several crates of spoiled vegetables. She immediately issued a statement to recall the product and apologize for the mistake. What positive action did Hope's company take? ", "choices": ["A. Protecting the business's reputation", "B. Aligning strategies and activities with goals", "C. Providing proper training for employees", "D. Using rational and emotional motivation to convince customers to buy"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Protecting the business's reputation. By admitting, apologizing for, and fixing her company's mistake, Hope is taking action to protect the business's reputation. This action does not illustrate aligning strategies and activities with goals, providing proper training for employees, or using rational and emotional motivation to convince customers to buy. SOURCE: MK:019 SOURCE: MK LAP 3\u2014Just Do It...Right (Company Actions and Results) "}, {"number": 49, "question": "What is the overall reason that marketing strategies are designed and implemented? ", "choices": ["A. Achieving planned goals", "B. Improving management techniques", "C. Changing the image of the business", "D. Increasing business profits immediately"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Achieving planned goals. The business's goals and strategies for achieving those goals may change frequently. Changing the business's image, increasing its profits, or improving management techniques might be specific goals at any point in time. SOURCE: MP:001 SOURCE: MP LAP 2\u2014Pick the Mix (Nature of Marketing Strategies) "}, {"number": 50, "question": "How does a marketing plan affect the way the marketing team plans its strategies? ", "choices": ["A. The team can plan strategies more quickly.", "B. The team can plan strategies up to 10 years in advance.", "C. The team has more difficulty planning strategies.", "D. The team can plan strategies with more precision."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "The team can plan strategies with more precision. Writing a marketing plan allows the marketing team to plan its strategies with more precision since it has done so much research into the current marketing situation, the target market(s), etc. This should make planning strategies easier, not more difficult. It won't necessarily make planning strategies go more quickly, however. A marketing team would not plan strategies 10 years in advance since the economic and marketing climate can change so quickly. SOURCE: MP:007 SOURCE: MP LAP 7\u2014A Winning Plan (Nature of Marketing Plans) "}, {"number": 51, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a possible opportunity that a business might identify as a resultof conducting a situational analysis: ", "choices": ["A. Customers changing their habits", "B. Increases in operating expenses", "C. Suppliers raising their prices", "D. Declines in economic conditions"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Customers changing their habits. The changing nature of the marketing environment brings with it many opportunities for businesses. One of the purposes of conducting a situational analysis is to identify possible opportunities in the business environment. An example of a possible opportunity is a change in customers' habits. If an analysis indicates that customers are buying more of one type of product and that the trend will continue, a business can take advantage of the change by providing that type of product. However, in order to be prepared to take advantage of such opportunities, a business first must analyze the environment to determine exactly what those opportunities are. A situational analysis also indicates possible threats to the business. Examples of threats include suppliers raising their prices and a decline in economic conditions. Increases in operating expenses is an internal problem. SOURCE: MP:008 SOURCE: Boundless. (2016). Conducting a situational analysis. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from https://www.boundless.com/marketing/textbooks/boundless-marketing-textbook/marketingstrategies-and-planning-2/steps-to-creating-a-marketing-plan-28/conducting-a-situationalanalysis-151-7221/ Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 52, "question": "In which of the following situations should a business increase its sales forecast for thecoming year: ", "choices": ["A. Cost of supplies will increase by 2%.", "B. Inflation rate is expected to drop by 1%.", "C. Wages and salaries will remain the same.", "D. Customer base will decrease by 5%."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Inflation rate is expected to drop by 1%. Changes in the economy affect sales and, thus, sales forecasting. When the economy improves for any reason, such as a 1% decrease in inflation, consumers' disposable income is increased, and sales of consumer products often increases. A business should consider economic changes when forecasting sales and raise its expectations for the coming year if it thinks consumers will be able to buy more of its product than in the past. A business might consider lowering its sales forecast if the cost of supplies will increase by 2% or the customer base will decrease by 5%. The sales forecast might stay the same if wages and salaries are expected to remain the same. SOURCE: MP:013 SOURCE: MP LAP 5\u2014Futurecast (The Nature of Sales Forecasts) "}, {"number": 53, "question": "Why is it important for businesses to store information for future use? ", "choices": ["A. To establish quality control", "B. To maintain data accuracy", "C. To make it accessible", "D. To ensure confidentiality"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To make it accessible. Businesses obtain a wide variety of information that often can be used for many purposes. Therefore, it is important to store the information for future use so it will be accessible when needed. For example, information about current customers might be used to develop procedures for attracting new customers in the future. If the information has not been stored so it is accessible, the business will need to obtain other types of information. Businesses do not need to store information to establish quality control. Storing information does not ensure that data is accurate, nor does it ensure that the information remains confidential. SOURCE: NF:081 SOURCE: Better Evaluation. (2016). Archive data for future use. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://betterevaluation.org/en/evaluation-options/archive_data_for_future_use "}, {"number": 54, "question": "Information management can be a challenge because ", "choices": ["A. there is only one right way to do it.", "B. there is often not enough information to manage.", "C. many people don't understand what it is.", "D. no one wants to participate in it."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Many people don't understand what it is. Information management can be a challenge because many people don't understand what it is or what role they should play in it. Many people may want to participate in information management but just don't know how. There is often too much information to manage, something known as information overload. There is no one right way to approach information management. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: NF LAP 110\u2014In the Know (Nature of Information Management) "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Which of the following is the type of information system that contains word-processing and spreadsheet applications: ", "choices": ["A. Office automation", "B. Transaction processing", "C. Meta tag", "D. Business intelligence"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Office automation. Businesses use office automation information systems to develop, manipulate, and store various types of administrative data, including documents, spreadsheets, graphics, and computergenerated presentations. Microsoft Office, AppleWorks, and IBM/Lotus SmartSuite are common office automation programs that businesses use. Transaction processing information systems process routine business transactions. Organizations use business intelligence information systems to collect, store, and analyze information about their markets and competitors. Meta tags are HTML codes that display information about web pages. SOURCE: NF:083 SOURCE: Inc. (2016). Office automation. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from http://www.inc.com/encyclopedia/office-automation.html "}, {"number": 56, "question": "What type of software program allows businesspeople to combine graphics, transparencies, slides, and text for an on-screen display of information? ", "choices": ["A. Publishing ", "B. Application ", "C. Operating ", "D. Presentation"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Presentation. Presentation software programs allow businesspeople to create computer-generated presentations that may include graphics, transparencies, slides, text, sound, video, or animation. The advantage of using presentation software is that it enables businesses to develop colorful, eye-catching presentations that display information in an interesting manner. Application, operating, and publishing software programs do not combine graphics, transparencies, slides, and text for an on-screen display of information. SOURCE: NF:008 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 214-215). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 57, "question": "Trent was reviewing a business record that did not reflect updated information. The quality of the business record was compromised because it was ", "choices": ["A. unavailable.", "B. inaccurate.", "C. unorganized.", "D. irrelevant."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Inaccurate. Quality business records should be retrievable, reliable, and accurate. When a business does not update information (e.g., inventory status), it runs the risk of making poor business decisions by using inaccurate information. The example does not indicate that the information is unavailable, unorganized, or irrelevant. SOURCE: NF:001 SOURCE: NF LAP 1\u2014Record It (Business Records) "}, {"number": 58, "question": "The growth of e-commerce is changing the way companies do business by allowing them to ", "choices": ["A. reduce the services they provide customers.", "B. communicate with similar organizations.", "C. place high prices on their products.", "D. be accessible to customers at all times."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Be accessible to customers at all times. E-commerce is a business trend that is expanding rapidly because of the Internet and the World Wide Web. E-commerce is changing the way companies do business because it allows them to be accessible to customers at all times. Customers who have access to a computer and the Internet can visit a business's website and obtain information or shop online at any time of the day or night. As a result, more and more businesses are adding websites to make their services and products available to customers at all times. The benefit to a business is often increased sales. The growth of e-commerce is increasing competition, which means that businesses often reduce prices and offer additional services to attract customers. Businesses do not use e-commerce to communicate with similar organizations. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 207-208). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following activities is part of operations: ", "choices": ["A. Creating an advertising campaign", "B. Researching and developing new products", "C. Shipping products to customers", "D. Buying a new office building"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Shipping products to customers. Operations refers to the day-to-day activities needed for continued business functioning. These activities include purchasing the materials needed to make products or maintain the company's facilities, storing inventory, shipping products to customers, etc. Buying property, researching and developing new products, and creating advertising campaigns are not included in the operations function of a business. SOURCE: OP:190 SOURCE: OP LAP 190\u2014Above Board (Ethics in Operations) "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Which of the following helps the operations function to control costs and increase productivity: ", "choices": ["A. Use of technology", "B. Hiring of employees", "C. Type of management", "D. Supply of money"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Use of technology. Operations are the day-to-day activities required for continued business functioning. Advances in technology make it possible for businesses to use computers to control various aspects of the operations function. For example, specialized computer programs can design the layout of the production facility, while other programs can monitor inventory levels and automatically place orders. This technology reduces the number of employees needed to perform these tasks, which controls costs. Other computer programs organize and schedule production activities, which decrease costs and increase productivity. Hiring employees may increase costs and will not necessarily increase productivity. The type of management and the supply of money do not help the operations function to control costs and increase productivity. SOURCE: OP:191 SOURCE: Pride, W.M., Hughes, R.J., & Kapoor, J.R. (2008). Business (9th ed.) [pp. 286-293]. Boston: Houghton Mifflin. "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Determine whether the following statement is true or false: Employees must be taught how to use equipment properly and the potential dangers of not doing so. ", "choices": ["A. True; well-trained employees always use safety precautions.", "B. False; employees know which equipment is dangerous and which is not.", "C. True; the business is responsible for creating a safe work environment.", "D. False; employees understand the hazards of misusing equipment."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "True; the business is responsible for creating a safe work environment. When there is potentially dangerous equipment in the workplace, employees should be instructed in the safe use of the equipment and the potential danger to themselves and others of not doing so. Even when such training is given, employees may become careless or forget to use safety precautions. It is not always obvious that equipment can be hazardous. SOURCE: OP:007 SOURCE: Rabid Office Monkey. (2014, August 21). Tips for a safe office environment. Retrieved December 5, 2016, from https://rabidofficemonkey.com/tips-safe-office-environment/ Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Which of the following actions should your business take to preventrobberies: ", "choices": ["A. Make sure fire doors are easy to access and open", "B. Keep valuables stored near windows", "C. Turn off the lights when no one is working", "D. Escort all visitors to their desired locations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Escort all visitors to their desired locations. To prevent robberies, it's a good idea to escort all guests to and from their desired locations at your business. This, along with asking for identification and providing guests with passes, will help you make sure that everyone in your business is supposed to be there. Valuables (such as electronics or important files) should be kept away from windows to discourage thieves from breaking windows and easily taking things. Your business should be well-lit when people aren't working; if there are no lights on, thieves can tell that no one is around, and they will be more likely to break in. Although fire doors should be easy to access in an emergency, they should not be easy for thieves to open. Keep doors secure so thieves can't get in. SOURCE: OP:013 SOURCE: University of Florida Police Department. (2012, May 11). Robbery prevention for businesses. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://www.police.ufl.edu/community-services/robberyprevention-for-businesses/ "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Tatiana is a project manager who is ready to close a project and has scheduled a \"lessons learned\" meeting with the project team. What will Tatiana most likely include on her meeting agenda? ", "choices": ["A. Explanation of the stakeholders' expectations", "B. The definition of the project's purpose", "C. Discussion of specific challenges encountered", "D. The distribution of project resources allocated"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Discussion of specific challenges encountered. After the stakeholders receive the deliverables, the project manager often meets with the team members to discuss what went well and what didn't go well with the project. The team members also discuss how processes could have been improved. The information obtained from the \u201clessons learned\u201d meeting is summarized in a \u201clessons learned\u201d document, which can be used by teams that execute similar projects for the organization in the future. The project's purpose and the stakeholders' expectations are explained during the initiation phase of the project. The allocation of resources is determined during the planning phase of the project. SOURCE: OP:159 SOURCE: Womack, J. (2012, January 5). Three tips for boosting productivity with project debriefing. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/222546 "}, {"number": 64, "question": "What is often the best way for a business to increase its profit? ", "choices": ["A. Raise prices", "B. Reduce expenses", "C. Lower taxes", "D. Improve sales"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Reduce expenses. Decreasing expenses is perhaps the best way that businesses can help to increase profit. Businesses have control over many of their expenses and can take measures to reduce them. For example, they can eliminate some free services and encourage workers to turn off lights and equipment when not being used, in order to save money on energy costs. Raising prices will not increase profits unless customers are willing to pay the higher prices. Tax rates are regulated by government. If businesses improve sales, they might increase their profits if the rate of sales is proportionately higher than the expense involved. SOURCE: OP:024 SOURCE: Carey, B. (2016). 5 ways to reduce your business expenses right now. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://quickbooks.intuit.com/r/expenses/5-ways-to-reduce-your-businessexpenses-right-now/ "}, {"number": 65, "question": "Arm and Hammer baking soda, which was originally developed as a cooking ingredient, is nowbeing sold as an effective refrigerator deodorizer. This is an example of innovation. ", "choices": ["A. distributed ", "B. process ", "C. positioning ", "D. associative"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Positioning. Position innovation occurs when an existing product is repositioned. In the situation provided, a new use for the baking soda prompted Arm and Hammer to reposition the product as a deodorizer. The basic product did not change, but the company redesigned the package so that a filtered panel opened on the side of the box for optimal odor absorption. Process innovation involves changing the way that a product is produced or delivered. Distributed innovation refers to a decentralized model used for problem solving. Associative innovation is a fictitious term. SOURCE: PD:126 SOURCE: Humanitarian Innovation Fund. (2016). Types of innovation. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://www.elrha.org/hif/innovation-resource-hub/innovation-explained/typeshumanitarian-innovation/ "}, {"number": 66, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a limited decision: ", "choices": ["A. What college you'll attend", "B. Where you'll take your bike for repair", "C. Which car you'll buy", "D. When you'll leave for school"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Where you'll take your bike for repair. An example of a limited decision is where you'll take your bike for repair\u2014because you'll spend a little time considering where you want to take it. It's not something you'll put no thought into (as deciding when you'll leave for school) or a lot of thought into (as deciding which car you'll buy or college you'll attend). SOURCE: PD:017 SOURCE: PD LAP 10\u2014Weigh Your Options (Decision Making in Business) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Which of the following is most likely to be able to provide in-depth information about career opportunities in specific fields: ", "choices": ["A. Marketing consultants", "B. Local newspapers", "C. College recruiters", "D. Trade associations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Trade associations. A trade association is a group of persons in the same industry who form a society to solve their common problems. Trade associations provide in-depth information about various jobs in their industries. This information includes skills, training, and education necessary to perform particular jobs in specific industries. Much of this information is often found on a trade association's website. The website might also provide links to other resources that have additional information about the field or industry. Local newspapers, college recruiters, and marketing consultants might be able to provide general career information about a specific field or topic of interest. SOURCE: PD:022 SOURCE: Entrepreneur. (2016). Trade association. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from https://www.entrepreneur.com/encyclopedia/trade-association "}, {"number": 68, "question": "The most likely reason an individual might turn a woodworking hobby into a business is because of ", "choices": ["A. higher taxes.", "B. guaranteed financial security.", "C. sales quotas.", "D. personal satisfaction."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Personal satisfaction. Hobbies or interests are activities that people enjoy. People obtain personal rewards by engaging in them. Woodworking is one activity that many people consider a hobby. Most people would not start businesses because higher tax rates might result in less income. Entrepreneurs are not guaranteed financial security when they begin new businesses. Sales quotas are specific selling goals for members of a sales force in a company. SOURCE: PD:066 SOURCE: PD LAP 66\u2014Own Your Own (Career Opportunities in Entrepreneurship) "}, {"number": 69, "question": "What action can workers take to acquire new skills that can enhance their job performance? ", "choices": ["A. Take classes at a community college", "B. Complete a college application", "C. Obtain recommendations from others", "D. Contact former employers"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Take classes at a community college. Workers who want to advance in or keep up with their chosen professions often need to obtain additional, ongoing education. There are many ways for workers to acquire job-related skills, such as taking classes at a university or community college. Completing a college application, obtaining recommendations, and contacting former employers are not actions that help workers obtain new skills. SOURCE: PD:033 SOURCE: Grilli, J. (2012, December 3). Continuing education programs benefit employees and employers. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://citizensvoice.com/opinion/letters/continuing-education-programs-benefit-employeesand-employers-1.1410489 "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Which of the following describes careers in marketing: ", "choices": ["A. They often overlap and run together.", "B. They exist in very few industries.", "C. They are separate and distinct.", "D. They only exist online."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "They often overlap and run together. Although marketing careers can generally be divided into several different areas, they often overlap and run together. They are not separate and distinct, they do not only exist online, and they exist in many different industries. SOURCE: PD:024 SOURCE: PD LAP 21\u2014Career Opportunities in Marketing "}, {"number": 71, "question": "What is an example of an unethical pricing practice? ", "choices": ["A. A firm sets a business objective to increase its profit margins over the next five years.", "B. A business increases its prices when the cost of the materials to make the products increases.", "C. A company prices its products low in an attempt to drive its competitors out of business.", "D. A business prices a new product line to reflect high quality and status."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "A company prices its products low in an attempt to drive its competitors out of business. Ethics are the principles that guide personal behavior. When a business prices its products very low with the goal to drive its competitors out of business, it may be acting unethically, and possibly illegally. This is because the business is deliberately pricing products so low that smaller businesses cannot afford to compete, which eventually drives them out of business. Increasing prices when production costs increase, setting profit-margin objectives, and using a prestige pricing strategy are legal and ethical business practices. SOURCE: PI:015 SOURCE: InvestorWords.com. (n.d.). Predatory pricing: Definition. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://www.investorwords.com/3770/predatory_pricing.html Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Pricing-analytic software applications enable businesses to ", "choices": ["A. generate price lists for different customers.", "B. automate pricing processes among channel members.", "C. identify favorable pricing strategies.", "D. simulate the impact of pricing changes."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Simulate the impact of pricing changes. Analytic applications enable marketers to input different variables and analyze their outcomes. By analyzing these \u201cwhat if\u201d situations or simulations, marketers can make sound pricing decisions that align with their objectives. Price-execution applications automate pricing processes and generate price lists. Price-optimization applications help marketers identify favorable pricing strategies. SOURCE: PI:016 SOURCE: Syncron. (2016). Price management software. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://www.syncron.com/en/Solutions/price-management-software/ "}, {"number": 73, "question": "In what stage of a product's life cycle might a business price goods very low for the purpose of eliminating excess inventory? ", "choices": ["A. Obsolescence ", "B. Introduction ", "C. Maturity ", "D. Initiation"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Obsolescence. During the obsolescence phase of a product's life cycle, the product is in a state of being outmoded or unfashionable. For example, apparel items experience obsolescence when clothing styles and seasons change. Therefore, retailers often slash prices in an attempt to get rid of old stock. Prices are usually set higher during the introduction stage to enable the business to recover its investment in the new product. During the maturity stage, businesses generally focus their efforts on stabilizing prices. Initiation is not a common term used to describe a phase of a product's life cycle. SOURCE: PI:002 SOURCE: PI LAP 3\u2014Factors Affecting Selling Price "}, {"number": 74, "question": "At what point in the new-product development process does a product's life cycle begin? ", "choices": ["A. Idea generation", "B. Commercialization", "C. Test marketing", "D. Product development"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Commercialization. Commercialization is the step in the new-product development process at which a product goes into full-scale production, the marketing plan is put into place, service and sales training is done, and the product's life cycle begins. Idea generation is the initial step in the new-product development process and involves thinking up or creating new products and modifying existing products. Product development is the step in the new-product development process in which a working model may be tested, modified, and retested. Test marketing involves introducing a product to a limited market to see what its acceptance will be. SOURCE: PM:001 SOURCE: PM LAP 17\u2014Rapping Up Products (Nature of Product/Service Management) "}, {"number": 75, "question": "During the growth stage of the product life cycle, a business's marketing efforts usually involve advertising ", "choices": ["A. that customers are satisfied with the product.", "B. the discounts that are being offered.", "C. that competitors' products are not as popular.", "D. the unique benefits of the product."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "That customers are satisfied with the product. Sales and profits increase during the growth stage of the product life cycle. Many customers are aware of the product and buy the product. To maintain sales, businesses usually start to focus on advertising that customers are satisfied with the product. It is more effective to promote customer satisfaction than to promote the product's benefits because most people are aware of the benefits. People are more likely to continue buying during the growth stage if they think that other people are satisfied with the product. Businesses usually advertise the unique benefits of the product during the introduction stage. Businesses often advertise that competitors' products are not as popular during the maturity stage. Businesses frequently advertise discounts during the decline stage. SOURCE: PM:024 SOURCE: Hill, B. (2016). Different marketing strategies for a product at its growth stage. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://yourbusiness.azcentral.com/different-marketing-strategiesproduct-its-growth-stage-14555.html Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 76, "question": "Why are many businesses looking for ways to reuse products by turning them into new products? ", "choices": ["A. To save money on the process of product development", "B. To solve the ethical problem of planned obsolescence", "C. To encourage customers to buy reconditioned products", "D. To position products as being technologically advanced"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "To solve the ethical problem of planned obsolescence. Because of continual advances in technology, some products become obsolete very quickly. Businesses that make these products are often aware of the ethical issues involved in producing goods that have a short life span because of their effect on the natural resources that are needed to produce them. To handle this problem, some businesses are looking for ways to recycle all or parts of these products and reuse them or turn them into new products. This enables businesses to preserve natural resources and to be ethical while producing products that become obsolete quickly. It is often expensive for businesses to develop ways of reusing products or turning them into new products. The businesses are reusing the products rather than reconditioning them and selling them to customers. Businesses do not turn products into new products to position them as being technologically advanced. SOURCE: PM:040 SOURCE: Perreault, W.D., Cannon, J.P., & McCarthy, E.J. (2008). Basic marketing: A marketing strategy planning approach (16th ed.) [p. 276]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 77, "question": "In the past several years, Jenny noticed that many younger people have moved from her town to larger cities and that a large segment of the town's citizens are reaching retirement age. Jenny realized that there is a growing need for a variety of home health-care services for the town's senior citizens. What factor presented Jenny with this product opportunity? ", "choices": ["A. Demographic changes ", "B. Personal attitudes ", "C. Geographic limitations ", "D. Economic resources"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Demographic changes. A product opportunity is a favorable circumstance that presents itself to provide a good or service that people are willing to buy. Individuals often discover product opportunities by simply being aware of changes that are occurring around them. Demographics are the physical and social characteristics of the population. Age is a demographic characteristic of the population or market segment. As a segment of the population ages, its wants and needs change. When an individual recognizes physical and social changes, s/he has identified a product opportunity due to demographic shifts. Personal attitudes are psychographic factors. Psychographics are a market segment's shared attitudes, opinions, and values. Geographic limitations relate to a specific location or region such as hilliness or a lack of water. Economic resources are the human and natural resources and capital goods used to produce goods and services. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: Brookins, M. (2016). Examples of demographic segmentation. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/examples-demographic-segmentation-12367.html "}, {"number": 78, "question": "Which of the following are creative-thinking techniques that people use to generate product ideas: ", "choices": ["A. Observation and forced analogies", "B. Brainstorming and mind mapping", "C. Unconscious problem solving and research", "D. Morphological analysis and observation"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Brainstorming and mind mapping. Creative-thinking techniques are the specific processes that people use to generate unique ideas, goods, or services. Most creative-thinking techniques can be used by one person or by a group of people. Some creative-thinking techniques are brainstorming, mind mapping, forced analogies, unconscious problem solving, and morphological analysis. Observation is a form of research, which people use to identify market opportunities rather than to generate product ideas. SOURCE: PM:127 SOURCE: PM LAP 127\u2014Unleash Your Mind (Techniques for Generating Product Ideas) "}, {"number": 79, "question": "A salesperson promising to repair or replace a product if it doesn't work properly during a period of time is an example of a(n) ", "choices": ["A. money-back guarantee. ", "B. implied warranty. ", "C. express warranty. ", "D. unconditional guarantee."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Express warranty. An express warranty is a warranty that is written or expressed verbally. It may be an oral promise given by the salesperson to a customer. A salesperson promising to repair or replace a product if it doesn't work properly during a period of time is an example of an express warranty. Then, the business must fulfill the promise to the customers. An implied warranty is an unwritten warranty understood by the consumer and the seller that the product will perform as expected. A money-back guarantee is a promise to refund the consumer's purchase price if the product does not perform as expected. An unconditional guarantee means that a product can be returned at any time for a refund or credit. SOURCE: PM:020 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009) Marketing essentials: Teacher wraparound edition (p. 675). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 80, "question": "Which of the following is not required by the Federal Trade Commission in a writtenwarranty: ", "choices": ["A. How long the warranty is in effect", "B. How to contact government agencies", "C. What kinds of service or repairs are included", "D. Where to take or send the merchandise for service"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "How to contact government agencies. There are many city, state, and federal government agencies that regulate the rights of consumers, but these agencies are not listed in a warranty. Explaining what kind of service or repairs are included, how long the warranty is in effect, and where to take or send the merchandise for service should be included in a written warranty. SOURCE: PM:017 SOURCE: PM LAP 7\u2014Protect and Serve (Consumer Protection) "}, {"number": 81, "question": "A characteristic of product bundling is that the products that are bundled are sold ", "choices": ["A. only at certain times of the year.", "B. for one all-inclusive price.", "C. at heavily discounted rates.", "D. as loss leaders to loyal customers."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "For one all-inclusive price. Product bundling involves combining several products and selling them for one all-inclusive price. Businesses often bundle products to encourage customers to buy products that they might not otherwise want to buy. The all-inclusive price of the bundled products is usually lower than the combined price of the products sold separately. The lower, all-inclusive price is an incentive to buy. Some bundled products may be sold only at certain times of the year, such as lawn care services; however, that is not a characteristic of product bundling. Product bundling does not involve selling at heavily discounted rates or selling the bundles as loss leaders to loyal customers. SOURCE: PM:041 SOURCE: Kokemuller, N. (2016). Product bundling strategy. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/product-bundling-strategy-41789.html "}, {"number": 82, "question": "Marketers position an online business on its simple \u201cone-click ordering\u201d feature. This is positioning by ", "choices": ["A. physical form. ", "B. ease of purchase. ", "C. performance. ", "D. quick delivery."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Ease of purchase. Positioning an online business on its simple ordering process is positioning by ease of purchase. The product may or may not come with quick delivery. The ordering process is not a physical product feature, nor does it relate to the product's performance. SOURCE: PM:042 SOURCE: PM LAP 19\u2014Getting Piece of Mind (Factors Used to Position Products/Services) "}, {"number": 83, "question": "A clothing store wants its customers to know how it differs from other retailers in the area, so it highlights the benefits of shopping at its store to create its image. The store is engaging in ", "choices": ["A. brand extension. ", "B. brand positioning. ", "C. brand licensing. ", "D. co-branding."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Brand positioning. A frequently used brand strategy is brand positioning, the creation of an image or impression of a brand as compared to those of competitors' brands. When a company uses an existing brand name for a new product line, it is known as a brand extension. Brand licensing allows one company to use another's brand name, logo, or character for a fee. Co-branding takes place when companies join forces to increase recognition, customer loyalty, and sales for both brands. SOURCE: PM:021 SOURCE: PM LAP 6\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (Nature of Product Branding) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Which of the following are touch points that a successful company often uses to communicate its corporate brand to its target market: ", "choices": ["A. Employees, sales staff, and compensation policies", "B. Company website, sales calls, and trade shows", "C. Trade shows, sales reports, and employees", "D. Sales calls, company website, and marketing audits"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Company website, sales calls, and trade shows. A corporate brand is all of the combined impressions and experiences associated with a particular company. A successful corporate brand involves developing product and promotional mixes that communicate a desired image of the business. This communication occurs through a variety of touch points. Touch points are the opportunities that the business has to connect with customers and reinforce its brand. Some opportunities that the business has to communicate and reinforce the corporate brand are through the company's website and during sales calls and trade shows. These opportunities involve the efforts of many of the company's employees, including the sales staff. Compensation policies, sales reports, and marketing audits are not targetmarket touch points. SOURCE: PM:206 SOURCE: Qlutch Marketing. (2006-2016). How to communicate a brand at every touchpoint. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from http://www.marketingmo.com/creative-brand-development/how-tocommunicate-a-brand-at-every-touchpoint/ "}, {"number": 85, "question": "A direct benefit to businesses of promotional activities is ", "choices": ["A. debates over controversial issues.", "B. increased product sales.", "C. deceptive advertising.", "D. a reduction in costs."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Increased product sales. Businesses use promotion to \"spread the word\" to consumers that they offer certain products which often result in increased sales. Businesses may also benefit from a more favorable corporate image. Deceptive advertising, added costs, and debates over controversial issues are disadvantages to the business. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: PR LAP 2\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Nature of Promotion) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 86, "question": "An independent organization using part of its website to post letters from satisfied grocery shoppers from Publix groceries is an example of which element of the promotional mix? ", "choices": ["A. Personal selling ", "B. Advertising ", "C. Publicity ", "D. Sales promotion"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Publicity. Publicity is any nonpersonal presentation of ideas, goods, or services that is not paid for by the company or individual which benefits from or is harmed by it. Publix is not paying for the website but is benefitting from the site that posts positive letters from satisfied customers. People who access the site will read the letters and may decide to shop at Publix. Advertising is a paid form of promotion. Personal selling involves interaction between a salesperson and a client. Sales promotion activities are promotional activities other than advertising, personal selling, and publicity. SOURCE: PR:003 SOURCE: Peretti, J. (2014, July 6). SUVs, handwash and FOMO: how the advertising industry embraced fear. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from https://www.theguardian.com/media/2014/jul/06/how-advertising-industry-concept-fear "}, {"number": 87, "question": "What form of unethical advertising leads consumers to believe that if they don't take a certain course of action, they will experience negative consequences? ", "choices": ["A. Infringement ", "B. Subliminal ", "C. Fear-based ", "D. Cause-and-effect"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Fear-based. Fear-based advertising is an extreme form of promotion that motivates an action, such as purchasing a certain product, by focusing on the risk of harm or unfavorable consequences. Subliminal messages contain images that prompt a person to feel or react in a certain manner at a subconscious level. Infringement is an action that violates the rights of another person. Cause-and-effect involves explaining what will happen as a result of a certain action, but it does not necessarily include negative consequences. SOURCE: PR:099 SOURCE: Semenik, R.J. (2002). Promotion and integrated marketing communications (pp. 275-276). Mason, OH: South-Western. "}, {"number": 88, "question": "Governments impose regulations on promotional activities, such as sweepstakes and contests, to reduce incidents that result in ", "choices": ["A. price fixing. ", "B. tax evasion. ", "C. slander. ", "D. fraud."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Fraud. Fraud is a deception purposely carried out to secure unfair or unlawful gain. The nature of promotional activities, such as sweepstakes and contests, indicates that the activities can and have been carried out in ways that deceive or unfairly treat participants. Therefore, governments often develop and enforce laws that protect consumers from deceptive or unfair practices which relate specifically to sweepstakes and contests. Tax evasion occurs when a business avoids paying monies that it owes the government. Slander is a verbal statement that one party makes with the intent to harm another party's character. Price fixing is an illegal agreement in which businesses agree on the prices of their goods and services. SOURCE: PR:101 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [pp. 133, 141, 572]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a direct-mail promotion that businesses often use to contact their target customers: ", "choices": ["A. Catalogs ", "B. News releases ", "C. Magazine ", "D. Press kits"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Catalogs. Many businesses develop catalogs featuring the latest fashions that they mail directly to their target customers. The catalogs advertise items that appeal to the business's potential customers. News releases and press kits are sent to media outlets. Magazines are not a form of direct-mail. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: PR LAP 3\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Promotional Media) "}, {"number": 90, "question": "What is a direct advertising strategy? ", "choices": ["A. Telemarketing ", "B. Merchandising ", "C. Syndicating ", "D. Broadcasting"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Telemarketing. Telemarketing is a promotional medium grouped with \"other media\" that utilizes telephone service to promote a product, either by phoning prospective customers or providing a number for them to call. Telemarketing is considered a direct advertising strategy because it provides direct contact between the business and the customer. Many businesses use telemarketing to inform customers of new goods and services and encourage them to buy. Broadcasting is a promotional media that uses radio waves to reach consumers. Merchandising is the process of having the right goods in the right place at the right time in order to make a profit. Syndicating is not a direct advertising strategy. SOURCE: PR:089 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [p. 635]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 91, "question": "Why do some businesses sponsor local events? ", "choices": ["A. To obtain publicity ", "B. To create news ", "C. To generate revenue ", "D. To sell products"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To obtain publicity. By sponsoring an event, businesses are using the event as a communications channel to provide information to others. The goal of sponsoring an event is to obtain publicity which is any nonpersonal presentation of ideas, goods, or services that is not paid for by the company or individual that benefits from or is harmed by it. In many cases, the media report the event and include information about the sponsors. As a result, the businesses obtain publicity. Businesses that sponsor local events are not creating news. Businesses do not sponsor local events to generate revenue or to sell products. However, by obtaining publicity, they might attract more customers which will result in selling more products and generating more revenue. SOURCE: PR:250 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [pp. 657-658]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an advertisement tag line: ", "choices": ["A. Nationwide is on your side. ", "B. The price is only $5.00 each. ", "C. Sincerely ", "D. Coca Cola"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Nationwide is on your side. A tag line or slogan is a catchy phrase that helps consumers remember the business and its products. Businesses often use tag lines throughout one or more promotional campaigns. Tag lines often appear on billboards, specialty promotional items, television and radio commercials, and in print advertisements. In the example, Nationwide Insurance communicates effectively and simply that it is available to help you by being \"on your side.\" A statement about a price of an item isn't a catchy phrase. Sincerely is word often used to close a business letter. Coca Cola is a brand name. SOURCE: PR:014 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 425-433). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 93, "question": "Which of the following is an activity that is performed by a business's public-relations department: ", "choices": ["A. Coordinating speaking engagements for employees", "B. Researching and developing product prototypes", "C. Developing job descriptions for employees", "D. Selecting media for print and broadcast advertisements"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Coordinating speaking engagements for employees. The public-relations department is a division of a business that is responsible for establishing good relations between the business and its publics. The various publics include the business's target market, its stakeholders, the local business community, its employees, and local residents. One activity that a public-relations department coordinates is speaking engagements for the business's employees. For example, a local civic group might ask the publicrelations department if a member of the business's executive-management staff could speak to the group about a particular issue that is affecting the community. The public-relations department would work with the appropriate employee to schedule the speaking engagement. The research and development department conducts product research and develops product prototypes. Developing job descriptions is a human-resources activity. The advertising department selects media for the business's advertising. SOURCE: PR:252 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [p. 657]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 94, "question": "Which of the following is an example of products being sold indirectly to consumers: ", "choices": ["A. Students selling candy to relatives", "B. Stores renting video games to customers", "C. Friends selling jewelry to friends", "D. Neighbors borrowing items from neighbors"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Stores renting video games to customers. Some goods and services are sold indirectly to the consumer or user through the use of intermediaries, such as wholesalers and retailers. An example is a store renting video games to customers after buying the video games from suppliers. The store is the retailer that provides the product to the customer. Students selling candy to relatives and friends selling jewelry to friends are examples of products being sold directly to the consumer without the use of a wholesaler or retailer. Neighbors borrowing items from neighbors is not an example of products being sold to consumers. SOURCE: SE:017 SOURCE: SE LAP 117\u2014Sell Away (The Nature and Scope of Selling) Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32 "}, {"number": 95, "question": "Because product quality and price can easily be matched, customer service becomes a keycomponent in business ", "choices": ["A. careers. ", "B. competition. ", "C. communications. ", "D. forecasts."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Competition. Because product quality and price can easily be matched, customer service becomes a key component in business competition. In selling, customer service is where the real competition among businesses begins. As a salesperson, you need to show your prospects that your company meets (and hopefully exceeds) customer-service expectations. Customer service is not a key component in business careers, business communication, or business forecasts. SOURCE: SE:076 SOURCE: SE LAP 130\u2014Go Beyond the Sale (Customer Service in Selling) "}, {"number": 96, "question": "Which of the following must a company's sales personnel possess in order to build a loyal clientele: ", "choices": ["A. Appropriate personality traits", "B. Professional awards and achievements", "C. Continued educational training", "D. Extensive technical experience"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Appropriate personality traits. A company's sales personnel must have the appropriate personality traits and attitudes in order to build a loyal clientele for the business. Effective salespeople generally are patient, courteous, friendly, sincere, honest, and trustworthy. These traits can turn a customer into a friend. The personal relationship that is established leads the customer to become a loyal client. Technical experience, professional awards, and continued training may help salespeople to sell, but do not necessarily build a loyal clientele. SOURCE: SE:828 SOURCE: SE LAP 115\u2014Keep Them Loyal (Building Clientele) "}, {"number": 97, "question": "A salesperson leaving one company and taking valuable information about customers to another company may be guilty of ", "choices": ["A. misusing assets. ", "B. breaking a contract. ", "C. offering bribes. ", "D. unethical behavior."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Unethical behavior. Ethics are the basic principles that govern a person's behavior. People who follow those principles and standards are behaving ethically, while people who disregard those principles and standards are behaving unethically. An example of behavior that might be considered unethical is leaving a company and taking valuable information about customers to another company. Salespeople taking specific information about a customer's buying habits, quantities purchased, and prices paid are behaving unethically because that information belongs to the company. Company assets include samples, vehicles, equipment, expense accounts, etc. If a salesperson has a noncompete contract with one company, s/he may be breaking the contract by going to another company. Taking valuable customer information is not an example of offering bribes. SOURCE: SE:106 SOURCE: SE LAP 129\u2014Keep It Real\u2014In Sales (Selling Ethics) "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Which of the following kinds of product information would you use to help a customer who is comparing designer sweaters: ", "choices": ["A. Materials and content ", "B. Pricing information ", "C. Production process ", "D. Product finish"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Materials and content. You can use the information about the composition of products to help solve customer buying problems and to assist customers in comparing similar products. Finishes are used in enhancing the beauty of products, increasing their value, protecting their surfaces, aiding in their care, or providing safety features. Consumers usually are not interested in the technical manufacturing process which determines the quality of a product. Pricing information helps the customer make a buying decision on price alone and does not consider the quality of the merchandise. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: Ward, S. (2016, September 23). Tips for better customer service: how to help a customer. Retrieved December 6, 2016, from https://www.thebalance.com/tips-for-better-customerservice-how-to-help-a-customer-2948070 "}, {"number": 99, "question": "When customers base their buying behavior on facts and logic, they are being influenced by ", "choices": ["A. personal preferences. ", "B. rational motives. ", "C. economic factors. ", "D. individual needs."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Rational motives. Rational motives are reasons for buying that appeal to the sense of reason or judgment. When customers are basing their buying behavior on logic, they are using reason in an orderly way and considering the facts. Rational motives often involve making buying decisions based on saving money or saving time. When customers base their buying behavior on facts and logic, they are not being influenced by personal preferences, economic factors, or individual needs. SOURCE: SE:359 SOURCE: Reference.com. (2016). What are rational buying motives? Retrieved December 6, 2016, from https://www.reference.com/world-view/rational-buying-motives-c99baa03505ac39e Test 1150 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 33 "}, {"number": 100, "question": "Manager Sara Mann has decided that in order to increase business, the sock manufacturing company she works for needs to expand into the children's puppet market. At what level of management is Sara's position? ", "choices": ["A. Middle ", "B. First-line ", "C. Executive ", "D. Supervisory"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Executive. Executive, or top-level, management is responsible for strategic planning, including making the decisions about entering a new market. Middle, or mid-level, management is the link between top and first-line management that would determine what needed to be done in order to enter the new market. First-line, or supervisory, management is made up of the supervisors who work directly with the employees carrying out the directions of top and mid-level management. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: SM LAP 3\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}], "1161-MKT": [{"number": 1, "question": "Which of the following is a way that local zoning laws affect businesses: ", "choices": ["A. Prohibit price discrimination", "B. Restrict placement of billboards", "C. Limit creation of monopolies", "D. Require labels on products"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Restrict placement of billboards. Local zoning laws affect businesses in a variety of ways, such as restricting the placement of billboards. Local communities have the right to regulate where businesses can locate, the physical appearance of the building, and the type of signage that can be used. Communities can also decide if billboards are allowed and where they can be placed. Businesses that want to use billboards to advertise must follow the zoning laws of the community. Zoning laws do not require labels on products, prohibit price discrimination, or limit the creation of monopolies. SOURCE: BL:001 SOURCE: Scenic America. (n.d.). Legal issues and billboards. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.scenic.org/billboards-a-sign-control/legal-issues-and-billboards "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship: ", "choices": ["A. Requiring specific information", "B. Receiving a monetary gift", "C. Obtaining a loan from a bank", "D. Owing punitive damages"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Obtaining a loan from a bank. The debtor is the individual or business that owes money to another individual or business, which is the creditor. A business that obtains a loan from a bank is entering into a voluntary debtor-creditor relationship. It is voluntary because the business (debtor) is seeking to obtain funds from the bank (creditor) by going through a loan application process. A monetary gift is given without expectations of repayment. A monetary gift and a request for information are not examples of debtor-creditor relationships. In tort cases, the court can order one party to pay punitive damages to the other party. This is an example of an involuntary debtor-creditor relationship. SOURCE: BL:071 SOURCE: BizFilings. (2012, May 24). Understanding the debtor-creditor relationship. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.bizfilings.com/toolkit/research-topics/running-yourbusiness/understanding-the-debtorcreditor-relationship "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Every channel of distribution begins with the __________ and ends with the user or consumer. ", "choices": ["A. intermediary", "B. producer", "C. retailer", "D. agent"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Producer. A channel of distribution is the route that a product takes in moving from a producer to a user or consumer. Hence, the producer is always at the beginning of a channel of distribution, and the user is at the end, regardless of the number of channel intermediaries used. Agents, wholesalers, and retailers are intermediaries who may perform specific functions as the product moves through the channel. These intermediaries are part of indirect channels. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: LAP-CM-003\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "How does implementing an electronic data interchange (EDI) system benefit businesses? ", "choices": ["A. It allows trading communities to establish linear distribution strategies.", "B. It increases the use of artificial intelligence systems.", "C. It duplicates the data entry process within the supply chain.", "D. It improves the speed and accuracy of information flow."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It improves the speed and accuracy of information flow. Electronic data interchange is a computer network that links two or more businesses for the exchange of information. Retailers often use EDI systems for reordering inventory with their vendors. Using an EDI system can cut back on paperwork for all businesses, resulting in speedier order processing and reducing the margin of error. The system eliminates duplication of the data entry process. Artificial intelligence systems are computer programs or machines that perform functions that humans carry out. Implementing an EDI system does not necessarily dictate the type of distribution system businesses use and, therefore, does not necessarily create a benefit. SOURCE: CM:004 SOURCE: EDI Basics. (2017). What is EDI (electronic data interchange)? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.edibasics.com/what-is-edi/ "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Marsha got a great deal on a phone that she bought on the Internet. When she had a problem with it, she contacted the manufacturer and was told that the company would not honor the warranty because her phone had been sold by the manufacturer to a company in China. The manufacturer would not honor the warranty because Marsha's phone is an example of a product in the ", "choices": ["A. distribution channel.", "B. product life cycle.", "C. product mix.", "D. gray market."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Gray market. Manufacturers price their products differently based on what a market will bear in a country. Goods are often sold in Asian countries for less than they are in the U.S. and Canada. Eager to make a profit, unscrupulous people buy up the products at the cheap price and resell them in the U.S. or Canada for less than the manufacturers' prices in those countries. A product life cycle is the various stages a product moves through from its inception to its death. A product mix is the combination of products that a business sells. A distribution channel is the route or path a product takes from its producer/provider to the ultimate consumer/industrial user. SOURCE: CM:006 SOURCE: Northrup, L. (2017, May 10). What is the gray market, and why should I care? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://consumerist.com/2013/05/09/what-is-the-gray-market-andwhy-should-i-care/ Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about channel-member relationships in the supply chain: ", "choices": ["A. Members can often reduce conflict by focusing on the common goal of customer satisfaction.", "B. Because the producers are the channel leaders, they usually have more negotiating power.", "C. Technological advancements have made interaction among channel members unnecessary.", "D. To minimize horizontal conflict, most wholesalers in the supply chain charge slotting fees."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Members can often reduce conflict by focusing on the common goal of customer satisfaction. Channel members are all of the businesses or individuals that move goods and services from the producer to the end user. The channel members depend on each other to make sure the end users receive the products when they need them and where they need them. Therefore, it is important for all channel members to remember that their common goal is customer satisfaction, especially when one or more of them disagree about a course of action that another channel member wants to take. Producers are not always channel leaders, nor do they necessarily have more negotiating power. Because the channel members are interdependent, interaction among the members is necessary. Slotting fees may cause a channel conflict rather than reduce it. SOURCE: CM:008 SOURCE: Hoos, D. (2017, April 7). How to overcome channel conflict with retail partners. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://thegood.com/insights/overcoming-channel-conflict/ "}, {"number": 7, "question": "An important factor in effective verbal communication is ", "choices": ["A. reading from a script.", "B. developing mannerisms.", "C. having a pleasant voice.", "D. enunciating rapidly."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Having a pleasant voice. Verbal communication has a much more positive effect on listeners when the speaker has a pleasant voice. Listeners are more likely to concentrate on the speaker's message than they would if the speaker's voice is harsh, unpleasant, or irritating. Enunciating, or pronouncing clearly, is important but should not necessarily be done rapidly. Mannerisms are part of body language, the way you express yourself through posture, facial expression, etc., and these are not forms of verbal communication. While reading from a script is occasionally appropriate, depending on the situation, it is not an important factor in effective verbal communication. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Erupting Mind. (2016, March 28). How to become a better communicator. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.eruptingmind.com/how-to-really-become-a-bettercommunicator/ "}, {"number": 8, "question": "When Jeremy extended his hand toward Hank as they were introduced, Hank said, \"Hello, Jeremy.\" However, he ignored Jeremy's hand and kept his own hands in his pockets. What kind of nonverbal message was Hank sending? ", "choices": ["A. We have met before.", "B. I am glad to meet you.", "C. We have a lot in common.", "D. I don't want to know you."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "I don't want to know you. There are several situations in which nonverbal communication is a better indicator of a person's attitude than words. In this situation, Hank has made a polite verbal response, but he has indicated by refusing to shake hands that he is not glad to meet Jeremy and does not really want to know Jeremy. Even if they had met before, shaking hands would have been appropriate. SOURCE: CO:059 SOURCE: Roberts, S.J. (2012). Fundamentals of business communication (pp. 30-32). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. "}, {"number": 9, "question": "What type of communication style is usually most appropriate to use when evaluating employees? ", "choices": ["A. Formal", "B. Casual", "C. Routine", "D. Instructional"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Formal. Different communication styles are appropriate for different situations and for different audiences. When conducting evaluation or counseling interviews with employees, it is usually appropriate to use a formal communication style. The person conducting the interview is in a position of authority and may be discussing problems or behavioral issues with an employee. Maintaining a formal communication style will help the interviewer to remain in control and provide the guidance that may be necessary. Casual and routine communication styles usually are appropriate for discussions between friends or coworkers on the same level. An instructional style may be appropriate when communicating information about how to perform specific tasks. SOURCE: CO:084 SOURCE: Rawes, E.M. (2010, December 9). Types of communication in the workplace. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.ehow.com/info_7742528_types-communicationworkplace.html Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 10, "question": "Which of the following should you be sure to do when taking notes: ", "choices": ["A. Write in complete sentences.", "B. Use correct spelling and grammar.", "C. Write as legibly as possible.", "D. Try to write down everything the teacher says."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Write as legibly as possible. Even though you may be writing your notes quickly, it's important to write as neatly as you can. After all, your notes won't be very helpful if you can't even read them later! You shouldn't worry about using correct spelling and grammar when taking notes. It's more important to focus on content. You also don't need to write in complete sentences. This will only slow down your notetaking. It's impossible to write down everything the teacher says; instead, just try to capture the main points and important information. SOURCE: CO:085 SOURCE: Stanford University. (2017, June 27). Study tips resources: Note taking (various methods). Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://vptl.stanford.edu/students/academic-skills/studytips-resources "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Identify the type of appeal used in the following persuasive message: \"This new book is written by Dr. Juliet Browne, who holds a doctorate from the Harvard School of Medicine and is the Chair of the World Health Organization.\" ", "choices": ["A. Shock value", "B. Reason", "C. Emotions", "D. Credibility"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Credibility. Credibility is achieved when the audience has confidence in the persuader. In this case, Dr. Browne's prestigious job title and degree lead the audience to believe she is a credible source. Reason is when logic is used to persuade someone to do something. It often involves solid facts and statistics. An emotional appeal affects the audience's feelings, such as sympathy or love. An appeal that uses shock value is a form of an emotional appeal that includes information that the audience would find shocking. SOURCE: CO:031 SOURCE: McIntyre, M., & McKee, J. (2012, April 16). Ethos. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://writingcommons.org/index.php/open-text/information-literacy/rhetoricalanalysis/rhetorical-appeals/585-ethos "}, {"number": 12, "question": "A characteristic of simple memorandums written by business employees is that they usually are intended to be read by a(n) ", "choices": ["A. internal audience.", "B. board of directors.", "C. planning committee.", "D. group of suppliers."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Internal audience. Memorandums are a type of simple written report that business employees often prepare to provide information to others within the business. Since memorandums are usually intended to be read by an internal audience, they are less formal and shorter than traditional business letters. They often provide information about the progress of current projects or an explanation of upcoming events. Not all businesses have boards of directors or planning committees. However, these are examples of internal audiences that may, or may not, receive memorandums. A group of suppliers is an external audience. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: Kaiser, K. (n.d.) Memorandums and letters. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://writingcommons.org/chapters/professional-technical-communication/memosproposals-reports/798-memorandums-and-letters "}, {"number": 13, "question": "A disadvantage of problem-solving in groups is that it ", "choices": ["A. hinders communication.", "B. decreases conformity.", "C. decreases risk-taking.", "D. takes more time."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Takes more time. Group problem-solving takes more time than individual problem-solving because of conflicting schedules, differing opinions, and more discussion. Group problem-solving increases conformity and risk-taking, rather than decreasing them. Finally, group problem-solving increases communication rather than hindering it. SOURCE: CO:067 SOURCE: Hadler, G. (2005-2016). Solving problems using a group - Advantages and disadvantages. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.itseducation.asia/groups.htm "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Businesses must keep in mind that word-of-mouth promotion can be ", "choices": ["A. bought.", "B. avoided.", "C. negative.", "D. inconsequential."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Negative. Businesses must keep in mind that word-of-mouth promotion can be negative as well as positive. It's important for businesses to build positive customer relations so word-of-mouth promotion will work in their favor since it cannot be avoided, cannot be bought, and is very powerful. SOURCE: CR:003 SOURCE: LAP-CR-001\u2014Accentuate the Positive (Nature of Customer Relations) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 15, "question": "When management establishes policies that help employees to deal with customers in the same way, under the same circumstances, the main purpose of these policies is the ", "choices": ["A. fair treatment of customers.", "B. reduction of expenses.", "C. satisfaction of customers' wants.", "D. smooth operation of the business."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Fair treatment of customers. Clear policies give employees guidelines to follow and help to reduce misunderstandings that create bad feelings. Fair treatment of customers is not an expense-reduction measure. Satisfying customers' wants is not possible since wants are constantly changing. The business may run more smoothly if customers are treated fairly, but that is not the main purpose of the policy. SOURCE: CR:007 SOURCE: Government of South Australia Equal Opportunity Commission. (2011, July 1). Developing your customer complaint policy. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.eoc.sa.gov.au/eo-business/shops-and-services/shops-and-servicestoolkit/developing-your-customer-complaint-policy "}, {"number": 16, "question": "Some natural resources are plentiful but are expensive and difficult to ", "choices": ["A. obtain.", "B. use.", "C. sell.", "D. conserve."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Obtain. Although many of the earth's resources are plentiful, some of them are difficult to obtain. For example, it is difficult and expensive to drill for the vast oil reserves on the floor of the ocean. Natural resources usually are not difficult to use or sell. The fact that some resources are difficult to obtain can help to conserve them. SOURCE: EC:001 SOURCE: LAP-EC-006\u2014Are You Satisfied? (Economics and Economic Activities) "}, {"number": 17, "question": "When the demand for a product increases, a producer will normally increase the quantity of product supplied. In this situation, what will usually happen to the product's price? ", "choices": ["A. The price will increase.", "B. The price is not affected.", "C. The price will decrease.", "D. The price will remain constant."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The price will increase. In this situation, a producer will normally increase the price in order to maximize profits. A decrease in the price would not achieve a maximum profit margin. Similarly, leaving prices at their present level would not maximize the advantage achieved through increased demand. SOURCE: EC:006 SOURCE: LAP-EC-012\u2014When More Is Less (Functions of Prices) "}, {"number": 18, "question": "The owner of a small retail store has decided to offer designer jeans for the back-to-school campaign. Which of the following business activities should be used to inform the potential customers about the new items for sale: ", "choices": ["A. Production", "B. Financial analysis", "C. Marketing", "D. Strategic management"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Marketing. Marketing is a primary business activity that involves creating, communicating, and delivering value to customers and managing customer relationships in ways that benefit the organization and its stakeholders. The communication, or promotion, aspect provides a connecting link between businesses and consumers by explaining the goods and services available for sale. Financial analysis, production, and strategic management are not used to inform the potential customers about new items for sale. SOURCE: EC:071 SOURCE: LAP-EC-019\u2014Strictly Business (Business Activities) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "A car dealership purchases new cars from a Ford factory and then sells them to consumers. What type of business model is this? ", "choices": ["A. Trader", "B. Manufacturer", "C. Distributor", "D. Importer"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Distributor. A distributor purchases products from a manufacturer and then resells them. A car dealership purchases new cars from the Ford manufacturer and resells them to customers. A manufacturer, such as a Ford factory, creates products out of raw materials (or premade parts). Traders and importers are not types of business models. SOURCE: EC:138 SOURCE: Job, A. (2016, August 15). Types of business models. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.entrepreneurmag.co.za/advice/starting-a-business/business-model/types-ofbusiness-models/ "}, {"number": 20, "question": "How does innovation support a business's long-term survival? ", "choices": ["A. By decreasing organizational conflict", "B. By making it impossible for employees to predict what's coming next", "C. By enabling a business to cut costs", "D. By giving a business a competitive edge"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "By giving a business a competitive edge. Innovation is key for a business's long-term survival outlook. It must constantly look for ways to improve products, develop new products or processes, obtain new markets, etc., if it is to survive in today's marketplace. When a business innovates, it obtains an advantage over its competitors that enables the business to attract customers. Although innovation may be disruptive to the way things have always been done, it doesn't make it impossible for employees to predict what's coming next. Although some innovations may cut costs, not all of them do. Innovation does not relate to organizational conflict. SOURCE: EC:107 SOURCE: LAP-EC-107\u2014Keep the Change (Adapting to Markets) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 21, "question": "The owner of Bonnie's Birds and Bugs realizes that she cannot completely protect her building from the possibility of fire. What would be the best means of dealing with this risk? ", "choices": ["A. Retain the risk", "B. Prevent the risk", "C. Avoid the risk", "D. Transfer the risk"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Transfer the risk. Along with reasonable prevention, risks may be transferred to some other person or business. This would most effectively be done through the purchase of insurance. Preventing the risk means to absolutely prevent the possibility of fire, which is not realistic. If fire were to occur, even after thorough prevention, the business would experience a great financial loss if it was not insured. Retaining the risk means to do nothing about the risk. This would be an ineffective means of dealing with this particular risk. Avoiding the risk means to recognize and then avoid or eliminate the risk completely. It would be very difficult to completely avoid or eliminate the risk of fire. SOURCE: EC:011 SOURCE: LAP-EC-003\u2014Lose, Win, or Draw (Business Risk) "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Union and management officials are meeting next week to determine the terms and conditions that will be provided to employees. This process is known as ", "choices": ["A. striking.", "B. collective bargaining.", "C. picketing.", "D. corporate campaigning."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Collective bargaining. Collective bargaining is the process in which unions and company officials engage to determine worker contracts. Strikes occur when the collective bargaining process breaks down, and the employees refuse to work. When employees picket, they stand outside the company to protest such things as company policies and pay scales. In a corporate campaign, dissatisfied union members might disrupt a company's shareholder meetings or even attempt to buy up stock and gain more control of the company. SOURCE: EC:015 SOURCE: LAP-EC-005\u2014Get United (Organized Labor) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Randy used to work in a factory. However, after technological advances brought robots that could do the same job for less money, he was laid off. Randy is looking for a new job in a factory, but everything requires knowledge of computer programs, which he doesn't have. Randy is facing __________ unemployment. ", "choices": ["A. cyclical", "B. frictional", "C. structural", "D. seasonal"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Structural. Structural unemployment occurs when workers' skills don't match up with the jobs available. This often happens when there are technological advances, like in Randy's situation. Although he is a skilled worker, the jobs available need a different set of skills. In Randy's case, his best option is to get more education or training so he will have the necessary skills to become employed again. Frictional unemployment occurs when the right jobs and workers just haven't been matched up. Unlike with structural employment, there is a job that utilizes the employee's skills, but s/he just hasn't found it yet. Cyclical unemployment happens when there's an overall decline in the economy. For example, when a recession hits, fewer people are able to find employment. This is not the case for Randy, as there are plenty of jobs. He just doesn't have the skills necessary for any of them. Seasonal unemployment is predictable and expected in many industries. For example, teachers aren't usually employed in the summer. SOURCE: EC:082 SOURCE: LAP-EC-029\u2014Help Wanted? (Impact of Unemployment Rates) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "What do individuals often identify when assessing their personal strengths and weaknesses? ", "choices": ["A. Risks", "B. Careers", "C. Benefits", "D. Interests"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Interests. Interests are the things that a person is curious about, concerned for, or involved with. When assessing their personal strengths and weaknesses, people often identify their interests because interests are strong points that might lead to appropriate occupations. For example, an individual works on the school newspaper, likes to create posters for upcoming events, and belongs to the English club. These interests are this person's strengths. After assessing personal strengths and weaknesses, individuals might select suitable careers. Assessing personal strengths and weaknesses does not involve identifying benefits or risks. SOURCE: EI:002 SOURCE: LAP-EI-017\u2014Assess for Success (Assessing Personal Strengths and Weaknesses) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "The act of deliberately giving a wrong or false impression of something is considered to be ", "choices": ["A. poor communications.", "B. dishonest.", "C. tactless.", "D. good business."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Dishonest. One form of dishonesty is lying or deliberately misleading others by giving a wrong or false impression. This is not a form of good business, but bad business\u2014as it creates mistrust in the minds of customers. Poor communications are ineffective efforts to provide information, not deliberate efforts to deceive. Being tactless is lacking in tact, the ability to do or say the right thing in a given situation. SOURCE: EI:022 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 221). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 26, "question": "We know we are being treated fairly when we ", "choices": ["A. are being treated better than others.", "B. get our way and receive the outcomes we want.", "C. feel happy and satisfied with others' decisions.", "D. are being treated the way we deserve to be treated."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Are being treated the way we deserve to be treated. Our general understanding of fairness usually means that we feel that we are being treated the way we deserve. It does not always mean getting our way and receiving the outcomes we want. Fairness also does not always mean we feel happy and satisfied with others' decisions. Fairness does not mean that we are being treated better than others. SOURCE: EI:127 SOURCE: LAP-EI-127\u2014Fair or Foul? (Demonstrating Fairness) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "If you cannot take the blame for your mistakes, then ", "choices": ["A. you will never be successful.", "B. your friends will likely take the blame for you.", "C. you cannot take the credit for your successes.", "D. it will be difficult to graduate."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "You cannot take the credit for your successes. If you cannot take the blame for your mistakes, then you cannot take the credit for your successes\u2014because you've given up control over your own life. To be responsible, a person must assume accountability for all of his/her actions and decisions. Your friends may or may not take the blame for you. Not taking the blame for your mistakes doesn't necessarily mean you'll never be successful or will have difficulty graduating, but it will certain cause other problems in your life. SOURCE: EI:075 SOURCE: LAP-EI-075\u2014It's Up to You (Taking Responsibility for Decisions and Actions) "}, {"number": 28, "question": "It is considered unethical for an employee to spread malicious gossip about a coworker because the gossip may ", "choices": ["A. earn the person a promotion.", "B. make the person uncomfortable.", "C. damage the person's reputation.", "D. affect the person's social life."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Damage the person's reputation. Gossip that may hurt a person or damage that person's reputation or character is malicious. Employees who spread malicious gossip about coworkers are behaving unethically. If an employee hears malicious gossip about a coworker, that employee should refuse to pass on the information. Employees who try to stop the spread of malicious gossip are behaving ethically because most gossip is inaccurate. Spreading malicious gossip may make people uncomfortable or affect their social lives, but those are not reasons it is unethical. Malicious gossip probably will not earn a person a promotion. SOURCE: EI:038 SOURCE: Conlan, C. (2017). 4 ways to handle gossip at work. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.monster.com/career-advice/article/ways-to-handle-gossip-at-work "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Alicia is trying to persuade members of her work team to implement a new process. Because Alicia used this process with her former employer, she is very knowledgeable and knows what needs to be done to make a smooth transition. The work team is likely to go along with the change because Alicia has ", "choices": ["A. exhibited cultural sensitivity.", "B. established personal credibility.", "C. demonstrated empathy.", "D. coached others effectively."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Established personal credibility. Credibility is believability. To be able to persuade others, individuals need to be credible so others believe what they say. Individuals who are credible have a reputation of providing accurate information in a fair manner. They are well-informed and use reliable sources to support their opinions and ideas. As a result, others believe them and often are persuaded to do what they want. Because Alicia is an honest person who has prior experience with the process, she has credibility. There is not enough information provided to determine if Alicia has exhibited cultural sensitivity, demonstrated empathy, or coached others effectively. SOURCE: EI:012 SOURCE: LAP-EI-121\u2014Win Them Over (Persuading Others) "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Often, people can creatively resolve a conflict by ", "choices": ["A. brainstorming.", "B. debating.", "C. deciding.", "D. mediating."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Brainstorming. Many people use brainstorming to come up with ideas to resolve conflicts. Brainstorming is a creative-thinking technique involving the identification of as many different ideas as possible during a certain time frame. Debating is disagreeing. Deciding is choosing among alternatives. Mediating is a process that involves asking a neutral third party to help resolve a conflict. It is not considered a creative solution. SOURCE: EI:015 SOURCE: LAP-EI-007\u2014Stop the Madness (Conflict Resolution in Business) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Zane is feeling overwhelmed about his stressful job. Which action should he take to manage his stress? ", "choices": ["A. Talk through the situation with a friend or coworker.", "B. Create an employee survey for his coworkers.", "C. Take on a greater amount of work.", "D. Skip work often so that he has time to relax."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Talk through the situation with a friend or coworker. Sharing your feelings with others is one way to manage stress. Holding stress inside doesn't make it go away\u2014in fact, it usually just makes it worse. Talking through problems with a friend or trusted coworker can often reduce stress. Creating an employee survey is a way that employers can identify stress. Zane should not take on a greater amount of work or skip work often. SOURCE: EI:028 SOURCE: LAP-EI-025\u2014Keep Your Cool (Stress Management) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Once a coach has helped a coachee establish an improvement plan, it is important for the coach to ", "choices": ["A. give monetary rewards to the coachee.", "B. set goals for the coachee.", "C. give harsh feedback to the coachee.", "D. track the coachee's progress."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Track the coachee's progress. Once a coach and coachee have developed an improvement plan, the coach must track the coachee's progress and provide support whenever possible. A coach and coachee must work together to set goals before an action or improvement plan can be implemented. A coach should provide constructive criticism so it comes across as helpful, instead of harsh. Harsh criticism tends to make coachees feel defensive. A coach does not always give monetary rewards to the coachee. SOURCE: EI:041 SOURCE: LAP-EI-041\u2014Bring Out the Best (Coaching Others) "}, {"number": 33, "question": "One benefit of assessing the long-term value and impact of your actions on others is helping you to act ", "choices": ["A. more ethically.", "B. on behalf of your business.", "C. in your own best interest.", "D. your age."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "More ethically. One benefit of assessing the long-term value and impact of your actions on others is helping you to act more ethically (with integrity and honesty). Considering the needs of others is an important part of ethical behavior. Assessing the long-term value and impact of your actions on others won't necessarily help you to act on behalf of your business, in your own best interest, or your age. SOURCE: EI:137 SOURCE: LAP-EI-137\u2014Choose for the Future (Assessing the Long-Term Value and Impact of Actions on Others) "}, {"number": 34, "question": "Following your teacher's guidelines is an example of which ethical principle? ", "choices": ["A. Viability", "B. Transparency", "C. Trust", "D. Rule of law"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Rule of law. Although the rules at your school and work are not laws, it's still ethically important to follow them. Following your teacher's rules is not an example of trust, viability, or transparency. SOURCE: EI:123 SOURCE: LAP-EI-123\u2014Rules to Live By (Nature of Ethics) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Cornell wants to start his own business, but he isn't exactly sure what product or service he wants to pursue at the moment. The first step of the entrepreneurial process that Cornell should focus on is ", "choices": ["A. idea generation.", "B. a feasibility study.", "C. illumination.", "D. verification."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Idea generation. Coming up with an idea is the first step in the entrepreneurial process; without an initial idea, none of the other steps can be completed. A feasibility study is conducted to see if the idea is viable. Two steps in the feasibility study are illumination (where the idea becomes realistic) and verification (where the idea is found to be practical and useful). SOURCE: EN:039 SOURCE: Chand, S. (2014, February 8). Entrepreneurship: Characteristics, importance, types, and functions of entrepreneurship. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.yourarticlelibrary.com/entrepreneur/entrepreneurship-characteristicsimportancetypes-and-functions-of-entrepreneurship/5228/ "}, {"number": 36, "question": "In an ancient society, townspeople used cows to pay for the things they needed. The cows are an example of __________ money. ", "choices": ["A. commodity", "B. representative", "C. fiat", "D. paper"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Commodity. Commodity money is a physical item that has value on its own. A cow, for example, has value even if it is not being used as money. Fiat money is not backed by a commodity. Instead, it has value because the government says it does. Representative money can be traded in for something valuable. A cow is not an example of paper money. SOURCE: FI:059 SOURCE: Money Instructor. (2002-2017). What is money? The evolution of money. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.moneyinstructor.com/doc/moneyevolution.asp "}, {"number": 37, "question": "Saving money helps you achieve __________ goals, while investing money helps you achieve __________ goals. ", "choices": ["A. long-term; career", "B. long-term; short-term", "C. career; short-term", "D. short-term; long-term"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Short-term; long-term. Saving money involves putting away a portion of your income to use in the future. This may involve placing money in a savings account where you can easily withdraw the funds when you need them. Saving money can help you achieve your short-term goals such as buying a new computer or taking a trip. Often, people use their savings to make investments. Investing money involves using money to make money. By investing your money, you can make more money than you can with just income and savings. The money you make from your investments can help you achieve your long-term goals such as funding your children's college education, starting your own business, or using it for living expenses when you retire. Your career goals involve your vocation, occupation, or profession and do not always involve saving or investing money. SOURCE: FI:270 SOURCE: The Money Advice Service. (n.d.). Should I save or invest my money? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.moneyadviceservice.org.uk/en/articles/should-i-save-or-invest Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Morgan received an email that claimed to be from her credit card company. The email said that her account would be cancelled immediately if she didn't follow a link and enter her credit card and social security numbers. After Morgan did so, she found out that the email wasn't actually from her credit card company. Instead, it was a scam designed to steal her personal information. Morgan was a victim of ", "choices": ["A. phishing.", "B. baiting.", "C. skimming.", "D. hacking."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Phishing. Phishing occurs when a scammer sends out an email pretending to be a legitimate company, such as a credit card company, in order to gain personal information. The phisher typically sends readers to a fake website that asks them to enter personal information, which can include credit card numbers, social security numbers, bank account numbers, etc. It's a good idea to be especially suspicious of any requests for personal information you receive online. Avoid giving out personal information unless you contact the company yourself. Skimming occurs when a thief runs a credit card through a \"skimmer\" to steal personal information. Hacking involves a person gaining access to a computer system to steal information. Baiting is not a term commonly used to describe phishing. SOURCE: FI:073 SOURCE: Microsoft Safety & Security Center. (2017). How to recognize phishing email messages, links, or phone calls. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.microsoft.com/enus/safety/online-privacy/phishing-symptoms.aspx "}, {"number": 39, "question": "The biggest risk to a real estate investment is ", "choices": ["A. inability to write checks.", "B. low rate of return.", "C. not being FDIC-insured.", "D. depreciation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Depreciation. The biggest risk to a real estate investment is depreciation. If property values go down, the investor will not make a return and could even lose money. Only bank accounts are FDIC-insured, so not having that advantage does not necessarily make real estate a riskier investment than any other ownership investment. The same goes for the inability to write checks\u2014this is not an advantage any other ownership investments have, either. As with most ownership investments, real estate has the potential for a high rate of return. SOURCE: FI:077 SOURCE: LAP-FI-077\u2014Invest for Success (Types of Investments) "}, {"number": 40, "question": "When John was injured in an auto accident on his way to work, what kind of insurance paid his hospital bill? ", "choices": ["A. Term", "B. Disability", "C. Health", "D. Life"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Health. Health insurance covers such medical expenses as hospital bills, doctors' fees, lab charges, and other medical costs. Disability insurance is sometimes called loss-of-income insurance because it pays a percentage of a worker's normal wages to the worker when s/he cannot work because of an illness or injury. Life insurance pays a sum of money at the time of death. Term is a form of life insurance that covers a specific number of years. SOURCE: FI:081 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., & Hughes, R.J. (2009). Personal finance (9th ed.) [pp. 343-344]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Finemart's bookkeeper journalizes the business's income and expenditures at the time they occur even if no money changes hands at that time. Finemart uses the __________ accounting method to record transactions. ", "choices": ["A. managerial", "B. cash", "C. accrual", "D. tax"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Accrual. Businesses using the accrual accounting method journalize income and expenditures at the time they occur even if no money changes hands at that time. This means that the business enters the amount of a transaction into the appropriate journal when a customer makes a credit purchase, or when the business orders goods from a supplier. Businesses using the cash accounting method record income and expenditures at the time the money changes hands. This means that the business enters the amount of a transaction into one of its journals on the day the money is received from a customer or paid out to a creditor. Managerial accounting involves reporting financial data to internal users. Tax accounting involves recording transactions for tax purposes. Finemart does not use the cash accounting method, and there is no indication that it is using managerial accounting or tax accounting to record transactions, either. SOURCE: FI:085 SOURCE: LAP-FI-085\u2014Show Me the Money (Nature of Accounting) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 42, "question": "Why do some governments require businesses to use specific accounting methods? ", "choices": ["A. To provide external sources with accurate financial information", "B. To ensure that the businesses are complying with intellectual property laws", "C. To control the ways in which businesses develop credit policies", "D. To monitor how businesses establish their sales goals and budgets"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To provide external sources with accurate financial information. The accounting function collects and records the financial information in the appropriate format. Governments require businesses to provide certain types of financial information to regulatory agencies and shareholders in specific ways. For example, some governments require large businesses to use a specific accounting method, such as the accrual method. The accrual accounting method records transactions at the time they occur even if no money changes hands at that time. An advantage of using the accrual method is that it provides investors, creditors, and customers with a more accurate picture of a business's cash flow over time. Governments do not require businesses to use a specific accounting method to ensure that they are complying with intellectual property laws, to control the ways in which businesses develop credit policies, or to monitor how businesses establish sales goals and budgets. SOURCE: FI:353 SOURCE: Fishman, S. (2017). Cash vs. accrual accounting. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/cash-vs-accrual-accounting-29513.html "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an employee-assistance program: ", "choices": ["A. Training on the use of dangerous power equipment", "B. Compensation", "C. Career and education planning", "D. Corrective action"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Career and education planning. Career and education planning is an example of an employee-assistance program a company may offer. Employee-assistance programs are part of the HR management activity of employee relations. Compensation is pay for work completed, not extra assistance. Training on the use of dangerous power equipment is a compliance issue. Corrective action is a training and development issue that occurs when an employee's performance is not up to standard. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: LAP-HR-035\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Businesses that obtain information about competitors with the use of questionable techniques, even though these techniques are legal, are often behaving ", "choices": ["A. aggressively.", "B. unethically.", "C. carelessly.", "D. recklessly."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Unethically. Unethical behavior is behavior that is wrong or immoral. It is often considered unethical to obtain information about competitors with the use of questionable techniques, even though these techniques are legal. For example, it is illegal to take aerial photographs of a competitor's facility, but it is not illegal to purchase aerial photographs from governmental agencies that have obtained them for other purposes. However, buying those photographs with the intent of obtaining information about a competitor's operation is usually considered to be unethical. Using questionable techniques to obtain information is not an example of being reckless, aggressive, or careless. SOURCE: IM:025 SOURCE: LAP-IM-025\u2014Info With Integrity (Ethics in Marketing-Information Management) "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Which situation is an example of SUGGING? ", "choices": ["A. A salesperson offers a customer the opportunity to try an expensive product free of charge.", "B. A telemarketer asks a customer if s/he knows anyone who would want to buy a certain product.", "C. A marketer tells a customer that s/he is conducting research, and then begins a sales pitch.", "D. A business promotes a product by sending samples to its customers without authorization."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "A marketer tells a customer that s/he is conducting research, and then begins a sales pitch. SUGGING is an acronym for \"selling under the guise of research.\" SUGGING is an unethical practice in which a marketer pretends to conduct research but, in fact, is really attempting to sell a good or service to a consumer. SUGGING is deceptive and rarely facilitates a long-term selling relationship. It also harms the integrity of the general marketing-research field because potential respondents who have been subjected to SUGGING are less likely to trust researchers and are likely to question their true motives. A telemarketer who asks a person if s/he knows anyone who might buy a certain product is trying to obtain a referral. Sending samples to consumers is a promotional technique. A salesperson providing a customer the opportunity to try a product for a certain period of time is implementing a strategy to make a sale. SOURCE: IM:419 SOURCE: Mordecai, V. (2014, October 9). Sugging is not (good) market research. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.insightsassociation.org/article/sugging-not-good-marketresearch Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 46, "question": "A marketing-research project that gathers sufficient information to help the business in its decisionmaking would be described as ", "choices": ["A. thorough.", "B. efficient.", "C. tedious.", "D. predictive."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Thorough. An important characteristic of effective marketing research is that it should be thorough. Incomplete or insufficient research won't give the business enough information to enable it to make good decisions. The way in which the research is carried out would determine whether or not it was efficient. Predictive research is marketing research used to help the business forecast future business developments. Some aspects of marketing research are tedious, tiresome, monotonous, or boring, but these aspects are not necessarily related to the amount of information gathered. SOURCE: IM:010 SOURCE: LAP-IM-010\u2014Seek and Find (Marketing Research) "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about qualitative research: ", "choices": ["A. It is based on statistics and facts.", "B. It is often conducted through experiments.", "C. It uses large samples of the population.", "D. It is conducted during a short time frame."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It is conducted during a short time frame. Qualitative research is conducted during a short timeframe. It uses small samples of the population and is based on subjective data\u2014thoughts, feeling, experiences, emotions, etc. Quantitative research uses experiments as a method; qualitative research relies more on questionnaires, focus groups, informal interview, etc. SOURCE: IM:281 SOURCE: LAP-IM-015\u2014What's the Source? (Obtaining Marketing-Research Data) "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Which of the following is determined in a research project's master plan: ", "choices": ["A. How much data to collect", "B. The company's target market", "C. How much the marketers will be paid", "D. The purpose of the research"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "How much data to collect. A research project's master plan, known as the research design, determines the types of data needed, how much data to collect, what collection methods to use, and how the data will be analyzed. The company should already know its target market and the purpose of the research before creating a research design. The research design does not include information about how much marketers will be paid. SOURCE: IM:284 SOURCE: LAP-IM-284\u2014Better by Design (Marketing Research Designs) "}, {"number": 49, "question": "Which probability design allows marketers to study distinct groups within the target population? ", "choices": ["A. Simple random sampling", "B. Stratified random sampling", "C. Systematic random sampling", "D. Cluster sampling"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Stratified random sampling. Stratified random sampling is a probability sampling method in which researchers break the target population down into non-overlapping groups and draw simple random samples from each one. The results are representative, yet marketers still have the ability to study distinct subgroups within the population. Simple random sampling is a probability sampling method in which every sampling unit has a known and equal chance of being selected. Systematic random sampling is a probability sampling method in which researchers place sampling units into a random list and draw a sample using a skip interval. Cluster sampling is a probability sampling method in which researchers divide the target population into non-overlapping subpopulations that are determined by geography and then randomly sample each one. SOURCE: IM:285 SOURCE: LAP-IM-016\u2014Take Your Pick (Nature of Sampling Plans) "}, {"number": 50, "question": "What type of marketing data can a business obtain by reviewing its inventory reports and customers' invoices? ", "choices": ["A. Customers' credit limits", "B. Customers' product preferences", "C. Product quality", "D. Actual market share"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Customers' product preferences. Internal records provide businesses with information about their customers' buying habits and product usage. By reviewing inventory reports, a business can determine which products are selling well and which products are moving slowly. This information may prompt the business to phase out the slow moving product and increase promotional efforts for the products that are selling well. Customers' invoices provide information about an individual customer's buying preferences and habits. For example, invoices might reveal that certain customers buy a certain quantity of a particular product four times a month. By knowing this type of information, the business can customize promotions for its customers and take steps to ensure that it has sufficient product on hand when it is needed. Financial reports provide information about customers' credit status and limits. Customer invoices do not provide information about a product's level of quality. Businesses need to analyze industry and competitors' data and compare them with internal data to evaluate their market share. SOURCE: IM:184 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 594-595). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 51, "question": "Listing the number of respondents who answered \"agree,\" \"no opinion,\" or \"disagree\" to each question on a marketing questionnaire is an example of ", "choices": ["A. tabulation.", "B. proportion.", "C. deviation.", "D. association."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Tabulation. In many cases, processing marketing information involves tabulating the results. Tabulating is counting the number of respondents who answered each question with one of the possible answers. For example, if 100 people answered a questionnaire, researchers need to know how many of them agreed, disagreed, or had no opinion about the questions. Also, tabulating helps researchers to determine if some people did not answer all the questions, which might have an effect on the accuracy of the information. Listing the number of respondents who answered a certain way to each question is not an example of deviation, proportion, or association. SOURCE: IM:062 SOURCE: QuickMBA. (1999-2010). Marketing research. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.quickmba.com/marketing/research/ "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Interviewers cause marketing-research errors when they ", "choices": ["A. allow respondents to answer questions honestly.", "B. communicate clearly with respondents.", "C. ask the respondents to answer all of the questions.", "D. express a biased attitude when asking questions."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Express a biased attitude when asking questions. If an interviewer uses a particular tone of voice, emotionally charged words, or expresses personal or biased opinions during an interview, respondents may feel uncomfortable and less willing to provide honest answers. When respondents do not answer interview questions honestly, the integrity of the marketing research is compromised. To reduce risks associated with improper interviewing techniques, interviewers should receive proper training, which helps them learn how to ask questions in an objective manner. Communicating clearly, ensuring that respondents answer all of the questions, and allowing respondents to answer questions honestly are ways in which interviewers can reduce the risk of marketing-research errors. SOURCE: IM:292 SOURCE: Churchill, G.A., Brown, T.J., & Suter, T.A. (2010). Basic marketing research (7th ed.) [pp. 382-383, 390]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 53, "question": "The belief that profitable sales volume will result from giving customers quality products at fair and reasonable prices is part of the ", "choices": ["A. planning process.", "B. marketing concept.", "C. marketing mix.", "D. consumers' movement."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Marketing concept. The marketing concept expresses a philosophy of conducting business that is based on the belief that all business activities should be aimed toward satisfying consumer wants and needs while achieving company goals. Product planning, pricing, promoting, and distributing goods and services are elements of the marketing mix. The consumers' movement refers to organized efforts by consumers to establish fairness, quality, and safety in the marketplace. SOURCE: MK:001 SOURCE: LAP-MK-004\u2014Have It Your Way! (Nature of Marketing) "}, {"number": 54, "question": "When a local athletic apparel store sells shoes, clothing, and accessories that are designed specifically for runners, it is using ____________ segmentation. ", "choices": ["A. geographic", "B. psychographic", "C. demographic", "D. rate of usage"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Psychographic. Market segmentation is dividing the market into groups that have similar characteristics. Segmenting markets helps businesses identify the people who are most likely to buy their products. Businesses segment markets in different ways. In the example, the athletic apparel store used psychographics to divide the market, which means that the market is divided on the basis of a lifestyle choice\u2014running. Geographic segmentation involves dividing a market on the basis of location (e.g., zip code). Demographics are the physical and social characteristics of the population. A business that segments the market on the basis of demographics considers factors such as the age, gender, and ethnicity of the population. Rate of usage is a type of behavioral segmentation, which involves dividing customers into groups according to their response to a product. SOURCE: MP:003 SOURCE: LAP-MP-003\u2014Have We Met? (Market Identification) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Which of the following is a question that a business should answer about its target market while conducting a situational analysis: ", "choices": ["A. What are our customers buying?", "B. How are our financing methods affecting our company's growth?", "C. Are we operating at peak efficiency?", "D. Which shipping companies are we using?"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "What are our customers buying? A situation analysis is a determination of a business's current situation and the direction in which the business is headed. A situation analysis evaluates many internal and external factors. The business's customers (target market) are an external factor the business considers when conducting a situation analysis. The business needs to know which products the customers are buying so it can determine if it needs to make product line changes, delete items, add items, etc. Answering questions about financing, efficiency, and shipping companies do not help the business obtain information about its target market. SOURCE: MP:008 SOURCE: Boundless. (2017, March 29). Conducting a situation analysis. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.boundless.com/marketing/textbooks/boundless-marketingtextbook/marketing-strategies-and-planning-2/steps-to-creating-a-marketing-plan28/conducting-a-situational-analysis-151-7221/ "}, {"number": 56, "question": "Which of the following factors affects how far ahead a business needs to predict its sales: ", "choices": ["A. The business's resources", "B. The typical information that is available", "C. The similarity of competitors", "D. The productivity of the business"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The business's resources. A business that is short of operating funds could use a short-term forecast in order to determine whether sales income will be enough to cover operating expenses. A business that has plenty of financial resources can afford to prepare a longer term sales forecast. Other factors that affect how far ahead a business needs to predict its sales are the objectives of the business, the purpose(s) of the forecast, and the conditions of the market. The choice of forecasting methods is affected by the type of information that is available. The productivity of the business affects the level at which the sales forecast will be set. Changes in the number of competitors or in their marketing strategies may require that sales forecasts be adjusted. However, the similarity of competitors does not affect the selection of a time frame for forecasting sales. SOURCE: MP:013 SOURCE: LAP-MP-005\u2014Futurecast (The Nature of Sales Forecasts) "}, {"number": 57, "question": "Your web search results contain URLs from a variety of sources. Which of the following sources should provide the most reliable data: ", "choices": ["A. A government agency", "B. A term paper", "C. A personal blog", "D. A Wikipedia site"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "A government agency. A government agency, such as the Bureau of Labor Statistics, should contain unbiased, accurate information. A term paper and a personal blog would probably be biased based on the writer's viewpoint. Although Wikipedia is an open source of information that is constantly updated, you might have received wiki information when it was inaccurate. SOURCE: NF:079 SOURCE: GCF LearnFree. (1998-2017). How to judge online information. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.gcflearnfree.org/searchbetter/judging-online-information/1/ "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Thomas wants to change the word \u201cdevelop\u201d to the word \u201ccreate\u201d in several places throughout his document. The quickest way to make these changes is by using the __________ function. ", "choices": ["A. find and replace", "B. cut and paste", "C. header and footer", "D. styles and formatting"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Find and replace. The find and replace function allows computer users to make changes to their documents quickly. This function is beneficial when working with large documents that contain multiple words or phrases that need to be changed. The cut function allows a computer user to remove text or graphics from the document. The paste function allows a computer user to place cut or copied text or graphics in the document. Although the cut and paste functions allow users to change words, they are not as quick as the find and replace function, which is one step. The header and footer function allows a computer user to place document names and page numbers into a document. The style and formatting function allows a computer user to organize the document's contents in a standard or consistent manner. SOURCE: NF:007 SOURCE: Microsoft. (2017). Find and replace text and other data in a Word document. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://support.office.com/en-us/article/Find-and-replace-text-andother-data-in-a-Word-document-c6728c16-469e-43cd-afe4-7708c6c779b7 Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following is needed to post a web page: ", "choices": ["A. Web server", "B. Product to sell", "C. Interested audience", "D. Legal permit"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Web server. After creating a web page, the developer needs to post the web page through a web server or Internet service provider (IPS). The Web server or IPS may charge a fee to post and store the web page, although some web servers will provide the service free of charge. Developers post web pages for many reasons, which may include selling products to interested audiences. Legal permits are not required to post a web page. SOURCE: NF:042 SOURCE: Build-Website.com. (2010). Upload web page to server. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://build-website.com/guide/upload.html "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Analyzing data with Simpson's Paradox in mind can help account for ", "choices": ["A. unconsidered variables or dimensions.", "B. human error.", "C. inconsistencies in data generation.", "D. incorrect assumptions."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Unconsidered variables or dimensions. Simpson's Paradox occurs when a trend that appears in different groups of data disappears when the groups are combined. It helps to reveal instances where data can be misinterpreted or variables can be overlooked because data have not been examined from multiple perspectives. Simpson's Paradox does not necessarily account for human error, inconsistencies in data generation, or incorrect assumptions about data. SOURCE: NF:139 SOURCE: Reda, G. (2014, March 23). Principles of good data analysis. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.gregreda.com/2014/03/23/principles-of-good-data-analysis/ "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Businesses can use data mining to ", "choices": ["A. show why information is valuable.", "B. see patterns within data.", "C. eliminate the need to understand data.", "D. make decisions for them."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "See patterns within data. Data mining is a way for businesses to see the relationships and patterns within data. Data mining can give businesses the information they need to make decisions, but it cannot make decisions for them. Businesses must decide for themselves why the information is valuable. Businesses still need to understand data. SOURCE: NF:152 SOURCE: SAS. (2017, August 7). Data mining: What it is and why it matters. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.sas.com/en_us/insights/analytics/data-mining.html "}, {"number": 62, "question": "A growing trend that is influencing the way that many companies do business is the concern for ", "choices": ["A. protecting the environment.", "B. distributing the wealth.", "C. monitoring the economy.", "D. regulating the government."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Protecting the environment. The growing concern over the condition of the environment is influencing the way that many companies do business. Businesses that once ignored the damage they did to the environment are now spending billions of dollars to correct the problems and to change the way they operate. Public sentiment is forcing these companies to address environmental issues, such as pollution. The businesses that fail to do their part to protect the environment often anger consumers, which may lead to a loss of sales. The government, rather than business, is concerned with the distribution of wealth. Monitoring the economy is not a new trend but an ongoing business function. Businesses do not regulate government; instead, government regulates business. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Zahorsky, D. (2016, June 1). Emerging business trends that are rocking the business world. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.thebalance.com/business-trends-affectprofitability-2951403 "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Statistical data revealed that Zane Industries sold 32% more of the Model EQ2 desktop photocopier last year after it made changes to increase the photocopier's speed and refine its print quality. In this situation, the statistical findings helped the company determine that ", "choices": ["A. its sales forecasts were inaccurate.", "B. product improvements helped boost sales.", "C. research and development expenses exceeded the budget.", "D. the company achieved its sales goals."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Product improvements helped boost sales. Statistics are information presented in numerical form. Businesses use statistics to evaluate performance and identify trends. In the situation described, the business used statistics to identify a specific increase in sales after it made improvements to a product. There is not enough information provided to know how the statistical information relates to the company's sales goals, sales forecasts, and research and development budget. SOURCE: NF:093 SOURCE: Bianca, A. (2011, August 14). The advantages of statistics in business. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/advantages-statistics-business-18698.html Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 64, "question": "A company trains its human resources department in how to handle emergency situations. Is this an example of operations management? ", "choices": ["A. Yes, because the human resources department is considered an outside customer.", "B. Yes, because it involves the operational aspects of safety and security.", "C. No, because the human resources department does not interact with outside customers.", "D. No, because the human resources department does not use operations."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Yes, because it involves the operational aspects of safety and security. Operations management involves the processes used by both internal and external customers. Emergency training in human resources improves the processes the department would use in emergency situations. The human resources department is an internal part of the company, not an outside customer. Internal customers can also benefit from improvements in operations management. The human resources department does use processes, or operations, to complete valuable internal tasks for the organization. SOURCE: OP:191 SOURCE: Dhoul, T. (2014, April 30). What is operations management? Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.topmba.com/mba-programs/what-operations-management "}, {"number": 65, "question": "Which of the following situations is an example of a hazard that affects the safety of the workplace: ", "choices": ["A. Wide aisles to accommodate foot traffic", "B. Proper lighting throughout the building", "C. Boxes stacked in front of a fire exit", "D. Secure locks on the building's exterior doors"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Boxes stacked in front of a fire exit. Nothing should ever block a fire exit. If a fire breaks out and the building's fire exit is blocked, employees may not be able to vacate the premises. Proper lighting, wide aisles, and secure locking systems promote workplace safety rather than present a workplace hazard. SOURCE: OP:008 SOURCE: SafeWork SA. (2014, October 21). Managing the work environment and facilities. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.safework.sa.gov.au/show_page.jsp?id=113704 "}, {"number": 66, "question": "Which of the following situations may represent a risk to the business: ", "choices": ["A. A regular customer is impatient when the cashier takes a telephone order.", "B. A regular customer brings a new neighbor to shop at the business.", "C. A new customer with a check provides a piece of photo identification.", "D. A new customer's check is for an amount larger than the purchase total."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "A new customer's check is for an amount larger than the purchase total. The customer's check may be valid, or it may be a bad check because there is not enough money in the customer's account to honor the check. If the business accepts a bad check, the bank will not honor the check, and the business will lose not only the value of the customer's purchase but the additional cash as well. To protect themselves, some businesses require checks for more than the purchase total to be approved by a manager. A regular customer who brings in a new neighbor does not represent a risk to the business. Most customers are rightfully impatient when they are kept waiting by telephone transactions. Photo identification is considered the most acceptable form because it carries both a picture and a signature. SOURCE: OP:013 SOURCE: Connecticut Department of Banking. (2002-2017). Checks and related issues. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.ct.gov/dob/cwp/view.asp?a=2235&q=297900 "}, {"number": 67, "question": "What do managers often use to evaluate project results? ", "choices": ["A. Activities", "B. Techniques", "C. Resources", "D. Standards"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Standards. Standards are specifications or statements that are used as a basis for making comparisons or judgments. Managers often use standards as the basis for evaluating project results. For example, one standard might be financial, such as to increase sales by a certain amount. Then, the manager compares the results with the standard to determine if the project was effective. Techniques are methods or activities that might be used to carry out the project. Resources are items that are needed to complete a project. SOURCE: OP:159 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 258). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 68, "question": "A materials and notions buyer who purchases more zippers and buttons from a supplier to replace depleted inventory is placing a ", "choices": ["A. production requisition.", "B. reorder.", "C. back order.", "D. line requisition."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Reorder. A purchase order is written documentation that a company provides to its suppliers. It outlines specific items, prices, and delivery dates for desired goods. A reorder is an order that is placed for the same items that have previously been ordered to replenish items that have been used or sold. Back orders are items that vendors do not have available for shipment at the time the customer requests the goods. Production and line requisitions are not terms generally used in the purchasing environment. SOURCE: OP:016 SOURCE: Davidson, E. (n.d.). A basic inventory control tutorial. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/basic-inventory-control-tutorial-2230.html Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Stan is a small-business owner who is always looking for ways to increase his company's ability to do the job right the first time. He listens to his staff members' suggestions and implements many of their ideas for improvement. What is Stan doing? ", "choices": ["A. Creating a quality culture", "B. Developing new products", "C. Supporting external resources", "D. Reorganizing priorities"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Creating a quality culture. A business with a quality culture believes that each employee has valuable ideas. A quality culture involves nurturing an environment in which all employees are committed to consistently achieve the business's quality standards and look for ways to improve those standards. Improvement might involve reorganizing priorities, supporting various initiatives, increasing personal work efficiency, streamlining processes, using creative thinking, improving goods and services, and obtaining external resources. SOURCE: OP:019 SOURCE: Leadership Review. (2014, December 12). How to build a culture of quality for your organization. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from https://www.leadershipreview.net/buildinga-culture-of-quality "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Which of the following is one of the biggest expenses that employees can help a business control: ", "choices": ["A. Rent", "B. Advertising", "C. Payroll", "D. Taxes"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Payroll. One of a business's biggest expenses is payroll. Therefore, it is important for businesses to get full value for their payroll dollars to control expenses. Employees who arrive on time and work their designated hours are helping to ensure that the business receives the time it pays for. Advertising, taxes, and rent are other types of business expenses that are not under the employee's control. SOURCE: OP:025 SOURCE: LAP-OP-025\u2014Buck Busters (Employee Role in Expense Control) "}, {"number": 71, "question": "Cathy is allowing her four friends to pick out a skirt for her at the mall\u2014with one request: that all four friends agree about the selection. Which style of decision-making is Cathy asking her friends to use? ", "choices": ["A. Minimum", "B. Maximum", "C. Medium", "D. Moderate"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Maximum. Cathy is asking her friends to use the maximum-input decision-making style\u2014one in which the entire group decides together. With the minimum-input style, the decision maker decides without help. With the moderate-input style, the decision maker asks for some help before deciding. Medium is not used to describe decision-making styles. SOURCE: PD:017 SOURCE: LAP-PD-010\u2014Weigh Your Options (Decision Making in Business) "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Why do we need creativity? ", "choices": ["A. It indicates one's intelligence.", "B. It moves the world along.", "C. It shows businesses which employees can think in concrete terms.", "D. It helps businesses to identify employees who will succeed in performing routine tasks."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It moves the world along. Without creativity, we would still be living in caves. Everything in our existence is based on something that was once a new idea. Without creativity, we'd have no new goods or services. Many highly intelligent people are not creative. Creative people think in abstract terms so that they are able to see what is not readily apparent. Creative people prefer variety and change to routine. SOURCE: PD:012 SOURCE: LAP-PD-012\u2014Imagine That (Demonstrating Creativity) "}, {"number": 73, "question": "If individuals enjoy operating machinery, driving vehicles, or using tools, they might consider a career that involves working with ", "choices": ["A. things.", "B. animals.", "C. people.", "D. information."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Things. Individuals should consider what they like to do, their favorite activities, when identifying possible occupations. For example, some individuals enjoy operating machinery, driving vehicles, or using tools. As a result, they might consider a career that involves working with things which are tangible items. Examples include a landscaper who operates equipment and drives a truck, and a carpenter who uses tools to build furniture. Careers that involve working with people and animals require a lot of personal interaction and patience. Careers that involve working with information involve keeping track of data such as facts and statistics. SOURCE: PD:023 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G. (2012). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 38-41). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 74, "question": "Javier had an interview with a potential employer, Dan Martinez. The interview was pretty casual and informal. How should Javier begin his thank you note? ", "choices": ["A. He doesn't need to send a thank you note for a casual interview.", "B. Dear Dan", "C. Hi Dan", "D. Dear Mr. Martinez"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Dear Mr. Martinez. Even if the interview was fairly casual, it's always better to err on the side of formality. If Javier isn't sure whether he should refer to his potential employer as Mr. Martinez or Dan, he should go with Mr. Martinez. It's very unlikely that his potential employer will take offense to that, but he may take offense to being referred to by his first name. Starting a thank you letter with \u201cHi Dan\u201d is definitely too informal. It's important to send follow-up letters after every job interview. This includes casual interviews, interviews that didn't go well, and interviews for jobs you don't think you want. SOURCE: PD:029 SOURCE: Littrell, J.J., Lorenz, J.H., & Smith, H.T. (2012). School to career (9th ed.) [pp. 375-379]. Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 75, "question": "Which of the following provides a business's employees with a foundation for acceptable behavior in the workplace: ", "choices": ["A. Rules of conduct", "B. Organizational chart", "C. Grievance procedures", "D. Articles of incorporation"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Rules of conduct. The rules of conduct outline a company's policies, procedures, and expectations regarding employees' behavior in the workplace. An organizational chart is a graphical representation of the flow of authority within an organization. Formal methods of settling disagreements between workers and employers are grievance procedures. Articles of incorporation is a document outlining a corporation's name, purpose, location, amount of stock to be issued, names of the board of directors, and other information about the conditions under which the business will operate. SOURCE: PD:251 SOURCE: Brunot, T. (n.d.). The importance of the code of conduct. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.ehow.com/about_6559640_importance-code-conduct.html "}, {"number": 76, "question": "The ability for marketers to think fast on their feet is most associated with ", "choices": ["A. decision-making.", "B. creativity.", "C. people skills.", "D. people knowledge."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Decision-making. With the marketing environment growing at such a fast pace, employers are looking for people who can think fast on their feet. To do this, marketers need to be independent thinkers who can solve problems without needing supervision. Examples of decision-making skills that marketers use regularly include determining what customers need, solving customers' problems, and resolving complaints. Creativity involves using imagination and intellect to generate new ideas. Creativity is not necessarily a fast process. People knowledge and skills deal with knowing what makes customers tick and how to best work with meeting customers' needs. SOURCE: PD:024 SOURCE: LAP-PD-021\u2014Career Opportunities in Marketing "}, {"number": 77, "question": "The price function often influences the place function by determining ", "choices": ["A. how the product is advertised.", "B. why the product is shipped.", "C. where the product is sold.", "D. when the product is made."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Where the product is sold. The place function involves shipping, handling, and storing of items and determining when and where they will be available. Pricing affects the place decision by determining where the product is sold. Products with high prices usually are sold in stores that carry expensive items, while products with low prices often are sold in other types of stores, such as discounters. The price function does not influence the place function by determining why the product is shipped, how the product is advertised, or when the product is made. SOURCE: PI:001 SOURCE: LAP-PI-002\u2014The Price Is Right (Nature of Pricing) "}, {"number": 78, "question": "In which of the following situations might loss-leader pricing be illegal: ", "choices": ["A. Customers pay a premium.", "B. Businesses make a large profit.", "C. Products are sold below cost.", "D. Competitors match the price."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Products are sold below cost. Loss-leader pricing involves selling products near or below cost. In some situations, laws prohibit the use of loss-leader pricing if the products are sold below cost. The reason is that the prices may be so low that competition is eliminated. However, the laws governing loss-leader pricing are seldom enforced because customers benefit from the low prices. Businesses often do not make any profit on loss-leader pricing because the purpose of that tactic is to attract customers who then will buy additional items at the regular price. Customers do not pay a premium when buying loss-leader items. Competitors often match the loss-leader price or try to beat it. SOURCE: PI:017 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 595-596). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 79, "question": "In product/service management, a major disadvantage of rapid technological changes is the ", "choices": ["A. increase in customer satisfaction and profitability.", "B. number of new products entering the market.", "C. increase of customer product awareness.", "D. rate at which existing products become obsolete."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Rate at which existing products become obsolete. Technology advances so rapidly that products introduced to market are quickly being reintroduced with upgrades or changes that make the original obsolete. The problem is that many technically advanced products have a short life cycle because more advanced products take their place. Increasing the introduction of new products and improving customer awareness will increase customer satisfaction and, as a result, increase sales and profitability. These are advantages of new technology. SOURCE: PM:039 SOURCE: Reynolds, P. (2011, December). Managing obsolete technologies: Strategies and practices. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://iom.invensys.com/EN/pdfLibrary/ManagingObsoleteTechnologiesStrategiesandPractices.pdf Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 80, "question": "Which of the following is a technique that many businesses use to identify product opportunities: ", "choices": ["A. Evaluating a prototype", "B. Testing the market", "C. Observing the competition", "D. Developing a brand"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Observing the competition. Businesses often observe the products developed by competitors in order to identify possible product opportunities. For example, a business might observe that a competitor's new product is popular and selling well. As a result, the business develops a similar product that is somewhat more advanced. By paying attention to what competitors are doing, businesses often are able to identify product opportunities. Once the opportunity is identified, businesses often evaluate a prototype and test the market. One of the final steps before introducing a new product is developing a brand. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 707-709). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 81, "question": "The primary goal during the brainstorming process is to ", "choices": ["A. come up with as many ideas as possible.", "B. analyze each idea as it is presented.", "C. rate each idea in relation to one another.", "D. come up with a set number of ideas within a certain time."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Come up with as many ideas as possible. Brainstorming is a creative-thinking technique involving the identification of as many different ideas as possible during a certain time frame. The process involves getting ideas out in an open, nonjudgmental environment. Therefore, rating and analyzing ideas are not primary goals during brainstorming sessions. SOURCE: PM:127 SOURCE: LAP-PM-127\u2014Unleash Your Mind (Techniques for Generating Product Ideas) "}, {"number": 82, "question": "Which federal agency has the responsibility for inspecting meat that is shipped across state lines? ", "choices": ["A. U.S. Department of Agriculture", "B. U.S. Department of Commerce", "C. Federal Trade Commission", "D. Interstate Commerce Commission"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "U.S. Department of Agriculture. Federal law states that all meat that is shipped across state lines is subject to inspection by the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA). The U.S. Department of Commerce grades fish that is sold for commercial consumption, but this is a voluntary program. The Interstate Commerce Commission regulates rates and other aspects of commercial transportation between states. The Federal Trade Commission administers and enforces antitrust laws to prevent price fixing and to prohibit unfair competitive practices. SOURCE: PM:019 SOURCE: LAP-PM-008\u2014Raise the Bar (Grades and Standards) "}, {"number": 83, "question": "A group of related products is called a product ", "choices": ["A. item.", "B. line.", "C. mix.", "D. expansion."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Line. An example of a product line would be bread, rolls, cookies, and cakes in a supermarket. Product items are each individual good, service, or idea that a business offers for sale. A product mix is the particular assortment of products that a business offers in order to meet its market's needs and its company's goals. Expansion is a product mix strategy in which a business expands its product mix by adding additional product items or product lines. SOURCE: PM:003 SOURCE: LAP-PM-003\u2014Mix and Match (The Nature of the Product Mix) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Which of the following situations is an example of product bundling: ", "choices": ["A. Buy item Y and receive service W free for six months.", "B. Buy item Z and receive a $50 manufacturer's rebate.", "C. Buy product X and receive a $15 discount if it is paid within 10 days.", "D. Buy service M and receive a coupon to use for future purchases."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Buy item Y and receive service W free for six months. Product bundling involves combining goods and/or services and offering them to customers as one product for a lower price than if the customers were to buy all of the products individually. Often, businesses bundle new products with existing products in order to create interest in the new product. A business that provides a free service for a certain amount of time hopes that the customer gets used to having the service and will pay to continue receiving the service once the free offer expires. Businesses may use rebates, invoice discounts, and coupons in conjunction with product-bundle strategies. SOURCE: PM:041 SOURCE: Boone, G., & Kurtz, D.L. (2013). Contemporary marketing 2013 (p. 660). Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 85, "question": "The following statement appears on a company's website: \"Unlike our competitors, Naturally Yours Cosmetics uses organically-grown ingredients in its facial scrubs and lotions.\" What strategy is the company using to position its line of skin-care items? ", "choices": ["A. Product reliability", "B. Price", "C. Customization", "D. Unique attributes"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Unique attributes. Product positioning is the customer's image or impression of a product as compared to that of competitive products. In the example, the company emphasizes that its products' ingredients are organically grown. Because organic ingredients are product attributes, Naturally Yours Cosmetics is using the attributes to set itself apart from other cosmetic companies that provide similar products. The business is not using price, customization, or product reliability to position its skin-care line. SOURCE: PM:042 SOURCE: LAP-PM-019\u2014Getting Piece of Mind (Factors Used to Position Products/Services) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 86, "question": "One reason that a brand name should be adaptable is so that the business can ", "choices": ["A. change the brand name as often as necessary.", "B. use the brand name in multinational marketing.", "C. use the brand name in packaging and advertising.", "D. make its products look like other similar products."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Use the brand name in multinational marketing. A good brand name should be easy to pronounce in all countries where the product will be marketed. For example, Kodak and Exxon are easy to pronounce by people who speak other languages. The business would want to establish a brand in consumers' minds, not change it frequently. The business would also want the brand name to set its product(s) apart rather than making them resemble competitive products. The length of the brand name, rather than its adaptability, makes it appropriate for packaging and advertising. SOURCE: PM:021 SOURCE: LAP-PM-006\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (Nature of Product Branding) "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Employee interactions, websites, and advertisements are all examples of ", "choices": ["A. corporate brands.", "B. touch points.", "C. logos.", "D. distributor brands."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Touch points. Touch points are all the opportunities that businesses have to connect with customers and reinforce their brand values. Any chance a business gets to interact with customers is a touch point; this includes products, packaging, employee interactions, websites, advertisements, social media interactions, and much more. Logos are distinctive symbols, designs, or groups of letters. Distributor brands are owned by the retailer or wholesaler that sells the brands, rather than the manufacturer. Corporate brands are all the combined customer impressions and experiences associated with a particular company. SOURCE: PM:206 SOURCE: LAP-PM-020\u2014Corporate Identity (Nature of Corporate Branding) "}, {"number": 88, "question": "Many of the town's residents have heard that this coming summer is predicted to be the hottest summer ever. As a result of hearing this, Tim, the owner of an appliance store, decided to do more advertising for air conditioners. Which of the following external factors has affected Tim and his business: ", "choices": ["A. Technology", "B. Legal and political factors", "C. Demand", "D. Cultural and social trends"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Demand. Demand for certain products tends to change with the seasons, such as air conditioners for summer. This means that Tim needs to adjust his promotion to meet this change. Technology deals with technological developments, not demand for a product. Legal and political factors deal with government regulations and restrictions, not demand for a product. Cultural and social trends deal with changes in attitudes, lifestyles, and tastes of the consumers, not demand for a product. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: LAP-PR-002\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Nature of Promotion) "}, {"number": 89, "question": "A promotion that makes false or exaggerated claims about a product is considered to be ", "choices": ["A. stereotypical.", "B. deceptive.", "C. offensive.", "D. manipulative."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Deceptive. When a promotion includes misleading or untrue claims, it is considered to be deceiving to consumers. An offensive promotion is one that is in bad taste, vulgar, or insulting to consumers. When a promotion reinforces stereotypes, it portrays people in ways that are stereotypical. Promotions that manipulate a consumer are ones that persuade people to act against their free will to purchase a good or service that they may not need. SOURCE: PR:002 SOURCE: LAP-PR-004\u2014Know Your Options (Product and Institutional Promotion) "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Technological advancements in computer software have made it possible for media planners to calculate reach, frequency, and __________ of their placements more quickly. ", "choices": ["A. promotional mix", "B. attention value", "C. cost efficiency", "D. audience fluency"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Cost efficiency. Computer software developments have made it possible for advertisers and agencies to calculate and analyze data to determine a medium's reach, frequency, and cost efficiency in relation to the overall placement. This information can now be calculated by computer programs instead of manually, which took a much longer time to ascertain. The information is used to determine optimal venues for advertising placement. Attention value refers to the level of viewer interest as it relates to the ad's message, copy, and medium. Attention value is a qualitative consideration and can be difficult to measure or calculate. Promotional mix is defined as a combination of marketing communication channels that a business uses to send its messages to consumers. Audience fluency is not a term that is widely used in the promotion industry. SOURCE: PR:100 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 277-279). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 91, "question": "To qualify as a specialty medium, an item must be ", "choices": ["A. delivered through the postal service.", "B. sold to a prospective customer.", "C. used for decorative purposes only.", "D. imprinted with the business's name/logo."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Imprinted with the business's name/logo. Specialty items must pass three criteria. They must have the business's name or logo printed on them. An example would be a Century 21 key chain. Also, they should be given away freely, not sold to a customer for any price. Finally, they should be a useful item (as opposed to simply decorative) such as a pen or baseball cap. An item does not need to be delivered through the postal service to be considered a specialty item. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: LAP-PR-003\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Advertising Media) "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Which of the following is an example of direct advertising: ", "choices": ["A. A retailer conducts a telephone survey to determine its customers' satisfaction with its services.", "B. A hotel chain develops an advertising campaign that includes television spots and billboards.", "C. A soft drink company places an advertisement on television during a major sporting event.", "D. An apparel company mails its latest catalog to customers who have ordered items within a year."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "An apparel company mails its latest catalog to customers who have ordered items within a year. Direct advertising refers to promotional messages that are sent directly to the target market through a medium in which market response can be measured. Catalogs that are mailed directly to established customers represent an example of direct advertising. Unless interactive capabilities are available, television is usually considered a mass medium that has substantial reach but cannot always be measured effectively. Therefore, the options referring to soft drinks and hotel chains are not examples of direct advertising. Telephone surveys are considered a function related to market research rather than promotion. SOURCE: PR:089 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 396-397). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 93, "question": "The reason for using certain communications channels, such as coupons, in sales promotion is to ", "choices": ["A. advertise a new product.", "B. create long-term demand.", "C. persuade customers to remain loyal.", "D. generate an immediate response."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Generate an immediate response. A communications channel is a path or means used to provide information to others. In sales promotion, coupons are a type of communications channel that are used to provide information about products to customers. The reason for using coupons is to generate an immediate response by offering reduced prices on specific items. The hope is that customers will be motivated to buy the product now because of the information they received. Sales promotion is usually intended to encourage a quick response, while advertising is intended to create long-term demand and persuade customers to remain loyal. Sales promotion involves promotional activities other than advertising. SOURCE: PR:249 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 405-411). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 94, "question": "In what communications channels are holding press conferences and giving interviews used? ", "choices": ["A. Target marketing", "B. Corporate management", "C. Personal selling", "D. Public relations"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Public relations. Public relations is a function of business designed to establish good relations between the business and the public. One way to establish good relations is to communicate with the public. Businesses often hold press conferences and give interviews to communicate information and pass on positive news about the business. Corporate management involves managing the business. Personal selling is the form of promotion that determines client needs and wants and responds through planned, personalized communication that influences purchase decisions and enhances future business opportunities. Target marketing is the identification and selection of markets for a business or for a product. SOURCE: PR:250 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 396-399). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 95, "question": "One way that salespeople develop and maintain positive relationships with customers is by providing excellent ", "choices": ["A. sales management.", "B. customer service.", "C. opportunities.", "D. demonstrations."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Customer service. Salespeople strive to develop and maintain positive relationships with customers to keep them as customers. Effective salespeople know that customers expect more than just a product when they purchase something. The salespeople who are able to provide excellent service for their customers are usually able to maintain positive selling relationships with them. Excellent demonstrations might help to sell customers the first time, but will not help to develop positive relationships unless salespeople also provide good service. Salespeople are not responsible for providing sales management. Providing the opportunity to buy will not necessarily help to develop positive relationships with customers. SOURCE: SE:076 SOURCE: LAP-SE-130\u2014Go Beyond the Sale (Customer Service in Selling) Test 1161 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32 "}, {"number": 96, "question": "A selling activity that helps salespeople to make sales is ", "choices": ["A. available credit.", "B. quality repair.", "C. referrals.", "D. preparation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Preparation. This involves gathering information about potential clients in order to understand the client's needs and problems. Gathering information is also important when considering how business products can meet the needs of clients. Referrals are individuals or businesses to whom salespeople are recommended. Offering quality repair service and credit are ways businesses can build a clientele, not selling activities. SOURCE: SE:828 SOURCE: LAP-SE-115\u2014Keep Them Loyal (Key Factors in Building Clientele) "}, {"number": 97, "question": "What type of law prevents salespeople from one company from interfering with their competition's activities? ", "choices": ["A. Warranty liability", "B. Product safety", "C. Consumer credit", "D. Unfair trade"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Unfair trade. Activities such as stealing a competitor's trade secrets, or attempting to get a competitor's customer to breach a contract, are considered unfair trade practices and are illegal practices in many countries. Consumer protection laws address issues such as product safety, consumer credit, and warranties. SOURCE: SE:108 SOURCE: Investopedia. (2014). Unfair trade practice. Retrieved September 6, 2017, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/u/unfair-trade-practice.asp "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Information about new or unusual uses for a product can often be obtained easily from ", "choices": ["A. factory visits.", "B. customers.", "C. inventors.", "D. the product manual."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Customers. Customers may have discovered new or different uses for products through actual use of the products. The product manual and factory visits provide basic information rather than innovative product uses. Sales personnel seldom have contact with inventors. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: LAP-SE-131\u2014Get Informed (Acquiring Product Information for Use in Selling) "}, {"number": 99, "question": "When a customer buying an appliance, piece of electronics, or vehicle asks questions about repairs, the salesperson should explain features and benefits relating to its ", "choices": ["A. service and warranty.", "B. popularity.", "C. history.", "D. appearance and style."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Service and warranty. When a customer buying an appliance, piece of electronics, or vehicle asks questions about repairs, the salesperson should explain features and benefits relating to its service and warranty. In some cases, whether or not a customer buys depends on the service your company offers and/or the warranty on the product. These factors may convince the customer to buy, and they are more important to a practical customer than a product's popularity, appearance, style, or history. SOURCE: SE:109 SOURCE: LAP-SE-113\u2014Find Features, Boost Benefits (Feature-Benefit Selling) "}, {"number": 100, "question": "A human resources manager sets up a computerized system for maintaining employee records. What type of resource is the manager using? ", "choices": ["A. Material", "B. Financial", "C. Human", "D. Natural"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Material. Material resources are equipment and supplies used by businesses in their operation. Financial resources are all the sources of money available to the business. Human resources are people who work to produce goods or services. Natural resources are resources found in nature that are used to produce goods and services. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: LAP-SM-003\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}],"1069-MKT": [{"number": 1, "question": "The purpose of legal procedure is to ensure that each party receives ", "choices": ["A. ongoing advice. ", "B. consistent treatment. ", "C. a reasonable verdict.", "D. an indictment."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Consistent treatment. Legal procedure refers to the methods and processes used to protect an individual's or business's legal rights. These rights include the right to obtain legal counsel, the right to be heard in court, the right to confront the accuser, etc. Legal procedure involves following the same steps and protocol to ensure that both the defendant and the plaintiff are treated in a fair and consistent manner. The purpose of legal procedure is not to ensure that each party receives ongoing advice. In most legal proceedings, one party is not going to be satisfied with the verdict or outcome. An indictment is a formal charge or accusation of a crime. SOURCE: BL:070 SOURCE: Beatty, J.F., & Samuelson, S.S. (2008). Essentials of business law (3rd ed.) [pp. 116-117]. Mason, OH: Thomson/South-Western. "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Wal-mart, Chevron Texaco, and Ford Motor Company sell stock in their companies. They are examples of which of the following types of business ownership: ", "choices": ["A. Franchisee ", "B. Corporation ", "C. Partnership", "D. Sole proprietorship"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Corporation. Wal-Mart, Chevron Texaco, and Ford Motor Company are all large businesses owned by their shareholders, who own stock in the company. These businesses are operated under written permission from the states or provinces in which they operate. A sole proprietorship is a business owned and operated by one person. A partnership is owned by two or more people. A franchisee purchases the rights to operate a business using the parent company's (franchisor's) name. SOURCE: BL:003 SOURCE: BL LAP 3\u2014Own It Your Way (Types of Business Ownership) "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Channels of distribution benefit businesses by ", "choices": ["A. lowering the prices of all industrial goods.", "B. getting their products to consumers more efficiently.", "C. raising their profits each year.", "D. allowing them to avoid all channel tasks."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Getting their products to consumers more efficiently. Channels of distribution benefit businesses by getting their products to consumers more efficiently. This may help to raise profits, but it is not a guarantee. Channels may lower the prices of some but not all industrial goods. Channels allow businesses to share channel tasks, but they will not be able to avoid all channel tasks\u2014every channel member contributes. SOURCE: CM:001 SOURCE: CM LAP 2\u2014Chart Your Channels (Channel Management) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Which of the following would not be considered an intermediary in a channel of distribution: ", "choices": ["A. Agent ", "B. Retailer ", "C. Producer", "D. Wholesaler"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Producer. The channel of distribution begins with the producer. The producer's goal is to reach the consumer as quickly and efficiently as possible. A retailer buys consumer goods or services and sells them to the ultimate consumer. A wholesaler buys goods from producers or agents and sells them to retailers. An agent assists in the sale and/or promotion of goods and services, but does not take title to them. The retailer, wholesaler, and agent are intermediaries because they operate between the producer and consumer to help the movement of goods and services. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: CM LAP 1\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) "}, {"number": 5, "question": "The negative effect of slotting fees is that they often limit a small producer's ability to ", "choices": ["A. introduce new items in the marketplace. ", "B. develop exclusive-dealing policies. ", "C. use direct-distribution strategies.", "D. identify potential target markets."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Introduce new items in the marketplace. A slotting fee is a cash premium that producers pay to businesses to cover the costs associated with carrying a new product. In many cases, the producer that offers the largest fee is the one that gets shelf space for its new product. This presents an unethical situation because many small producers cannot afford to pay large slotting fees, which limits the introduction of new items in the marketplace. Exclusive dealing is an illegal practice when it restricts competition; however, it may be legal when small businesses are entering the marketplace. Direct distribution is a channel of distribution in which products move directly from the producer to the end user. Slotting fees may hinder a business's ability to distribute its products to the target market, but the slotting fees do not limit the business's ability to identify potential target markets. SOURCE: CM:006 SOURCE: Etzel, M.J., Walker, B.J., & Stanton, W.J. (2007). Marketing (14th ed.) [p. 399]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 11 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "What type of channel conflict often occurs between manufacturers and their authorized dealers? ", "choices": ["A. Corporate ", "B. Horizontal ", "C. Indirect", "D. Vertical"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Vertical. Vertical conflict involves disagreements among businesses on different levels of the same channel of distribution. Manufacturers and their authorized dealers are in the same channel of distribution, but they are on different levels. Conflict might occur if the manufacturers develop policies or restrictions that anger the dealers and which the dealers refuse to accept. Horizontal conflict occurs among businesses at the same level in a channel of distribution. Indirect and corporate are not types of channel conflict. SOURCE: CM:008 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong, G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [p. 339]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. "}, {"number": 7, "question": "When you look for supporting evidence in published materials, you are evaluating the ", "choices": ["A. timeliness of the content. ", "B. readability of the text. ", "C. margin of error.", "D. credibility of the sources."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Credibility of the sources. When identifying sources that provide relevant, valid written material, the researcher evaluates a variety of factors, including the credibility or believability of the source. If the writer provides feasible supporting evidence to back up an opinion, outcome, or claim, the researcher may determine that the source is credible. Other considerations are the timeliness of the data or article, the relevance of the information to the topic at hand, and the expertise of the writer or publisher. Readability of the text involves the reader's ability to understand the content. If the researcher is evaluating a research study, s/he might analyze the margin of error of certain types of data as one factor in determining a source's credibility. SOURCE: CO:054 SOURCE: Young, D.J. (2006). Foundations of business communication: An integrative approach (pp. 293, 494). New York: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Listening carefully should enable employees to ", "choices": ["A. earn frequent raises. ", "B. become good speakers. ", "C. avoid criticism.", "D. follow directions."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Follow directions. In order to follow directions or instructions, the person receiving them must listen carefully. Listening is an important skill for everyone, but it is especially important to workers who receive directions from supervisors about their job duties. Good listeners are often effective workers who are less likely to receive criticism and more likely to earn raises. However, listening skill does not enable workers to avoid all criticism, to earn frequent raises, or to become good speakers themselves. SOURCE: CO:017 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2006). Marketing essentials (pp. 179-182). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Sara is a new marketing employee who is learning that the best way to listen to customers is ", "choices": ["A. passively. ", "B. actively. ", "C. emotionally.", "D. distractedly."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Actively. Active listening is giving full attention to what is being said. It enables the listener to note major points and to notice gestures or actions which give added meaning to what is being said. Passive listening is casual listening, or paying only partial attention to what is being said. Distractedly describes a listener whose mind is on other things, not just on what the customer is saying. Listening to customers should be thoughtful and rational, not emotional. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 52]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 10, "question": "When Amber walked by Ryan's desk, she noticed that Ryan was raking his left hand through his hair, that his face was red, and that he kept hitting the enter button on keyboard with his right hand, while frowning at his computer screen. Based on his nonverbal cues, Amber would probably assume that Ryan was ", "choices": ["A. patient. ", "B. frustrated. ", "C. bored.", "D. enthusiastic."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Frustrated. Nonverbal cues can tell others a lot about your emotions. In this situation, Ryan's nonverbal behavior indicated that he was frustrated because he couldn't get his computer to do what he wanted it to do. If Ryan was patient, he would not continuously hit his keyboard, turn red, or frown. If Ryan was bored, he would be inattentive about his situation or surroundings. He might even yawn or do something other than computer work for a while. Enthusiasm is associated with a positive attitude. SOURCE: CO:059 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 54-57]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 12 "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Which of the following examples illustrates the use of the cause and effect method of a format for structuring oral presentations: ", "choices": ["A. We will begin by discussing the basic steps used in developing effective time management\ntechniques, and the first step is to prioritize all of your commitments.", "B. The public supports increased spending on national security, and a survey reports that over\nseventy percent of the citizens fear future terrorist attacks.", "C. Monet and Cezanne were both impressionist artists; however, their painting techniques and use\nof color varied greatly.", "D. The use of toxic chemicals in the environment can result in the extinction of many species of"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "The use of toxic chemicals in the environment can result in the extinction of many species of waterfowl. This example indicates that the extinction of waterfowl (the end result or effect) is caused by the use of toxic chemicals (the cause). The public supports increased spending on national security, and a survey reports that over seventy percent of the citizens fear future terrorist attacks: This is an example of the use of a generalization with an example method of presentation organization. Monet and Cezanne were both impressionist artists; however, their painting techniques and use of color varied greatly: This is an example of the compare and contrast method of presentation organization. An example of the enumeration method of presentation organization is as follows: We will begin by discussing the basic steps used in developing effective time management techniques, and the first step is to prioritize all of your commitments. SOURCE: CO:025 SOURCE: Miculka, J. (2007). Speaking for success (2nd ed.) [p. 191]. Mason, OH: Thomson SouthWestern. "}, {"number": 12, "question": "Allison is attending a business seminar. Because the seminar presenter is speaking very quickly, Allison is having a difficult time taking accurate notes. What technique would help Allison take notes quickly? ", "choices": ["A. Use abbreviations and symbols ", "B. Write notes on index cards ", "C. Focus on the subtopics", "D. Ask the speaker to provide handouts"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Use abbreviations and symbols. Developing a system of and writing down abbreviations and symbols (i.e., shorthand) is much quicker than writing out long phrases and complete sentences. For example, to remember a very important point, Allison might place a star or asterisk by a key word, short phrase, or abbreviation. After the seminar, Allison can refer to her \u201cshorthand\u201d notes and write more comprehensive notes for future use. Writing on note cards, focusing on subtopics, and asking the speaker to provide handouts will not help Allison take accurate notes in real time. SOURCE: CO:085 SOURCE: Pearson Education. (2000-2012). Taking notes. Retrieved August 8, 2012, from http://www.factmonster.com/homework/studyskills2.html "}, {"number": 13, "question": "An e-mail message that is sent to a coworker should contain ", "choices": ["A. a persuasive argument. ", "B. an urgent tone. ", "C. essential information.", "D. encouraging news."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Essential information. E-mail is a quick, efficient way to communicate with customers and coworkers. The primary reason for writing the e-mail message is to inform others about various business activities; therefore, it should be written in a friendly, professional manner that contains essential information. Businesspeople tend to receive a lot of e-mail messages, so it is important to get to the point quickly. The message should be concise, free of typographical errors, and grammatically correct. The e-mail message may or may not be urgent, persuasive, or encouraging in nature\u2014these factors depend on the purpose of the message. SOURCE: CO:090 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 183-186]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Employees often use simple written reports to provide managers with __________ information. ", "choices": ["A. extensive ", "B. analytical ", "C. in-depth", "D. routine"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Routine. Employees often use simple written reports to provide managers with routine information, such as the number of items sold each week. Routine information is the type of data that managers need on a regular basis in order to monitor the operation of the business. Simple written reports are straightforward and direct and contain only routine business information. They do not contain analytical, extensive, or indepth information, which is usually presented in complex written reports. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: Berman, B., & Evans, J.R. (2004). Retail management: A strategic approach (9th ed.) [p. 190]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Many businesses try to foster positive customer/client relations by encouraging employees to be ", "choices": ["A. talkative. ", "B. friendly. ", "C. reserved.", "D. authoritative."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Friendly. Positive customer/client relations are important to the success of the business because they help to create repeat business. Many businesses encourage employees to adopt a friendly, helpful attitude toward customers as part of their efforts to create positive relations. Being reserved could prevent employees from offering appropriate help and might be interpreted as coldness. Being talkative may offend customers or prevent employees from identifying their needs. Being authoritative is only appropriate when providing the customer with technical or factual information. SOURCE: CR:003 SOURCE: CR LAP 1\u2014Accentuate the Positive (Nature of Customer Relations) Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 13 "}, {"number": 16, "question": "A local supermarket's front-end employees are trained to smile and greet customers as they approach the cash register and say thank you as customers leave. This approach ", "choices": ["A. decreases customer patronage. ", "B. builds customer loyalty. ", "C. encourages employee rivalry.", "D. decreases employee productivity."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Builds customer loyalty. Employee courtesy at the checkstand reminds customers that the supermarket appreciates their business, which builds customer loyalty to the store. Employee courtesy should not encourage rivalry among front-end employees. Building customer loyalty through courtesy would increase, not decrease, customer patronage. A decrease in employee productivity should not occur as the result of courtesy toward customers. SOURCE: CR:004 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 281-282). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Which of the following is often the best way for a salesperson to handle the slow/methodical type of difficult customer: ", "choices": ["A. Summarize benefits ", "B. Ask their advice ", "C. Be brief", "D. Let the customer do the talking"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Summarize benefits. Slow/Methodical customers need to have the salesperson draw out the needed information, to be treated patiently, and to have the benefits of the good/service summarized in order to guide them to a close. The other three approaches are aimed at the domineering/superior type, who need to do most of the talking, be complimented and praised, and allowed to sell themselves on the good/service. SOURCE: CR:009 SOURCE: CR LAP 3\u2014Making Mad Glad (Handling Difficult Customers) "}, {"number": 18, "question": "Distribution examines how income is divided between ", "choices": ["A. consumers and resource owners. ", "B. producers and resource owners. ", "C. consumers and producers.", "D. producers and economizers."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Producers and resource owners. Distribution examines how producers and resource owners divide the income that they receive from consumers. Anyone who uses goods and services is a consumer. Producers are individuals who make or provide goods and services to consumers. Resource owners are individuals and organizations who provide human resources, natural resources, or capital goods for use in production. An economizer is someone who strives to obtain the greatest satisfaction from his/her limited resources. SOURCE: EC:001 SOURCE: EC LAP 6\u2014Are You Satisfied? (Concept of Economics) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "Consumers buy products to benefit ", "choices": ["A. marketers. ", "B. themselves. ", "C. producers.", "D. retailers."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Themselves. Consumers buy products to benefit themselves. Their purchases may also benefit marketers, producers, and/or retailers\u2014but consumers aim to please themselves. SOURCE: EC:004 SOURCE: EC LAP 13\u2014Use It (Economic Utility) "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of the matrix organizational structure: ", "choices": ["A. It lacks flexibility.", "B. It makes the organization less competitive.", "C. It cannot balance conflicting organizational objectives.", "D. It violates the unity of command principle."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "It violates the unity of command principle. The matrix organizational structure violates the unity of command principle by giving employees more than one manager to answer to at a time. It does not make the organization less competitive. It does not lack flexibility. Balancing conflicting organizational objectives is an advantage of the matrix structure. SOURCE: EC:103 SOURCE: EC LAP 23\u2014Designed to Work (Organizational Design) "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Kent is going to start his own business. He is concerned that the merchandise he wants to carry will go out of style soon after opening his business. Which type of risk must he prepare for? ", "choices": ["A. Economic ", "B. Natural ", "C. Human", "D. Incompetence"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Economic. Economic risks are changes in the market that force prices to be lowered, products to change, or even businesses to fail. Changes in the market that may make some products go out of style are a type of economic risk. Natural risks result from such natural causes as floods, tornadoes, fires, lightning, blizzards, and earthquakes. Human risks are caused by human weakness and the unpredictability of employees and/or customers. Incompetence is a form of human risk whereby the employee does not have the skills, knowledge, or attitudes needed to succeed in the position. SOURCE: EC:011 SOURCE: EC LAP 3\u2014Lose, Win, or Draw (Business Risk) Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 22, "question": "The payment of taxes to the federal government allows it to provide goods and services to ___________ and ___________ . ", "choices": ["A. businesses; households ", "B. businesses; resource markets ", "C. households; product markets", "D. businesses; product markets"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Businesses; households. The net taxes paid by both are translated by government programs into goods and services for businesses and individuals. Resource markets provide resources to the government and in return receive government expenditures. The product market provides goods and services to the federal government and receives government expenditures as payment. SOURCE: EC:072 SOURCE: McConnell, C.R., & Brue, S.L. (2005). Economics: Principles, problems, and policies (16th ed.) [p. 84]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Which of the following economic laws is a business following when it stops hiring after its current employees achieve a certain level of productivity: ", "choices": ["A. Negative returns ", "B. Diminishing returns ", "C. Marginal revenues", "D. Variable products"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Diminishing returns. The law of diminishing returns states that, at some point, adding more employees does not proportionately increase productivity. Each business operates effectively with a certain number of employees who are able to make the best use of the business's resources. After that point is reached, hiring more employees causes an overabundance of employees in relation to the available resources. The additional employees get in each others' way, which causes an overall decrease in each employee's level of productivity. Negative returns is a stage of production in which businesses usually stop hiring employees. Marginal revenues and variable products are not economic laws. SOURCE: EC:023 SOURCE: McConnell, C.R., & Brue, S.L. (2005). Economics: Principles, problems, and policies (16th ed.) [p. 395]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 24, "question": "The goods and services sold during a year to foreign buyers are a country's ", "choices": ["A. gross private investments. ", "B. imports. ", "C. exports.", "D. personal consumption expenditures."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Exports. Exports are goods and services sold to other countries. Imports are the goods and services that one country purchases from a foreign country. Gross private investments is the value of all capital goods created in the economy during the year and inventories held by businesses from current production. Personal consumption expenditures is the final market value of goods and services purchased for direct consumption by individuals, families, and nonprofit organizations. SOURCE: EC:017 SOURCE: Clayton, G.E. (2005). Economics: Principles & practices (pp. 342-343). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 25, "question": "Which of the following occurs when a country can produce goods at a relatively more efficient rate than another country: ", "choices": ["A. Absolute advantage ", "B. Comparative advantage ", "C. Trade deficit", "D. Trade surplus"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Comparative advantage. A country has a comparative advantage when it produces and sells those goods and services for which it will earn the most money, while trading for those which will earn relatively less money. A country has an absolute advantage when it can produce a product for less than another nation can. A trade deficit exists when a nation's imports are greater than its exports. A trade surplus exists when a nation's exports are greater than its imports. SOURCE: EC:016 SOURCE: EC LAP 4\u2014Beyond US (International Trade) "}, {"number": 26, "question": "An employee who is able to adjust to changing conditions possesses the desirable trait of ", "choices": ["A. loyalty. ", "B. adaptability. ", "C. friendliness.", "D. tact."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Adaptability. This is the ability to be flexible and to change with the times. Friendliness means to display good feelings toward others. Loyalty means giving steady support. Tact is the ability to say the right thing in all circumstances. SOURCE: EI:018 SOURCE: EI LAP 9\u2014You've Got Personality (Personality Traits in Business) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "Which of the following is a reason to avoid drawing distinctions between people: ", "choices": ["A. Discrimination is illegal. ", "B. Everyone is unique. ", "C. Some people aren't \"normal.\"", "D. Certain people don't deserve respect."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Everyone is unique. There's no reason to draw distinctions between people because everyone is unique. There's no such thing as \"normal.\" Everyone deserves to be treated with kindness and respect. In many cases, discrimination is illegal, but drawing distinctions between people is something that happens on a personal level and can only be controlled by ourselves. SOURCE: EI:021 SOURCE: EI LAP 21\u2014Make the Honor Role (Acting Responsibly) Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 28, "question": "Cameron said to his manager, \u201cThe order didn't ship because Sam didn't tell me that we didn't have enough items in stock.\u201d What is Cameron doing? ", "choices": ["A. Blaming another person for a communication breakdown", "B. Acknowledging that he failed to follow through with the order", "C. Stating the facts on Sam's behalf", "D. Responding to inappropriate remarks"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Blaming another person for a communication breakdown. When you accept responsibility for your behavior, you are willing to accept the consequences of your actions. In Cameron's situation, he is blaming another person for a work-related mistake. While Sam may be partially responsible for not communicating the stock outage to Cameron, Cameron did not follow up on the order. If he had followed up on the order, he may have detected that there was a problem. Cameron is not acknowledging his responsibility for the problem, and he is not stating facts on Sam's behalf. Sam may have another view or opinion about the chain of events. There is not enough information provided to determine if Cameron's manager made an inappropriate remark. SOURCE: EI:075 SOURCE: eHow.com. (n.d.). How to take responsibility for your actions. Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://www.ehow.com/how_4802685_responsibility-actions.html "}, {"number": 29, "question": "In order for teachers to prepare report cards, they must __________ their students. ", "choices": ["A. motivate ", "B. criticize ", "C. evaluate", "D. compliment"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Evaluate. Report cards are a form of feedback. In order for teachers to provide students with this feedback, they must first evaluate the students' work and behavior. Their findings are reflected in the grades and comments on the report card. Whether those findings are criticisms or compliments depends upon the students' performance. The results may indicate that the teacher needs to motivate the students to work harder, but motivation is not a part of evaluation. SOURCE: EI:003 SOURCE: EI LAP 15\u2014Grin and Bear It (Using Feedback for Personal Growth) "}, {"number": 30, "question": "You are in a better position to control your own future if you __________ change. ", "choices": ["A. agonize over ", "B. anticipate ", "C. wait for", "D. avoid"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Anticipate. You must be able to anticipate and plan for changes that are likely to occur if you want some control over your future. Avoiding change is not possible. Agonizing over change or waiting for change to occur would not help you to control your future. SOURCE: EI:026 SOURCE: Lussier, R.N. (2008). Human relations in organizations: Applications and skill building (7th ed.) [p. 511]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Persuasion is an important part of which of the following functions: ", "choices": ["A. Education ", "B. Motivation ", "C. Communication", "D. Self-control"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Communication. Communication is an exchange of information in which the words and gestures are understood in the same way by both the speaker and the listener. Persuasion is an important part of communication and is something you do almost every time you talk to someone. You want others to understand your message and agree with you. During the process of persuading, you usually try to motivate others to take some kind of action. Education involves learning. Self-control is restraint of your feelings, words, and actions. SOURCE: EI:012 SOURCE: QS LAP 10\u2014Win Them Over "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Because people often change their negotiating styles and strategies, effective negotiators must be ", "choices": ["A. optimistic. ", "B. flexible. ", "C. indifferent.", "D. uneasy."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Flexible. During a negotiation, one person may change strategies one or more times in order to confuse or distract the other person. To remain effective if this situation occurs, a negotiator must be flexible, patient, and aware of the tactics that the other person is using. Effective negotiators try to remain optimistic during a session under all circumstances, not only when the other person changes strategies. An indifferent or uneasy attitude often hinders the negotiating process. SOURCE: EI:062 SOURCE: EI LAP 8\u2014Make It a Win-Win (Negotiation in Business) Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 33, "question": "A primary reason that employees experience burnout in the workplace is because they ", "choices": ["A. become bored with the work. ", "B. receive new work assignments. ", "C. interact with coworkers.", "D. obtain feedback from managers."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Become bored with the work. Burnout is a type of exhaustion that is usually caused by too much stress. Stress is a mental, physical, or emotional feeling of pressure or tension. Burnout can occur when employees perform the same tasks over and over again, which causes them to become bored. Ongoing boredom can create a certain type of stress and burnout in some individuals, especially those who thrive on variety and activity. Receiving new work assignments and interacting with coworkers often relieve boredom. Receiving (positive) feedback from managers often motivates employees to improve or continue producing quality work rather than causing them to experience burnout. SOURCE: EI:028 SOURCE: Jackson, S.E., Schuler, R.S. (n.d.). Preventing employee burnout. Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://selfhelpmagazine.com/article/how-managers-can-prevent-employee-burnout "}, {"number": 34, "question": "One of the differences among people that can be difficult to change is their ", "choices": ["A. language usage. ", "B. job position. ", "C. education.", "D. mental ability."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Mental ability. A person's mental ability refers to his/her learning and thinking ability. People are born with different levels of mental ability. This ability is difficult to change. Job position is the worker's assigned duties and level of responsibility, which the worker can change by changing jobs or seeking promotions. Language usage is the way the language is used in certain parts of the country. People are able to change the way they speak if they so desire. Education is the amount of learning a person has acquired. Learning is an ongoing process. SOURCE: EI:036 SOURCE: EI LAP 20\u2014Fair and Square (Treat Others Fairly at Work) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "When Brandon lost his job due to downsizing, the government sent him an unemployment check to help him cover his living expenses until he found another job. What is Brandon's source of income? ", "choices": ["A. Transfer payment ", "B. Rebate ", "C. Refund", "D. Wage garnishment"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Transfer payment. Income is money received from outside sources. Sources of income include salaries, interest earned, dividends, rent, and transfer payments. Transfer payments are monies paid by the government in which no goods or services are received in exchange, such as welfare benefits, veterans' benefits, disaster aid, and unemployment. To receive transfer payments, individuals, businesses, or jurisdictions must meet certain criteria. A rebate is a return of part of the price a customer pays for a product, usually from the product's manufacturer. A refund is a sum of money given back to individuals or businesses. Refunds are issued when an excessive amount has been paid (e.g., tax refund) or when items have been returned to a business. Wage garnishments are court-ordered initiatives that involve taking income taken from an employee's salary and submitting it to another person or organization. Examples of garnishments include child support and alimony. SOURCE: FI:061 SOURCE: WebFinance. (2012). Transfer payments. Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://www.investorwords.com/5050/transfer_payments.html "}, {"number": 36, "question": "One reason customers who pay for products with a credit card usually want to know the interest charges is because those charges ", "choices": ["A. generate the profit for the business. ", "B. increase the retail price. ", "C. are calculated on a yearly basis.", "D. add to the cost of the purchase."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Add to the cost of the purchase. Using credit can add to the total cost of goods and services. For example, interest, or finance, charges are added to accounts that are not paid in full at the end of each payment period. When customers buy products with a credit card, they often pay over a period of time. Then, each month they pay interest on the unpaid balance. The interest charges add to the cost of the purchase. Interest charges do not increase the retail price because customers who pay in cash are not charged interest. Interest usually is calculated monthly rather than yearly. Interest generates profit for the credit-card company rather than the store. SOURCE: FI:002 SOURCE: FI LAP 2\u2014Give Credit Where Credit Is Due (Credit and Its Importance) "}, {"number": 37, "question": "Which of the following is categorized as a fixed expense in a personal budget: ", "choices": ["A. Groceries ", "B. Car payment ", "C. Home repairs", "D. Clothing"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Car payment. Developing a personal budget helps individuals manage their income and expenses. An important consideration in budgeting involves identifying fixed expenses, which are the expenses (cash outflows) that do not fluctuate or change from month to month. Car payments, insurance, and rent are examples of fixed expenses. Groceries, home repairs, and clothing are variable expenses, or expenses that may fluctuate slightly from month to month. SOURCE: FI:066 SOURCE: Ryan, J.S. (2010). Managing your personal finances (6th ed.) [p. 165]. Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a payroll deduction: ", "choices": ["A. Health insurance ", "B. Overtime hours ", "C. Net pay", "D. Pay rate"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Health insurance. Payroll deductions are monies that an employer withholds from an employee's gross earnings. A large portion of the deductions is the various income taxes, which the employer pays to the government on behalf of the employee. Other deductions might include health insurance premiums, voluntary savings, and child-support payments. Net pay is the amount the employee receives in his/her paycheck after the deductions have been subtracted from the gross earnings. Gross earnings are income before deductions. Overtime hours are the number of hours an employee works over his/her regular schedule. Pay rate is the amount of pay a worker earns at a set interval (e.g., an hour). SOURCE: FI:068 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., Hughes, R.J., & Hoyt, W.B. (2005). Business and personal finance (pp. 612-613). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Which of the following financial services providers is most likely to provide a small, local coffee shop with business loans, checking and savings accounts, and overdraft protection: ", "choices": ["A. Eastern Region Investment Bank", "B. Marley and Winston Commercial Bank", "C. Walker, Steinbrenner, and Houghton, CPA Firm", "D. Allen and Mellon Brokerage Firm"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Marley and Winston Commercial Bank. Commercial banks provide a variety of financial services for businesses and individuals, such as checking and savings accounts, loans, credit cards, and overdraft protection. Investment banks primarily work with corporations by underwriting securities, aiding in mergers and acquisitions, etc. CPA (Certified Public Accountant) firms provide accounting services. A brokerage firm buys and sells securities on behalf of investors. SOURCE: FI:075 SOURCE: WebFinance. (2012). Commercial bank. Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://www.investorwords.com/955/commercial_bank.html "}, {"number": 40, "question": "Loss due to shoplifting is an example of a(n) __________ business risk. ", "choices": ["A. economic ", "B. human ", "C. natural", "D. internal"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Human. The possibility of financial loss in marketing is called risk. Human risks are those risks that result from human weakness and unpredictability. Economic risks are those risks related to changes in the market that force a lowering of prices, a change of product, or even failure of businesses. Natural risks are those that result from natural causes such as fires, floods, etc. Since shoplifting is theft by persons who are not employees of the business, it is not considered an internal risk. SOURCE: FI:084 SOURCE: FI LAP 7\u2014Money Matters (Role of Finance in Business) "}, {"number": 41, "question": "What is often one of the largest sources of money flowing out of a business? ", "choices": ["A. Payroll and benefits ", "B. Accounts receivable ", "C. Profit and loss", "D. Goods and services"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Payroll and benefits. Payroll and benefits are often one of the largest sources of money flowing out of a business because businesses must pay employees for their labor. Many businesses also pay for employee benefits, such as health insurance, paid vacation, sick leave, tuition reimbursements, and retirement savings. Businesses bring money in by selling goods and services. Accounts receivable are all the monies owed to a firm by its customers. Profit and loss indicates if the business is making sufficient money to cover its expenses. SOURCE: FI:091 SOURCE: FI LAP 6\u2014Count the Cash (Cash Flow Statements) "}, {"number": 42, "question": "When businesses invest funds to expand, they are involved in the process of ", "choices": ["A. selling. ", "B. depreciation. ", "C. finance.", "D. capitalism."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Finance. This is the process of obtaining funds and using them to achieve the goals of the business. If one of the goals of the business is to expand, then investing funds in expansion is part of the finance process. Depreciation is the reduction in value of goods or assets occurring over a period of time. Selling is a marketing function that involves determining client needs and wants and responding through planned, personalized communication that influences purchase decisions and enhances future business opportunities. Capitalism is an economic system that depends on honest, healthy competition among businesses. SOURCE: FI:354 SOURCE: Pride, W.M., Hughes, R.J., & Kapoor, J.R. (2008). Business (9th ed.) [p. 667]. Boston: Houghton Mifflin. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Many businesses use their company manuals as a source of information in order to __________ new employees. ", "choices": ["A. select ", "B. recruit ", "C. manage", "D. orient"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Orient. One of the main sources of printed information that businesses use in order to orient new employees is the company manual. A manual usually contains the information that a new employee needs to know about company benefits, vacation policy, absenteeism, etc. Businesses usually encourage new employees to thoroughly read the company manual because it will answer most of their questions about routine policies. Businesses do not use their company manuals as a source of information to recruit, manage, or select new employees. SOURCE: HR:360 SOURCE: Noe, R.A., Hollenbeck, J.R., Gerhart, B., Wright, P.M. (2010). Human resource Management: Gaining a competitive advantage (7th ed.) [pp. 333-334]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 44, "question": "A manufacturer has learned that its market is expanding. How should this information be used? ", "choices": ["A. To buy risk protection insurance ", "B. To drop current product lines ", "C. To lay off employees", "D. To increase production"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To increase production. To meet the potential increase in demand, the manufacturer should increase production. An expanding market implies a positive outlook, while laying off employees and dropping product lines are actions taken with negative outlooks. Buying insurance does not indicate an expanding or contracting market. SOURCE: IM:001 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2006). Marketing dynamics (pp. 235-237). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. "}, {"number": 45, "question": "What is a company's private computer network that allows authorized users to share information? ", "choices": ["A. Intranet ", "B. Internet ", "C. E-mail", "D. Extranet"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Intranet. An intranet is an organization's private, secure network that allows authorized users to share information while reducing waste of materials, time, and effort. The Internet is a worldwide network of linked computers that allows the transfer of data from one computer to another anywhere in the world. Email (electronic mail) is the basic Internet tool for sending messages to other computer users. An extranet is a private network that companies use to share information with selected people outside the organization. SOURCE: IM:183 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., Burrow, J.L., & Kleindl, B.A. (2012). Principles of business (8th ed.) [p. 264]. South-Western, Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 46, "question": "Advertisers that use concept testing to obtain feedback from potential customers are conducting ", "choices": ["A. target readership evaluation. ", "B. focus group analysis. ", "C. primary market research.", "D. pretest idea measurement."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Primary market research. Concept testing involves exploring the concept, or idea, for a product in order to obtain feedback. Concept testing is one way to conduct primary market research, which results in obtaining new information specifically for the project at hand. The benefit of conducting primary market research is that it provides information that is relevant to the concept being tested. Other ways to conduct primary market research include analyzing focus groups, evaluating readership, and pretesting. SOURCE: IM:281 SOURCE: Lane, W.R., King, K.W., & Russell, J.T. (2005). Kleppner's advertising procedure (16th ed.) [pp. 468-469]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson/Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 47, "question": "What is the relationship between research purpose and research design? ", "choices": ["A. There is no relationship between the two. ", "B. Purpose dictates design. ", "C. Design is more important than purpose.", "D. Design is unnecessary."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Purpose dictates design. Research purpose and design have a very important relationship. Purpose dictates design. If the design is not appropriate to the purpose, a company can waste a lot of time and money. Both are very necessary ingredients of a research project; one is not more important than the other. SOURCE: IM:284 SOURCE: IM LAP 14\u2014Better By Design (Marketing-Research Designs) "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about sample size: ", "choices": ["A. Sample size is more important than sample design.", "B. The larger the sample size, the better.", "C. It must be determined before the target population is defined.", "D. The size of the sample does not matter."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "The larger the sample size, the better. The size of a sample does matter. Generally speaking, the larger the sample size, the better. It leaves less room for error. Marketers decide on sample size after they have defined their target population. Sample size is not more important than sample design. SOURCE: IM:285 SOURCE: IM LAP 16\u2014Take Your Pick (Nature of Sampling Plans) Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 49, "question": "The data needed for sales volume analyses and market share analyses come from ", "choices": ["A. company sales reports. ", "B. expense reports. ", "C. sales invoices.", "D. customer records."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Company sales reports. The data needed for sales volume analyses and market share analyses come from the facts and figures in sales reports. Expense reports let a company know how much money is being spent on employees' food, lodging, travel, etc. Sales invoices don't show sales in relation to goals, budgets, prior time periods, etc. Customer records don't include sales data for the entire company. SOURCE: IM:184 SOURCE: IM LAP 11\u2014Data Diving (Identifying Marketing Data) "}, {"number": 50, "question": "What data-collection method can be used to obtain product information during the point-of-purchase process? ", "choices": ["A. Photographic scanner ", "B. Volume-tracking scanner ", "C. E-mail survey", "D. Statistical survey"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Volume-tracking scanner. A scanner is an electronic device that reads or translates codes that are placed on products and enters the product information into a computer. Scanners are commonly used during a sales transaction, which is the point of purchase. This is a popular method of collecting information about customers' buying habits and inventory status because the scanning system can track large volumes of goods. Once enough data are collected, researchers evaluate the data to determine how fast or slow certain products are moving, which is information they can use to make business decisions. Photographic scanners, e-mail surveys, and statistical surveys are not data-collection methods that researchers use during the point-of-purchase process. SOURCE: IM:289 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 256-257]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 51, "question": "What process might a business use to enter marketing data into a computer for analysis? ", "choices": ["A. Editing ", "B. Keyboarding ", "C. Screening", "D. Tabulating"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Keyboarding. The most popular technique for entering marketing data into a computer for analysis is keyboarding. The keyboarding technique involves the use of a keyboard that is connected to a computer. An individual types in the information via the keyboard and then saves it to the computer for future use and analysis. Before the data are entered into a computer, they are edited for mistakes. Screening is a method of validating the accuracy of the data. After the data are entered into a computer, researchers are able to tabulate and analyze the information. SOURCE: IM:062 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B. (2010). Essentials of marketing research (4th ed.) [p. 153]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 52, "question": "A research study participant providing incorrect information on a questionnaire is an example of a ", "choices": ["A. feedback method. ", "B. negative answer. ", "C. false positive.", "D. response error."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Response error. One of the issues associated with collecting research information is the possibility that some of the information will be incorrect. A participant providing incorrect information is an example of a response error that may affect the accuracy of the research results. There are many reasons why a participant might give an incorrect answer, such as not understanding the question. A participant providing incorrect information on a questionnaire is not an example of a negative answer, a false positive, or a feedback method. SOURCE: IM:292 SOURCE: Churchill, G.A., Brown, T.J., & Suter, T.A. (2010). Basic marketing research (7th ed.) [p. 380]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 53, "question": "One way to determine the usefulness and accuracy of research information is to ", "choices": ["A. assess timeliness. ", "B. organize a database. ", "C. calculate frequency.", "D. develop a profile."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Assess timeliness. To be useful, research information should be timely and current. If the information is outdated, it might be inaccurate and not helpful in addressing the research problem or issue. As a result, it is important to assess timeliness when collecting research information to make sure it is as current as possible. It is not possible to determine the usefulness and accuracy of research information by organizing a database, calculating frequency, or developing a profile. SOURCE: IM:428 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2006). Marketing essentials (p. 614). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 54, "question": "Customers are more likely to spend a lot of time evaluating several options before buying a product when ", "choices": ["A. the need is immediate. ", "B. the product is perishable. ", "C. the product is expensive.", "D. brand insistence is a factor."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "The product is expensive. Because money is a limited resource, customers tend to spend more time comparing and evaluating the features and benefits of expensive items before making a decision to buy. Individuals tend to spend more time evaluating options when buying homes, cars, and computers. Businesses tend to spend more time evaluating items such as operating equipment and contract services (e.g., ad agencies and tech support) before making a decision. Customers are less likely to spend a lot of time evaluating perishable items (e.g., food) or things that they need immediately (emergency health care). If a customer has a high level of loyalty to a specific brand, then the customer will spend less time evaluating competitors' products before making a decision to buy. SOURCE: MK:014 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong, G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [p. 145]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. "}, {"number": 55, "question": "A market for goods and services exists when there is a group of ", "choices": ["A. laborers. ", "B. responsible homeowners. ", "C. professionals.", "D. potential consumers."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Potential consumers. A market is composed of individuals who have unfulfilled desires and are willing and able to spend money in order to satisfy those desires. Without knowing the needs of professionals, homeowners, or laborers, it cannot be determined if they are potential consumers. SOURCE: MP:003 SOURCE: MP LAP 3\u2014Have We Met? (Market Identification) "}, {"number": 56, "question": "What types of environmental factors do businesses often consider when conducting a situational analysis? ", "choices": ["A. Formal and informal ", "B. Physical and personal ", "C. Ethical and legal", "D. Internal and external"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Internal and external. The environmental factors that businesses consider when conducting a situational analysis may be internal as well as external. Internal factors are those within the business itself that have an impact on the business's marketing effort, such as the distribution system or the pricing strategy. External factors are those that exist outside the business and over which the business may have no control, such as the state of the economy or the number of competitors. Businesses examine both types of environmental factors in order to adapt to change and make effective marketing decisions. For example, a business might decide to adjust its prices to remain competitive if the economy is slowing down. Physical and personal, ethical and legal, and formal and informal are not types of environmental factors that businesses consider when conducting a situational analysis. SOURCE: MP:008 SOURCE: Soloman, M. R., Marshall, G. W., & Stuart, E. W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [pp. 43-44]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 57, "question": "The Microsoft Corporation generated $51.12 billion in revenue in 2007. This is an example of ", "choices": ["A. factual information. ", "B. unwarranted criticism. ", "C. inconclusive evidence.", "D. current data."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Factual information. Facts contain true data or information. Microsoft has multiple sources of documentation that indicates it generated $51.12 billion in revenue in 2007, which makes the statement a fact. It is important for companies to verify facts when they are making business decisions. Basing decisions on incorrect information can be very costly to a company. Unwarranted criticism is inappropriate, biased, or exaggerated feedback. Inconclusive evidence means that the presented facts do not indicate a distinct or unquestionable outcome of a situation. The amount of money Microsoft generated occurred a few years ago; therefore, the statement does not contain current data. SOURCE: NF:077 SOURCE: WiseGEEK.com. (2003-2012). What is the difference between fact and opinion? Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://www.wisegeek.com/what-is-the-difference-between-fact-andopinion.htm "}, {"number": 58, "question": "How does appropriate information management affect a business's relationship with its customers? ", "choices": ["A. Businesses lose focus on customers.", "B. Businesses earn higher profits.", "C. Businesses serve customers more effectively.", "D. Businesses make better financial decisions."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Businesses serve customers more effectively. Managing information appropriately helps businesses focus on the important task of serving customers more effectively which, in turn, may help lead to higher profits, although it is not a guarantee. A business's financial decisions may or may not have to do with serving customers. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: NF LAP 3\u2014In the Know (Nature of Information Management) Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 59, "question": "A company's computer network allows many users to access the same programs on different computer units throughout the company. What type of computer operating system is the company using? ", "choices": ["A. Hosted ", "B. Multithreading ", "C. Augmented", "D. Multiprocessing"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Multiprocessing. The computer's operating system consists of the components needed to run all of the computer applications and programs. An operating system that allows several central processing units (computers) to access a single program has multiprocessing capabilities. Multithreading capabilities allow different components of one computer program to run at the same time. Augmented and hosted are not types of operating systems. SOURCE: NF:085 SOURCE: Webopedia. (2012). Operating system. Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/O/operating_system.html "}, {"number": 60, "question": "What feature do many word-processing software programs contain that enables businesses to prepare accurate written documents? ", "choices": ["A. Encyclopedia ", "B. Calculator ", "C. Flowchart", "D. Dictionary"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Dictionary. Many word-processing software programs contain a dictionary, which enables businesses to check the spelling in their documents. The dictionary feature identifies words that are incorrectly spelled and provides several alternatives. This feature helps businesses to prepare accurately-written documents and avoid sending letters or reports to customers that contain misspelled words. Some word-processing software programs include a calculator, which helps businesses with mathematical tabulations. A flowchart is part of spreadsheet software programs. Businesses with Internet capability have access to online encyclopedias. SOURCE: NF:007 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials [p. 199]. Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 61, "question": "A benefit of using an integrated software application package is that it allows businesses to ", "choices": ["A. manage all aspects of the operation. ", "B. develop research reports. ", "C. search the Internet for information.", "D. prepare routine budgets."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Manage all aspects of the operation. Integrated software application packages allow businesses to manage all aspects of the operation, including planning sales, marketing, etc. For example, businesses can monitor the manufacturing process to track the level of inventory to know when products will be available to ship to customers and then generate invoices. Word processing software is used to develop research reports. Spreadsheet programs are used to prepare routine budgets. These programs, as well as programs that enable businesses to search the Internet, may be combined in an integrated software application package. SOURCE: NF:088 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 206). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 62, "question": "If a business wants all of the members of a project team to have the ability to access the same information from different locations, it should use _________ applications. ", "choices": ["A. data mining ", "B. presentation software ", "C. spreadsheet software", "D. groupware computer"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Groupware computer. Groupware computer software allows employees to share and access the same information from a variety of locations. The ability to access the same information allows each employee to have the necessary data to complete his/her portion of the project in a timely manner. Using groupware computer applications can increase productivity and efficiency. Businesspeople use presentation software to develop computer-operated visual aids that support an oral presentation. Spreadsheet software programs are designed to organize, calculate, and analyze mathematical or numerical information. Data mining is the process of searching computer databases to look for patterns and relationships among information. SOURCE: NF:011 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 109]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Businesses usually maintain customer sales records that contain information about the ", "choices": ["A. discounts offered by manufacturers. ", "B. types of products being purchased. ", "C. cost of paying commissioned salespeople.", "D. suppliers that provide the goods."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Types of products being purchased. Businesses maintain a variety of records about the quantities and types of products that customers are purchasing. These records are usually known as sales records. By analyzing past sales records, businesses can determine what customers are buying, when they are buying, and how much they are buying. This helps a business forecast future sales so it can be prepared to offer the products that customers want. Businesses do not maintain customer sales records that contain information about the discounts offered by manufacturers, the cost of paying commissioned salespeople, or the suppliers that provide the goods. SOURCE: NF:002 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L. (2006). Marketing (2nd ed.) [pp. 120-121]. Mason, OH: South-Western. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 64, "question": "A clothing manufacturer builds quality into its operating system, placing responsibility on each employee. This process is known as quality ", "choices": ["A. delivery. ", "B. guarantee. ", "C. assurance.", "D. inspection."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Assurance. This clothing manufacturer is using quality assurance. Quality assurance is a process businesses use to prevent defective products from being created, not just to eliminate or correct them after they've already been produced. Quality inspection is a process businesses use to check for defects after products have been produced. Quality guarantee and quality delivery are not traditional terms used in operations or quality control. SOURCE: OP:189 SOURCE: OP LAP 3\u2014Smooth Operations (Nature of Operations) "}, {"number": 65, "question": "Some companies have lowered the number of accidents on the job by using ", "choices": ["A. fewer workers. ", "B. safety programs. ", "C. suggestion boxes.", "D. surveillance cameras."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Safety programs. These programs include accident prevention instruction and educational presentations such as safety lectures, slides, films, and booklets. Hiring fewer workers or providing suggestion boxes would not reduce the number of accidents on the job. Surveillance cameras are used to prevent shoplifting. SOURCE: OP:007 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2010). Marketing dynamics: Teacher's edition (2nd ed.) [pp. 407-408]. Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company, Inc. "}, {"number": 66, "question": "The purpose of depositing large bills in drop boxes upon receipt is to prevent ", "choices": ["A. robbery. ", "B. fraud. ", "C. burglary.", "D. pilferage."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Robbery. Cash drop boxes are built into the floor of the business and cannot be removed or opened by employees. Businesses using drop boxes often attempt to prevent robberies by posting a sign indicating that they use a drop box. Fraud, deceiving or cheating an individual or a business out of money; burglary, any illegal entry into a building to commit a theft; and pilferage, theft of small sums of money or inexpensive items, are all types of losses that businesses try to prevent. SOURCE: OP:013 SOURCE: eHow.com. (1999-2012). About retail security. Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://www.ehow.com/about_7217080_retail-security.html "}, {"number": 67, "question": "What do managers often do after a project has been successfully completed? ", "choices": ["A. Provide feedback to vendors ", "B. Close the front office ", "C. Give up power", "D. Prepare a report"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Prepare a report. When a project has been successfully completed, it's a good idea to have a final meeting. Group members often will have suggestions for improvement that the manager can include in a report. Managers usually prepare some type of brief report that explains the project, what worked, and what didn't work. This is particularly helpful if the project is one that will be completed again. The information in the report will make next year's project much easier to plan and manage. In many cases, there is no front office to close. Managers do not actually give up power or authority. The project they were in charge of is simply over. After the project has been completed, managers often obtain feedback from the group to include in a report. SOURCE: OP:002 SOURCE: QS LAP 18\u2014Make It Happen "}, {"number": 68, "question": "Tatiana is a project manager who is ready to close a project, and has scheduled a \u201clessons learned\u201d meeting with the project team. What will Tatiana most likely include on her meeting agenda? ", "choices": ["A. Explanation of the stakeholders' expectations", "B. The definition of the project's purpose", "C. Discussion of specific challenges encountered", "D. The distribution of project resources allocated"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Discussion of specific challenges encountered. After the stakeholders receive the deliverables, the project manager often meets with the team members to discuss what went well and what didn't go well with the project. The team members also discuss how processes could have been improved. The information obtained from the \u201clessons learned\u201d meeting is summarized in a \u201clessons learned\u201d document, which can be used by teams that execute similar projects for the organization in the future. The project's purpose and the stakeholders' expectations are explained during the initiation phase of the project. The allocation of resources is determined during the planning phase of the project. SOURCE: OP:159 SOURCE: Campbell, G.M., & Baker, S. (2007). The complete idiot's guide to project management (4th ed.) [pp. 335-336]. New York: Penguin Group. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Which of the following represents an operating expense for a business: ", "choices": ["A. Sales revenue ", "B. Cost of goods ", "C. Cost of utilities", "D. Returns and allowances"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Cost of utilities. This is an expense that is part of a business's day-to-day operation. Sales revenue is income coming into the business from sales. The cost of goods is the expense of purchasing the goods. Returns and allowances are refunds or price adjustments given to customers. SOURCE: OP:024 SOURCE: Ivancevich, J.M., & Duening, T.N. (2007). Business principles, guidelines, and practices (2nd ed.) [pp. 523-524]. Mason, OH: Thomson. "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about housekeeping in a retail business: ", "choices": ["A. It is not an important responsibility. ", "B. It is usually a monthly activity. ", "C. It is an ongoing responsibility.", "D. It is limited to emptying trash."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "It is an ongoing responsibility. Keeping the sales areas of a retail business clean and neat is not a onetime or monthly activity, but an ongoing responsibility. It can include dusting, straightening stock, picking up debris from the floor, getting rid of empty boxes, or any other light housekeeping chores that are needed. It is important to the success of the business for customers to find sales areas as neat and clean as possible. SOURCE: OP:032 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2010). Marketing dynamics: Teacher's edition (2nd ed.) [p. 407]. Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company, Inc. "}, {"number": 71, "question": "Which of the following would be a short-term financial goal: ", "choices": ["A. Starting your own business ", "B. Saving enough to buy a DVD ", "C. Walking a mile every day", "D. Getting a promotion within five years"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Saving enough to buy a DVD. A short-term goal is an objective or want that takes less than a year to achieve\u2014normally set for a day, week, or month. Saving money for any purpose, such as purchasing a DVD, is a financial goal. Starting your own business would be a career goal that includes long-term financial goals. Walking a mile every day is a physical goal. Getting a promotion within five years is a long-term career goal. SOURCE: PD:018 SOURCE: PD LAP 16\u2014Go For the Goal (Goal Setting) "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Creative problem solving requires the ability to think ", "choices": ["A. nontraditionally. ", "B. systematically. ", "C. methodically.", "D. illogically."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Nontraditionally. To solve problems innovatively, you must be able to break away from traditional, systematic, methodical thought patterns. By no means, however, does this imply that creative thinking should be illogical. SOURCE: PD:012 SOURCE: Wallace, H.R., & Masters, L.A. (2006). Personal development for life & work (9th ed.) [pp. 331-333]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 73, "question": "The principles by which you live your life are referred to as your ", "choices": ["A. feelings. ", "B. values. ", "C. issues.", "D. interests."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Values. In order to develop self-understanding, you should examine your values because they affect everything you are and plan to become. Feelings are the emotional responses (positive or negative) elicited by values, issues are points of interest and/or disagreement, and interests are the things that we are involved with, concerned for, or curious about. SOURCE: PD:013 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 258-260). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 74, "question": "What should job applicants do if certain questions on the application do not pertain to them? ", "choices": ["A. Leave the space blank ", "B. Make up an answer ", "C. Ignore the question", "D. Write N/A in the space"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Write N/A in the space. Some questions on job applications do not pertain to all applicants, such as military service. In those cases, the applicants should write N/A, or Not Applicable, indicating that they have read and understood the question, but that it does not pertain to them. Applicants should not leave the space blank because businesses may think that they overlooked the question or did not understand it. It is never appropriate to make up an answer or to purposely ignore a question. SOURCE: PD:027 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [p. 47]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 75, "question": "Job applicants often list on their r\u00e9sum\u00e9s the names, positions, and addresses of several people who are willing to serve as ", "choices": ["A. references. ", "B. companions. ", "C. associates.", "D. colleagues."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "References. Many job applicants include the names, positions, and addresses of several people who have agreed to be their references. References are people who can provide information about an applicant's character and qualifications. References often include former teachers and employers and long-time family friends. Companions and associates are terms for people who work, travel, and participate in activities together. Colleagues are coworkers. SOURCE: PD:031 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [pp. 45-48]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 76, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an occupationally specific trade association: ", "choices": ["A. Retail Merchants Association", "B. National Restaurant Association", "C. Chamber of Commerce", "D. Sales and Marketing Executives International"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "National Restaurant Association. Members of the National Restaurant Association all have interests in the field of food service. Merchants' associations and chambers of commerce unite individuals who represent the same geographic region but different areas of marketing. SMEI is a professional organization for sales executives who work in a variety of industries. SOURCE: PD:036 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 789-790). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 77, "question": "The price factor is important to the other three factors in marketing because the four marketing factors are ", "choices": ["A. in competition. ", "B. interdependent. ", "C. unique.", "D. equivalent."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Interdependent. Pricing plays a key role in marketing. In fact, it is one of four factors in marketing: product, price, place, and promotion. These factors are interdependent because a change in one of these will change the others. The four factors are not in competition, nor are they unique or unusual. The marketing factors are not equivalent or the same. SOURCE: PI:001 SOURCE: PI LAP 2\u2014The Price is Right (Pricing) "}, {"number": 78, "question": "Predatory pricing is an unethical business practice because it can create economic conditions in which ", "choices": ["A. consumers have fewer choices.", "B. consumers pay higher property taxes.", "C. small businesses gain significant profits.", "D. small businesses control market conditions."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Consumers have fewer choices. Predatory pricing is the practice of pricing goods extremely low with the goal of driving the competition out of business. If a company forces its competitors out of business, consumers have fewer items from which to choose or fewer places to purchase goods. Predatory pricing practices might leave fewer choices for consumers, but they do not necessarily lead to higher property taxes. Small companies are often the businesses that are most affected by predatory pricing. SOURCE: PI:015 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [p. 364]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Product/service management can help to decrease ", "choices": ["A. business risk. ", "B. profits. ", "C. sales.", "D. financial success."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Business risk. A company that spreads its business risk over several products is in a much better position than a company that relies on one or two products for its income. If one of those products fails, and no replacement products have been planned, the company may be in serious trouble. Product/service management is supposed to increase profits, sales, and financial success rather than decrease them. SOURCE: PM:001 SOURCE: PM LAP 17\u2014Rapping Up Products (Nature of Product/Service Management) "}, {"number": 80, "question": "What is a technologically advanced method that allows businesses to produce products that are specialized for a very few customers? ", "choices": ["A. Mass customization ", "B. Automatic production ", "C. Computerized robotics", "D. Intermittent conversion"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Mass customization. Computerization and the technology of mass production have created the method of mass customization which allows businesses to produce customized products for one customer or only a very few customers. Businesses that use a mass-customization method can produce large quantities of one product in many different varieties. This method allows businesses to meet the individual needs of many customers by making variations of one product. Automatic production, computerized robotics, and intermittent conversion are not methods that allow businesses to produce products that are specialized for a very few customers. SOURCE: PM:039 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [p. 220]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 81, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a business behaving ethically in an effort to protect consumers: ", "choices": ["A. Explaining the new manufacturing process", "B. Wrapping products in plain paper", "C. Placing informative commercials on television", "D. Using tamper-resistant packaging"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Using tamper-resistant packaging. Many businesses produce products that might be harmful to consumers if the products are tampered with or become contaminated. To protect consumers, businesses often use tamper-resistant packaging which makes it extremely difficult for someone to get to the product without damaging the packaging. As a result, customers are able to easily determine if this type of packaging has been tampered with, which warns them not to buy the products. Using tamperresistant packaging is an ethical procedure that businesses follow in an effort to protect their products and ensure the safety of their customers. Products usually are not wrapped in plain paper. Placing informative commercials on television and explaining the new manufacturing process are not ways of protecting consumers. SOURCE: PM:040 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 661-663). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 82, "question": "Being attentive, watching trends, and pinpointing problems are ways for entrepreneurs to uncover ", "choices": ["A. true motives. ", "B. financial strategies. ", "C. intangible goals.", "D. product opportunities."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Product opportunities. A product opportunity occurs when a favorable circumstance to market a product exists. Entrepreneurs uncover these circumstances by being attentive, watching trends, and pinpointing problems. Financial strategies are plans of action for achieving financial goals. An intangible goal is an objective or desired outcome that cannot be detected through the senses. True motives are the real reasons for taking a certain course of action. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2006). Marketing dynamics (pp. 279-280). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. "}, {"number": 83, "question": "What synectics technique compares a problem with something else that is unrelated? ", "choices": ["A. Discretionary comparisons ", "B. Forced analogies ", "C. Arbitrary metaphors", "D. Deliberate allegories"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Forced analogies. A forced analogy is a synectics technique that compares a problem with something totally unrelated. Arbitrary metaphors, discretionary comparisons, and deliberate allegories are not terms widely used to describe a synectics creative-thinking method. SOURCE: PM:127 SOURCE: PM LAP 11\u2014Unleash Your Oh! Zone (Idea Generation) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Feedback from customers about problems with products provides producers with the information needed to ", "choices": ["A. select promotional media. ", "B. hire employees. ", "C. make product improvements.", "D. modify brand values."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Make product improvements. Businesses receive benefits from offering warranties and guarantees. One benefit is getting feedback from customers about unsatisfactory products. Without this feedback, the company would not be able to make corrections and improvements in its products. Companies do not use information about problems with products to select promotional media, hire employees, or modify brand values. SOURCE: PM:020 SOURCE: PM LAP 4\u2014Promises, Promises (Warranties and Guarantees) "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Which of the following would be least likely to be found on the label of a nonhazardous product: ", "choices": ["A. Proper circumstances for use ", "B. Acceptable uses ", "C. Precautions when using the product", "D. Ingredients"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Precautions when using the product. Labels for nonhazardous products should list all ingredients, any additives or preservatives the product contains, fiber content, acceptable uses, unacceptable uses, or proper circumstances for use. On the other hand, producers of hazardous products can use the product label to warn consumers of any dangers involved in using the product and tell them what precautions to take. For example, the makers of a drain cleaner print a poison \"death's head\" on the label and tell consumers how to protect themselves when using the cleaner. All label information should be accurate and as easy to understand as possible. SOURCE: PM:017 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 664-667). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 86, "question": "What a brand is and stands for, as well as how it behaves and the qualities it projects, are embodied in its ", "choices": ["A. personality. ", "B. identity. ", "C. logo.", "D. equity."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Personality. Just as with a person, the brand has an essence, or a personality, that embodies what it is, what it stands for, and how it behaves. Brand equity is customers' goodwill that accumulates over time, while brand identity consists of a brand's representations, including a name, logo, and possibly, a trade character. A logo is a brand symbol\u2014that part of its identity that cannot be spoken. SOURCE: PM:206 SOURCE: PM LAP 6\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (The Nature of Branding) "}, {"number": 87, "question": "The marketing function that helps sellers to provide information to buyers about the seller's products is ", "choices": ["A. distribution. ", "B. promotion. ", "C. purchasing.", "D. financing."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Promotion. Promotion is the communication of information about goods, services, images, and/or ideas. It is used by businesses to inform consumers about products and to persuade them to buy. Distribution is the marketing function that is responsible for moving, storing, locating, and/or transferring ownership of goods or services. Purchasing is a business activity which involves the planning and procedures necessary to obtain goods and services for use in the operation of a business or for resale. Financing is a business activity which involves understanding the financial concepts used in making business decisions. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: PR LAP 2\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Promotion) "}, {"number": 88, "question": "One reason advertising prescription drugs online might be considered an ethical issue is because the advertisements might persuade customers to ", "choices": ["A. use drugs they do not need. ", "B. obtain drugs from the manufacturer. ", "C. buy drugs they cannot afford.", "D. order drugs that are inexpensive."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Use drugs they do not need. Advertising prescription drugs is often a controversial topic. Those who feel it is ethical to advertise drugs believe that the ads are simply providing information. Those who feel that this type of advertising might be unethical believe that it persuades customers to ask their doctors for drugs they do not need. If customers see ads for certain drugs, they may decide they would like to try them. Oftentimes, doctors will write prescriptions for patients if they are persistent, even if the doctors don't think the drugs are necessary. Also, promoting name-brand prescription drugs encourages customers to ask for them rather than comparable generic drugs that are less expensive. Customers usually are unable to buy drugs they cannot afford. Prescription drugs usually must be purchased from a licensed pharmacy rather than from the manufacturer. Persuading customers to order inexpensive drugs is not an ethical issue. SOURCE: PR:099 SOURCE: NGP. (2012). Pharmaceutical marketing: Just what the doctor ordered? Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://www.ngpharma.com/article/Pharmaceutical-marketing-just-what-the-doctorordered/ "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following technological tools has made it possible for a business to send personalized promotional messages in a cost-efficient manner: ", "choices": ["A. Electronic mail ", "B. Encryption card ", "C. Interactive banner", "D. Exclusive kiosk"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Electronic mail. Electronic mail (e-mail) refers to the electronic transmission of messages across computer networks. Businesses often use electronic mail to send promotional messages to customers or potential customers in a cost-efficient manner. Encryption card, interactive banner, and exclusive kiosk are not technological terms that are commonly used to describe a means of sending promotional messages. SOURCE: PR:100 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong, G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [pp. 503-504]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. "}, {"number": 90, "question": "What type of promotional media might a statewide chain of supermarkets use in order to reach a large number of potential customers in its geographic area? ", "choices": ["A. Regional magazines ", "B. Suburban newspapers ", "C. National television", "D. Transit advertising"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Suburban newspapers. Newspapers are the main advertising media for supermarkets. Suburban newspapers are intended for audiences within a certain geographic area. These newspapers contain articles that appeal to customers who live in that area and attract advertisers who want to reach that specific market. A statewide chain of supermarkets might choose to advertise in suburban newspapers in order to reach a large number of potential customers who live in the area that the chain services. Transit advertising serves certain city areas and would not reach customers in the chain's entire area. Regional magazines and national television would reach customers far beyond the chain's geographic area. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: PR LAP 3\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Promotional Media) Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 91, "question": "What best describes the goal of amplified word-of-mouth? ", "choices": ["A. Encouraging customers to provide both positive and negative feedback", "B. Providing information to activists to share with others", "C. Building loyal relationships with the customers", "D. Improving the quality of goods and services the business offers"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Providing information to activists to share with others. Word-of-mouth promotion involves customers who tell others about their satisfaction with the business. Amplified word-of-mouth promotion involves the use of proactive efforts (campaigns) in which the business provides specific information to customers (activists) to pass along to their friends, family, and business contacts. On the other hand, organic wordof-mouth promotion occurs naturally. Because customers are satisfied with the business and its products, they tell others about this satisfaction in the course of normal conversation. For example, if a business shows a sincere interest in the customer by asking for feedback, taking actions to ensure customer loyalty, or improving products, the customer is likely to share those positive experiences with others. SOURCE: PR:247 SOURCE: Digital Vibes. (2008, June 1). Word of mouth: Organic or amplified. Retrieved August 9, 2012, from http://digitalvibes.wordpress.com/2008/06/01/word-of-mouth-101-organic-vsamplified/ "}, {"number": 92, "question": "What communication channels is a corporation's public-relations department most likely to use to maintain positive relationships with shareholders? ", "choices": ["A. Newsletters, annual reports, and the company's web site", "B. Press releases, online social networks, and print advertisements", "C. News conferences, consumer blogs, and employee manuals", "D. Policy manuals, commercials, and sponsorships"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Newsletters, annual reports, and the company's web site. Public relations involves establishing good relationships between the business and the public. A business tries to maintain positive relationships with different groups that make up the public, such as employees, local businesses, government officials, the media, and the business's shareholders. Because the shareholders are the owners of the company, it is important to develop and maintain positive relationships with them. The public-relations department does this by communicating with them through newsletters, annual reports, the company's web site, and online social networks. Print advertisements and commercials are forms of nonpersonal advertising. Businesses use press releases and news conferences to convey information to the media. Policy manuals help guide employees' actions on the job. Consumer blogs can be developed by anyone to communicate positive and negative information about various goods and services. A sponsorship is a partnership in which a company pays a fee to affiliate itself with a team, league, or event. SOURCE: PR:250 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [pp. 432-435]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 93, "question": "What communication channel do businesses often use to disseminate positive public-relations information about themselves and their employees to external audiences? ", "choices": ["A. The media ", "B. Marketing-research firm ", "C. Creative writer", "D. Infomercial"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The media. The media are the message channels used by a seller to promote a good, service, or ideas, e.g., radio, television, newspapers, magazines, Internet, etc. Businesses often use the media to disseminate positive information about themselves and their employees to external audiences in order to establish good relations with those audiences. For example, businesses might prepare press releases or hold press conferences so the media will publicize the information and inform external audiences. A marketing-research firm conducts marketing research for clients. A creative writer puts the information in a written format but does not disseminate it. An infomercial is a lengthy commercial that looks like a television program. SOURCE: PR:253 SOURCE: Clow, K.E, & Baack, D. (2010). Integrated advertising, promotion, and marketing communications (4th ed.) [pp. 356-357]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 94, "question": "The most appropriate way for the High-Tech Computer Company to communicate information about its new line of computers at a trade show is by ", "choices": ["A. sending direct mail. ", "B. holding product demonstrations. ", "C. placing billboard advertisements.", "D. developing a contest."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Holding product demonstrations. A trade show is an event where businesses communicate information about products to build sales leads and interest. Trade-show participation is a way for businesses to communicate with the individuals or businesses most likely to buy the business's products. When a business's salesperson demonstrates the product, trade-show attendees see the product's attributes and how it works. In some demonstrations, the show attendees often have an opportunity to try the product themselves. Businesses send direct mail to their customers' homes and businesses. A billboard is a form of outdoor advertising. Direct mail and billboards are not the most appropriate ways to communicate at a trade show. A contest is a sales promotion activity that offers a prize or award. Holding a contest, rather than developing one, is a good way to draw attendees to a trade-show booth, so the business can communicate information about its products. SOURCE: PR:254 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [p. 579]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 95, "question": "A business's advertising and display efforts should be ", "choices": ["A. contradictory. ", "B. coordinated. ", "C. separate.", "D. competitive."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Coordinated. Advertising and display should work together and have a common theme in order to do an effective job of selling the business's products. Such coordination results in a comprehensive promotional approach, rather than a disjointed one that would result from independent, contradictory, or competitive efforts. SOURCE: PR:076 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2006). Marketing essentials (p. 367). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 96, "question": "Which of the following situations is most likely to result in long-term, increased sales for a business: ", "choices": ["A. Constantly providing new choices for consumers", "B. Raising the price of its current products", "C. Lowering the price of its current products", "D. Eliminating a slow-selling product line"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Constantly providing new choices for consumers. There is much competition between businesses, which leads to increased competition to produce better products. Businesses need to develop new or improved products in order to make more sales than their competitors. A company that raises or lowers the prices of existing products may make temporary sales gains, but only a company that provides choices based on the needs of its consumers will enjoy a long-term sales increase. Elimination of a slow-selling product line may not increase sales for a business. SOURCE: SE:017 SOURCE: SE LAP 117\u2014Sell Away (The Nature and Scope of Selling) "}, {"number": 97, "question": "Salespeople may risk losing a sale to a potential customer if they are unable to explain a business's __________ policies. ", "choices": ["A. purchasing ", "B. operating ", "C. employee", "D. selling"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Selling. Selling policies are general rules established by management to guide the personal selling effort and outline how things must be done. Salespeople may encounter problems when they are not knowledgeable of their company's selling policies, and are unable to explain them to potential customers. Salespeople may risk losing a sale if they are unable to explain policies about issues such as credit terms and delivery service. Operating policies regulate the actual running of a business. Employee policies are guidelines explaining how employees are to act and how they are to deal with customers. Purchasing policies are guidelines that direct purchasing decisions. SOURCE: SE:932 SOURCE: Levy, M., & Weitz, B.A. (2007). Retailing management (6th ed.) [pp. 251-252, 262]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 98, "question": "With a high level of selling ethics, you would typically ask which of the following questions in an ethical situation: ", "choices": ["A. What would others advise? ", "B. What can I get away with? ", "C. What is required of me?", "D. What is the right thing to do?"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "What is the right thing to do? With a high level of selling ethics, you would typically ask, \"What is the right thing to do?\" You would not consider what you could get away with, and you would not do only what is required. Although you might consider someone else's advice, the right thing to do may be different from that advice. SOURCE: SE:106 SOURCE: SE LAP 129\u2014Keep It Real\u2014In Sales (Selling Ethics) "}, {"number": 99, "question": "What form of technology are salespeople using that eliminates the need to carry a laptop and personal data assistant while making sales calls? ", "choices": ["A. Router ", "B. Pager ", "C. Micro kiosk", "D. Smartphone"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Smartphone. Smartphones, such as Blackberries and iPhones, are mobile devices that salespeople can use to make telephone calls, access the Internet, manage contacts, schedule appointments, and send wireless faxes while calling on customers. Smartphones also contain digital cameras, which are often useful when salespeople must take photographs of goods or spaces that require customized products. Because smartphones have many applications and are small enough to fit into a coat pocket, salespeople no longer need to carry around laptops, personal data assistants, etc. Pagers have capabilities such as telephone message notification and e-mail, but do not have the same capabilities as smartphones. A kiosk is a stand-alone structure placed in public places that is designed to provide information and sell products. Micro kiosks are smaller and more compact than traditional kiosks. A router is a device that intercepts and forwards signals on a computer network, allowing users to obtain wireless Internet access. SOURCE: SE:107 SOURCE: Ingram, T.N, LaForge, R.W., Avila, R.A., Schwepker, C.H., & Williams, M.R. (2008). Professional selling: A trust-based approach (4th ed.) [pp. 277-278]. Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. Test 1069 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 100, "question": "The Acquired Needs Theory implies that a person's buying behavior is affected by three primary needs, which include achievement, power, and ", "choices": ["A. advancement. ", "B. affiliation. ", "C. esteem.", "D. enrichment."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Affiliation. By understanding peoples' needs and the factors that motivate them to buy, a salesperson is in a better position to help his/her customers make appropriate purchasing decisions. Many theories exist that try to explain peoples' needs and the factors that motivate them to behave in certain ways. The Acquired Needs Theory places needs into three categories\u2014achievement, power, and affiliation. The Acquired Needs Theory suggests that one of the three needs tends to be dominant in an individual, and the dominant needs guide or motivate the person's behavior. A person's self-esteem and her/his desire for advancement and enrichment are possible factors that affect the individual's level of need for achievement, power, and affiliation. SOURCE: SE:359 SOURCE: DuBrin, A. (2009). Essentials of management: Instructor's edition (8th ed.) [p. 377]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning"}], "1076-MKT": [{"number": 1, "question": "One business promising to do something for another business in return for receiving compensation is an example of a ", "choices": ["A. treaty. ", "B. benefit. ", "C. contract.", "D. enterprise."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Contract. Contracts are agreements among two or more parties stating that one party is to do something in return for something provided by another party. If one business promises to do something for another business in return for receiving compensation, the two businesses have a contract. Then, the businesses are obligated to fulfill their part of the contract. In most cases, contracts benefit both parties, although promising to do something in return for receiving compensation is not necessarily a benefit. Treaties are trade agreements among two or more countries. An enterprise is another term for a business. SOURCE: BL:002 SOURCE: Beatty, J.F., & Samuelson, S.S. (2008). Essentials of business law (3rd ed.) [pp. 211-219]. Mason, OH: Thomson/South-Western. "}, {"number": 2, "question": "A basic principle of procedural due process involves __________ before taking action. ", "choices": ["A. obtaining witnesses ", "B. providing notice ", "C. awarding damages", "D. creating evidence"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Providing notice. Due process is the concept that the government must respect all of the legal rights that are owed to individuals and businesses according to the law of the land. Legal procedure refers to the methods and processes that are used to protect an individual's or business's legal rights. In many societies, these rights include the right to be notified of accusation or lawsuit (providing notice), the right to obtain legal counsel, the right to be heard in court, the right to confront the accuser, etc. Obtaining witnesses is a pretrial activity. Awarding damages is a possible remedy or outcome of civil litigation. Due process involves presenting evidence, not creating it. SOURCE: BL:070 SOURCE: McAdams, T., Neslund, N., & Neslund, K. (2007). Law, business, and society (8th ed.) [pp. 199-200]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Channels of distribution allow channel members to share ", "choices": ["A. equipment. ", "B. profits. ", "C. risk.", "D. employees."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Risk. Channels of distribution allow channel members to share risk. Moving products through a channel requires financing and includes an inherent financial risk. Channel members do not share profits, equipment, or employees. SOURCE: CM:001 SOURCE: CM LAP 2\u2014Chart Your Channels (Channel Management) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Massimo's Corner Grocery sells a variety of fruits and vegetables to consumers within the community. Massimo's is considered a(n) ", "choices": ["A. wholesaler. ", "B. retailer. ", "C. agent.", "D. producer."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Retailer. A retailer is a business that buys goods and sells them to the final consumer. Wholesalers are intermediaries who buy goods from producers or agents and resell them to other businesses. Agents are intermediaries who assist in the sale of goods but do not take title to them. Producers are growers, providers, or manufacturers of goods and services. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: CM LAP 1\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Radio frequency identification (RFID) increases channel efficiency because it stores product information on a computer chip that is attached to the ", "choices": ["A. box or container. ", "B. delivery truck's antenna. ", "C. customer's inventory report.", "D. receiving dock."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Box or container. Radio frequency identification (RFID) involves storing an order's product information on a computer chip and then attaching it to the shipment's box, container, or pallet. When a shipment arrives at a business, warehouse personnel use computer scanners to receive the items quickly, which increases efficiency. The computer chip is not attached to the delivery truck's antenna, the customer's inventory report, or the receiving dock. SOURCE: CM:004 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [p. 360]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 11 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "To assist and support another channel member's sales promotion in a particular area, a producer might work with the channel member to ", "choices": ["A. coordinate a regional advertising campaign. ", "B. research and develop innovative products. ", "C. identify trends and market shifts.", "D. develop a reliable accounting system."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Coordinate a regional advertising campaign. Channel members are all of the businesses and individuals that assist in moving goods and services from the producer to the consumer. In many situations, producers will assist other channel members (e.g., dealers, distributors, retailers) in sales promotions. One way to assist channel members planning a sales promotion in a certain area is by providing resources (e.g., money, product samples) to develop an advertising campaign. The goal of the advertising campaign is to communicate information about the sales promotion to consumers in order to stimulate interest and sales. The producer may provide assistance by developing new products and identifying market trends, but these activities do not relate to a specific sales promotion. An accounting system refers to the methods and procedures a business uses in handling its financial information. SOURCE: CM:007 SOURCE: Monczka, R.M., Handfield, R.B., Giunipero, L.C., & Patterson, J.L. (2009). Purchasing and supply chain management (4th ed.) [p. 117]. South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 7, "question": "What does a channel of distribution usually need to be able to manage or avoid conflict within the channel? ", "choices": ["A. Limited competition ", "B. Updated technology ", "C. Equal authority", "D. Strong leadership"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Strong leadership. A channel of distribution that has strong leadership is often able to manage or avoid conflict because the leadership has the power to assign specific responsibilities to each channel member. Strong leadership has the authority to set goals for the entire channel and demand cooperation, which reduces the possibility of conflict. When a channel has strong leadership, channel members work for the good of the channel rather than for their individual goals. A channel of distribution does not need updated technology or limited competition to manage or avoid conflict within the channel. Equal authority might create conflict because there is no clear leader who has power and control over the channel. SOURCE: CM:008 SOURCE: Boone, L.E., & Kurtz, D.L. (2004). Contemporary marketing (11th ed.) [pp. 444-445]. Mason, OH: Thomson/South-Western. "}, {"number": 8, "question": "One of the characteristics of effective verbal communication is ", "choices": ["A. precise speech. ", "B. lack of clarity. ", "C. lack of tact.", "D. good use of slang."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Precise speech. Precise speech involves choosing the words that most accurately communicate what you want to say. This makes your communication effective because it has clarity, and the listener will be most likely to receive the message you want to transmit. Effective verbal communication should also be tactful and should not include slang. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Cheesebro, T., O'Connor, L., & Rios, F. (2007). Communication skills: Preparing for career success (3rd ed.) [pp. 76-77]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Before DiAnn presents her new idea to her boss, she searches the Internet and jots down two statistics that reinforce the idea. This is an example of ", "choices": ["A. giving alternative ideas. ", "B. obtaining primary information. ", "C. supporting ideas with research.", "D. clarifying a new idea."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Supporting ideas with research. Ideas that are research-based are more easily accepted than those that are not. Primary information is new information collected for the issue at hand. DiAnn is collecting secondary information, which involves obtaining information that has already been collected by others. The research does not create alternative ideas. It is meant to add validation to the original idea. Clarifying an idea involves explaining it in more detail. SOURCE: CO:061 SOURCE: Leitch, M. (2006, February 15). Giving ideas. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://www.internalcontrolsdesign.co.uk/advice/index.html#all "}, {"number": 10, "question": "What should you do if you phone an important customer and the customer indicates that you have called at a bad time? ", "choices": ["A. Offer to schedule a second call. ", "B. Try to continue the conversation. ", "C. Ask the customer to call you back.", "D. Explain that the call will be short."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Offer to schedule a second call. In some situations, you will call an important customer at a time when the customer is busy or in a hurry and is unable to speak to you. Then, it is appropriate to offer to schedule a second call at a time that will be convenient for the customer. You should not try to continue the conversation or explain that the call will be short if the customer indicates that this is a bad time. It is your responsibility to return the call rather than ask the customer to call you. SOURCE: CO:114 SOURCE: Hyden, J.S., Jordan, A.K., Steinauer, M.H., & Jones, M.J. (2006). Communicating for success (3rd ed.) [p. 45]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 12 "}, {"number": 11, "question": "When businesses need to formalize the information provided to employees, customers, or other businesses, they often use __________ communication. ", "choices": ["A. verbal ", "B. lateral ", "C. upward", "D. written"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Written. Written communication involves putting ideas, thoughts, and agreements into words and writing those words in a document or letter. Written communication is often considered to be formal because a copy of the information exists which indicates that all parties involved received the same message. Businesses often use formal written communication in order to document important transactions and preserve the information for future reference. Verbal communication involves speaking. Lateral communication is between people on the same level. Upward communication is from employees to supervisors or managers. SOURCE: CO:016 SOURCE: Hyden, J.S., Jordan, A.K., Steinauer, M.H., & Jones, M.J. (2006). Communicating for success (3rd ed.) [pp. 282-303]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western. "}, {"number": 12, "question": "When writing e-mail correspondence to customers and coworkers, it is important to remember that the messages ", "choices": ["A. should include graphics to hold the reader's interest.", "B. should be written in an entertaining, informal way.", "C. are often seen by people other than the recipients.", "D. are usually deleted as soon as they are read."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Are often seen by people other than the recipients. When writing e-mail messages to customers and coworkers, the correspondence should address various business issues; therefore, writers should develop the messages using a concise, friendly, and businesslike tone. If the writer uses language that is very casual, personal, or questionable, there is a risk of offending the recipient or others to whom the recipient forwards the message. Because many businesses have e-mail policies and can monitor the contents of e-mail messages going into and out of their companies, e-mail writers should take care not to send inappropriate messages. Business e-mail messages do not need to be entertaining or informal, nor do they need to include graphics. Many businesspeople save important e-mail messages and flag them for follow-up at a later time. SOURCE: CO:090 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [pp. 183-186]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 13, "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a persuasive sales message: ", "choices": ["A. Contains loaded language ", "B. Reminds customer of the product ", "C. Discredits the competition", "D. Makes the product appealing"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Makes the product appealing. Persuasive messages usually are intended to encourage someone to do something. In the case of a sales message, the goal usually is to persuade a customer to buy a product. In order to do this, the message should make the product appealing to the customer so the customer will understand the benefit of buying and want to buy. The sales message should persuade the customer to spend money. Persuasive sales messages are not intended to simply remind the customer of the product or discredit the competition. Persuasive messages should not use loaded language, which is often biased and stereotypical. SOURCE: CO:031 SOURCE: Lehman, C. & DuFrene, D. (2005). Business communication (14th ed.) [pp. 290-291]. Mason, OH: South-Western. "}, {"number": 14, "question": "When Brian got a new job, he made sure he knew how to use the cash register, became familiar with all the products and prices, and kept his work station very organized. In which way did Brian demonstrate the customer-service mindset? ", "choices": ["A. Following-up ", "B. Following-through ", "C. Being efficient", "D. Being accurate"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Being efficient. Being efficient demonstrates the customer-service mindset. Specifically, this means knowing how to operate equipment and software, becoming familiar with all the products the business offers, and keeping work spaces organized for action. Being accurate is demonstrated through doublechecking work for accuracy. Following-through means always doing what you say you're going to do. Following-up with customers suggests to customers that you care about their continued satisfaction. SOURCE: CR:004 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2010). Marketing dynamics: Teacher's edition (2nd ed.) [pp. 622-623]. Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company, Inc. "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Which of the following is the best way to handle slow/methodical customers: ", "choices": ["A. Let them have their say. ", "B. Don't jump to quick conclusions. ", "C. Help them along by not overwhelming them.", "D. Serve them nonemotionally."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Help them along by not overwhelming them. Helping them along by not overwhelming them is the best way to deal with slow/methodical customers. Be patient. Mirror their methodical behavior. They will come around when they trust your good intentions. Avoiding jumping to quick conclusions is the best way to deal with dishonest customers. Letting them have their say is the best way to deal with domineering/superior customers. Serving non-emotionally is the best way to deal with insulting customers. SOURCE: CR:009 SOURCE: CR LAP 3\u2014Making Mad Glad (Handling Difficult Customers) Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 13 "}, {"number": 16, "question": "What is the most important economic resource? ", "choices": ["A. Equipment ", "B. Minerals ", "C. Energy", "D. People"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "People. Human resources, people, are the most important economic resource because they combine the other resources to produce goods and services. Without the work of people, land would not be used to grow crops, roads would not be built, and equipment would not be used to manufacture goods. Minerals and energy are natural resources. Equipment is capital goods. SOURCE: EC:003 SOURCE: EC LAP 14\u2014Be Resourceful (Economic Resources) "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Which of the following is a reason that natural resources are considered limited: ", "choices": ["A. Some countries are unable to manufacture them.", "B. Technology has advanced faster than training.", "C. The earth has certain boundaries.", "D. People lack training or skills needed to do a job."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "The earth has certain boundaries. Currently, the earth provides most of our natural resources. As the population of the world increases, there will be more and more people living within those boundaries and demanding more resources. Therefore, there will be fewer resources per person. Lack of training and technology advancing faster than training are reasons for limited human resources. Natural resources are found in nature, rather than being manufactured. SOURCE: EC:001 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2006). Marketing dynamics (pp. 32-33). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. "}, {"number": 18, "question": "One of the advantages of a market economy is ", "choices": ["A. freedom of competition. ", "B. absence of taxes. ", "C. government control.", "D. assigned occupations."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Freedom of competition. In a market economy, businesses are free to compete with each other for labor and for customers. The government taxes the profits made by businesses and the money earned by workers in order to provide services to the people. The role of the government in our economy is limited to protecting private property, ensuring competition, and preserving law and order. Workers are free to choose the type of work they want and are limited only by their own abilities and finances. SOURCE: EC:009 SOURCE: EC LAP 15\u2014People Power (Private Enterprise) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of labor specialization: ", "choices": ["A. Increased worker efficiency ", "B. Increased interdependency ", "C. Increased production rates", "D. Simplified training of workers"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Increased interdependency. Increased interdependency means workers need to rely on each other. It is a disadvantage of specialization. All of the other alternatives are advantages of specialization. Production rates increase because the speed with which workers perform their specific tasks increases. Workers become highly skilled as job tasks are performed repeatedly, and this results in increased efficiency. Training of workers is simplified due to the limited nature of the tasks to be performed. SOURCE: EC:014 SOURCE: Murray, J.L. (n.d.). Three types of interdependence in an organizational structure. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/three-types-interdependenceorganizational-structure-1764.html "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Why is the concept of price stability an effective measurement of the state of the economy? ", "choices": ["A. Matches the effects with the causes ", "B. Reflects the rise in wages and benefits ", "C. Indicates positive and negative trends", "D. Compares revenues with expenses"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Indicates positive and negative trends. Price stability means that price levels remain fairly constant. When prices are stable, they do not drastically fluctuate up or down. Price stability is one way to measure the condition of a country's economy. If prices are stable (a positive trend), the economy is also stable. Large upswings or downswings in prices (negative trend) indicate that the economy is not stable. When the trend is negative, governments take steps to correct the problem. The concept of price stability does not reflect the rise in wages and benefits, does not match the effects with the causes, and does not compare revenues with expenses. SOURCE: EC:083 SOURCE: McConnell, C.R., & Brue, S.L. (2005). Economics: Principles, problems, and policies (16th ed.) [pp. 8-9]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of the peak phase of a business cycle: ", "choices": ["A. High prices ", "B. High dividends ", "C. High unemployment", "D. High interest rates"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "High unemployment. The peak phase of a business cycle is considered the high point of economic activity. It is characterized by high dividends, high production, high prices, high interest rates, and high employment. High unemployment is characteristic of the trough phase of a business cycle. SOURCE: EC:018 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 64-67). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Which of the following characteristics describes a person who always arrives at work on time: ", "choices": ["A. Dependable ", "B. Creative ", "C. Honest", "D. Independent"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Dependable. A dependable person is one who can be relied upon to do what s/he is supposed to do. Dependable employees comply with such rules as coming to work at a certain time every day. An independent person is self-reliant and likes to be in charge of his/her own life. A creative person is imaginative and able to come up with original ideas. An honest person tells the truth and behaves in a straightforward manner. SOURCE: EI:018 SOURCE: EI LAP 9\u2014You've Got Personality (Personality Traits in Business) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "A responsible employee who realizes that s/he has given a fellow employee the wrong answer to a work question would handle the situation by ", "choices": ["A. apologizing and giving the right answer. ", "B. letting the other employee figure it out. ", "C. pretending that s/he gave the right answer.", "D. refusing to answer questions in the future."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Apologizing and giving the right answer. A responsible person acknowledges his/her mistakes as soon as s/he is aware of them and then corrects them whenever possible. Since an incorrect answer may have caused a problem for the other employee, an apology is also in order. Letting the other employee figure out that the answer was incorrect, pretending that the right answer was given, and refusing to answer questions in the future are examples of irresponsible behavior. SOURCE: EI:021 SOURCE: EI LAP 21\u2014Make the Honor Role (Acting Responsibly) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "One way that businesses can protect the privacy of their customers is to limit the number of employees who have access to the customers' ", "choices": ["A. purchasing history. ", "B. personal information. ", "C. identification code.", "D. telephone numbers."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Personal information. Many businesses gather personal information about their customers that they store in a database. This might include information about a customer's credit rating, financial status, education, etc. Such information should be available only to employees who need to know it in order to do their jobs. Businesses should limit the number of employees who have access to customers' personal information in order to protect the privacy of their customers and prevent unauthorized persons from obtaining and using this information. A customer's telephone number, purchasing history, and identification code are types of routine business information that usually are not considered to be private. SOURCE: EI:029 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 172]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 25, "question": "When you ask coworkers for help and they aren't able to help you, which of the following responses would be most appropriate: ", "choices": ["A. \"I guess you don't remember when I helped you.\"", "B. \"I don't know how I'll ever get done.\"", "C. \"Thanks anyway; I won't bother you again.\"", "D. \"Thanks anyway; maybe another time.\""], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "\"Thanks anyway; maybe another time.\" This is an appropriate response because it expresses your thanks for their response and lets them know you understand and will ask them again. Reminding coworkers that you had helped them earlier is attempting to make them feel guilty, which they will probably resent. Saying that you won't bother them again indicates you are offended by their refusal. Saying you don't know how you'll get done (without help) is whining, which is a very negative habit that annoys other people. SOURCE: EI:008 SOURCE: EI LAP 18\u2014Assert Yourself (Assertiveness) "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of good visions: ", "choices": ["A. Concrete situations ", "B. Permanent results ", "C. Complicated ideas", "D. Expensive processes"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Permanent results. Good visions have permanent results. They are something that other people can carry on for many years even if the person who had the vision is not around. Examples include the right to vote, equal rights, and vaccines for diseases. Visions are abstract rather than concrete. Visions should be simple enough that anyone can understand rather than overly complicated. Some visions are expensive to turn into reality but are worth the price; however, some visions may not justify the price. SOURCE: EI:063 SOURCE: QS LAP 11\u2014Picture This! "}, {"number": 27, "question": "Achievement-oriented people rely on __________ to set the standards for their work. ", "choices": ["A. their bosses ", "B. their followers ", "C. their coworkers", "D. themselves"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Themselves. Achievement-oriented people rely on themselves to set the standards for their work. They don't allow others to set the standards for them. SOURCE: EI:027 SOURCE: EI LAP 10\u2014High Hopes (Developing an Achievement Orientation) Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 28, "question": "A business manager who wants to lead change in the company needs to be ", "choices": ["A. forceful. ", "B. emotional. ", "C. persuasive.", "D. conservative."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Persuasive. Business managers who want to lead change in the company need to have certain characteristics to be effective. They should be persuasive which means they have the ability to get people to see things their way, do things their way, or agree with them. Change doesn't just happen on its own. Change leaders need the involvement and help of many different people. Effective change leaders are able to persuade the right people to go along with them and help make the change happen. A manager who wants to lead change does not need to be emotional, forceful, or conservative. SOURCE: EI:005 SOURCE: QS LAP 23\u201420/20 Foresight "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Pedro received a check in the amount of $432.87 from the Tabor Corporation, a company in which he is a stockholder. This source of income is referred to as ", "choices": ["A. inheritance. ", "B. wages. ", "C. interest.", "D. dividends."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Dividends. Individuals and businesses acquire income in many ways. Dividends are earnings that are paid to investors or stockholders for their investments. When Pedro purchased shares of Tabor stock, he became an owner of the company. As an owner of the company, Pedro has the opportunity to earn a percentage of the company's profits, which are paid to him in the form of dividends. Wages are the income that workers earn for the work that they perform. Interest is the reward or cost of lending or borrowing money, usually figured as a percentage of the amount borrowed. An inheritance is the assets (e.g., property, goods, money) that a person leaves to others upon his/her death. SOURCE: FI:061 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., & Hughes, R.J. (2009). Personal finance (9th ed.) [pp. 447-448]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Choosing to buy an item at the check-out counter is often an example of ", "choices": ["A. financial self-control. ", "B. poor use of credit. ", "C. impulsive spending.", "D. smart shopping."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Impulsive spending. Choosing to buy an item at the check-out counter is a classic example of impulsive spending. Poor use of credit may or may not be involved. Choosing not to buy the item would illustrate financial control and would be a good example of smart shopping. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up "}, {"number": 31, "question": "Investors take a risk for the potential of receiving which of the following: ", "choices": ["A. Return ", "B. Prize ", "C. Recognition", "D. Bonus"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Return. Investors are willing to take a risk for the potential of return (reward or benefit they might receive). The return is what the investment can potentially earn for the investor. Prizes are awarded to players in sweepstakes contests. Bonuses are added to employees' paychecks. And, recognition is positive attention for extraordinary achievements. Prizes, bonuses, and recognition do not provide the motivation for investing. SOURCE: FI:077 SOURCE: QS LAP 32\u2014Risky Business? "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Electrical storms, floods, and earthquakes are examples of __________ risk. ", "choices": ["A. human ", "B. marketing ", "C. natural", "D. economic"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Natural. Natural risks are chances of loss which result from natural causes. These are natural phenomena occurring outside anyone's control. Economic risks are chances of loss due to changes in the market that force a lowering of prices, change of products, or even failure of businesses. Human risks are chances of loss caused by human weakness and unpredictability. Marketing is not a classification of risk. SOURCE: FI:084 SOURCE: FI LAP 8\u2014Prepare for the Worst; Expect the Best (Nature of Risk Management) "}, {"number": 33, "question": "A summarization of the total income and expense of a business for a period of time is called ", "choices": ["A. the profit-and-loss statement. ", "B. gross profit. ", "C. cost of goods sold.", "D. balance sheet."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The profit-and-loss statement. This income statement reports total revenue and expenses for a specific period of time. A balance sheet identifies a business's assets, liabilities, and capital on a given date. The difference between total sales and cost of goods sold is the gross profit. The cost of goods sold is the purchase price of the goods that were sold. SOURCE: FI:094 SOURCE: FI LAP 4\u2014Watch Your Bottom Line (Income Statements) Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 34, "question": "When return on capital is positive, the company is ", "choices": ["A. low on cash. ", "B. losing value. ", "C. growing in value.", "D. paying out dividends."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Growing in value. When return on capital is positive, the company is growing in value. When return on capital is negative, the company is losing value. A high return on capital would not indicate that a company is low on cash. Businesses can have a high return on capital but not pay out dividends. SOURCE: FI:354 SOURCE: FI LAP 7\u2014Money Matters (Role of Finance) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "To make sure that their budgets are effective, what should businesses do with budget information? ", "choices": ["A. Send it to all stockholders ", "B. Provide it to all top managers ", "C. Post it on bulletin boards", "D. Communicate it to all employees"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Communicate it to all employees. To make sure their budgets are effective, businesses should communicate them to all employees. Even the best, most accurate budget is ineffective if no one sees it. Effective budgets are those that have been clearly communicated to all employees, so that each person in the company is aware of his/her effect on the company's profits. All employees should receive this information, not just top managers. Businesses usually send annual financial statements rather than budget information to their stockholders. Specific budget information usually is not posted on company bulletin boards. SOURCE: FI:106 SOURCE: FI LAP 3\u2014Money Tracks (Nature of Budgets) "}, {"number": 36, "question": "A human-resources manager is reviewing job applications for a marketing position to select which candidates to call for an interview. What process is the human-resources manager performing? ", "choices": ["A. Prospecting ", "B. On-boarding ", "C. Screening", "D. Negotiating"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Screening. In the human-resources function, screening involves \u201cweeding out\u201d the applicants that do not meet minimum requirements for the job or have not satisfactorily completed the application. On-boarding activities are human-resources tasks that must be performed when a new employee joins the company (e.g., orientation and paperwork). Prospecting is a sales activity that involves identifying any person or organization with the potential to buy a product. Negotiating is the process of influencing someone to take a certain course of action in order to achieve a desired outcome. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: HR LAP 35\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 37, "question": "The purpose of using a marketing-information management system to gather data on the activities and new products of other businesses is to ", "choices": ["A. compare warehouse procedures. ", "B. monitor the competition. ", "C. improve stock control.", "D. analyze promotional methods."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Monitor the competition. Information about competitors' activities is very important to a business. An important responsibility of a marketing-information management system is to gather and analyze such data as improvements planned for competitive products, new products that are being introduced, or the competition's market share. Comparing warehouse procedures, analyzing promotional methods, and improving stock control are other functions of a marketing-information management system not related to monitoring the competition. SOURCE: IM:001 SOURCE: IM LAP 2\u2014Get the Facts Straight (Marketing-Information Management) "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a business obtaining marketing information about consumers in a way that might be considered unethical: ", "choices": ["A. Offering a free product in exchange for personal data", "B. Conducting a random survey", "C. Sending questionnaires to a specific audience", "D. Developing a scientific experiment"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Offering a free product in exchange for personal data. Certain ways of obtaining marketing information may be considered unethical even though they are legal. An example is offering free products in exchange for personal data. Consumers may be persuaded to provide information that they normally would not provide simply because the offer is so tempting, or they need the product being offered. Furthermore, consumers have no guarantee that the business will keep the personal data confidential. In some cases, businesses try to obtain this information in order to sell it to others. Most businesses follow ethical procedures when obtaining marketing information about consumers. These procedures might include conducting a random survey, sending questionnaires to a specific audience, and developing a scientific experiment. SOURCE: IM:025 SOURCE: Aaker, D.A., Kumar, V., & Day, G.S. (2007). Marketing research (9th ed.) [pp. 20-23]. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley & Sons, Inc. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Secondary research is cost-effective for marketers because the data ", "choices": ["A. are incomplete. ", "B. are cheap to purchase. ", "C. are specific.", "D. already exist."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Already exist. Secondary research is cost-effective for marketers because the data already exist. The organization does not need to pay the costs of undertaking original research. Secondary data are not necessarily cheap to purchase, nor are they specific to the research project at hand. Secondary data may be incomplete; however, this is not a reason that secondary research is cost-effective. SOURCE: IM:281 SOURCE: IM LAP 15\u2014What's the Source? (Obtaining Marketing-Research Data) "}, {"number": 40, "question": "Managers should avoid marketing-research projects that ", "choices": ["A. make little financial sense. ", "B. might give unfavorable results. ", "C. take a long time to complete.", "D. involve new products."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Make little financial sense. Managers should avoid marketing-research projects that make little financial sense\u2014in other words, the costs of conducting the research don't outweigh the potential benefits. Even if a marketing-research project gives unfavorable results, managers can still use the information to make the best decisions and strategies for the company. It shouldn't make a difference if a marketing-research study takes a long time to complete or involves new products\u2014it can still be useful. SOURCE: IM:282 SOURCE: IM LAP 13\u2014What's the Problem? (Marketing-Research Problems) "}, {"number": 41, "question": "The results of exploratory research are often ", "choices": ["A. unusable. ", "B. specific. ", "C. quantitative.", "D. qualitative."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Qualitative. The results of exploratory research are often qualitative, or based on thoughts, opinions, or feelings. They are not necessarily specific. They are usually not quantitative, or measurable. They are usable for generating hypotheses or familiarizing marketers with the problem at hand. SOURCE: IM:284 SOURCE: IM LAP 14\u2014Better By Design (Marketing-Research Designs) "}, {"number": 42, "question": "Marketers draw samples from ", "choices": ["A. current and former employees. ", "B. media stories. ", "C. their target population.", "D. groups of university students."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Their target population. Marketers draw samples from their target population, or the specific group of individuals or units they are studying. The target population may or may not include media stories, current and former employees, or groups of university students. SOURCE: IM:285 SOURCE: IM LAP 16\u2014Take Your Pick (Nature of Sampling Plans) "}, {"number": 43, "question": "Marketing researchers would use the Likert rating scale when its questionnaire's statements are designed to measure the respondents' ", "choices": ["A. feelings and knowledge. ", "B. level of agreement. ", "C. specific beliefs.", "D. level of intuitiveness."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Level of agreement. The Likert scale measures the respondents' level of agreement with a statement. For example, a questionnaire might contain the statement, \u201cThe PTR Company consistently provides excellent customer service.\u201d The response options might include phrases such as strongly agree, agree, no opinion, disagree, and strongly disagree. The respondents select the option that corresponds to their feelings. Marketing researchers do not use the Likert scale to measure the respondents' knowledge, specific beliefs, or levels of intuitiveness. SOURCE: IM:286 SOURCE: Aaker, D.A., Kumar, V., & Day, G.S. (2007). Marketing research (9th ed.) [p. 297]. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley & Sons, Inc. "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Which of the following is a technique that businesses can use to monitor their competitors' activities: ", "choices": ["A. Reading annual reports ", "B. Analyzing economic factors ", "C. Studying regional data", "D. Reviewing buying motives"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Reading annual reports. Businesses often monitor their competitors' activities in order to make marketing decisions that will help them to stay competitive. Businesses can obtain valuable information by reading their competitors' annual reports that often list major customers and describe successful promotional activities. Annual reports also include information about profitability, sales volume, new product development, and expansion. Businesses can use this information to develop similar products or to expand their sales area. Economic factors involve the state of the local economy. Regional data include geographic and demographic information about the area. Buying motives are the reasons or benefits that cause people to make purchases to satisfy wants and needs. SOURCE: IM:184 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 742). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 45, "question": "What is an example of a marketing-research method that is used to collect primary data? ", "choices": ["A. Census data ", "B. Customer survey ", "C. Trade-journal article", "D. External reports"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Customer survey. Primary marketing research is information that a business obtains for a specific purpose. Businesses use many techniques to obtain primary data, such as observation, interviews, and surveys. Surveys contain questions about the information the business wants to obtain. For example, a business might distribute a survey to its customers when it wants to find out what the customers think of the business's goods and services. Census data, trade-journal articles, and external reports are forms of secondary research. SOURCE: IM:289 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 614-615). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 46, "question": "When should researchers ask potentially sensitive questions during an interview? ", "choices": ["A. Toward the end of the interview", "B. At the beginning of the interview to get them out of the way", "C. Throughout the interview", "D. At the mid-point of the interview to allow time for the researcher to build rapport"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Toward the end of the interview. By asking potentially sensitive questions toward the end of an interview, the researcher can avoid having the participant cut off the interview before important information can be collected. By asking the questions at the beginning, in the middle, or throughout the interview, the researcher risks prematurely ended interviews. SOURCE: IM:418 SOURCE: Agriculture and Consumer Protection. (n.d.). Chapter 4: Questionnaire design. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://www.fao.org/docrep/W3241E/w3241e05.htm "}, {"number": 47, "question": "One reason businesses often avoid using open-ended questions as a method of obtaining results from a marketing survey is because the results may be difficult to ", "choices": ["A. enter into a database. ", "B. store for future use. ", "C. code for evaluation.", "D. distribute to management."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Code for evaluation. Businesses assign codes to survey responses in an effort to use the information in a numerical mode. Open-ended questions are designed so that respondents react to questions in a manner that requires more than \"yes\" or \"no\" as an answer. Because possible responses are not controlled or limited, coding is often more difficult. If businesses are not able to assign codes to the responses, the survey results may be extremely difficult to evaluate. The results of surveys that contain open-ended questions are not difficult to store for future use, to enter into a database, or to distribute to management. SOURCE: IM:062 SOURCE: Aaker, D.A., Kumar, V., & Day, G.S. (2007). Marketing research (9th ed.) [p. 433]. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley & Sons, Inc. "}, {"number": 48, "question": "It is beneficial to a marketing researcher to use open-ended questions on a survey when ", "choices": ["A. maintaining structure is important. ", "B. the survey is long and technical. ", "C. conducting exploratory research.", "D. objectivity is an important factor."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Conducting exploratory research. Exploratory research is marketing research that collects information to help the business define its issue, situation, or concern and decide which direction to go in order to address it. Surveys that consist of open-ended questions require respondents to provide more than a \u201cyes\u201d or \u201cno\u201d answer. An open-ended question is a type of unstructured question that allows a respondent the opportunity to express opinions, state issues, and provide ideas. By obtaining this type of in-depth, qualitative information, the researcher may be able to define the problem and determine in which direction to proceed with the research. Long and technical surveys tend to overwhelm the respondents; so open-ended questions may not be answered fully, if at all. The use of open-ended questions yields subjective responses. SOURCE: IM:293 SOURCE: Churchill, G.A., Brown, T.J., & Suter, T.A. (2010). Basic marketing research (7th ed.) [pp. 81-82]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 49, "question": "One of the strengths of using internal sources to collect marketing research information is that the information ", "choices": ["A. pertains directly to the issue. ", "B. is available to outside users. ", "C. relates to industry problems.", "D. is organized by department."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Pertains directly to the issue. Internal information is information located inside the company. One of the strengths of using internal information is that it often pertains directly to the issue. For example, if the issue is the popularity of a specific product, current sales and inventory data can provide information about how well that product is selling. Internal information often is not available to outside users. Although the information might relate to industry problems, that is not one of its strengths. Internal information may, or may not, be organized by department. SOURCE: IM:428 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2006). Marketing essentials (pp. 612-614). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 50, "question": "Which of the following is a measure of how happy a customer is: ", "choices": ["A. Customer attitude ", "B. Customer behavior ", "C. Customer satisfaction", "D. Customer loyalty"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Customer satisfaction. Customer satisfaction is a measure of how well your business or product meets or exceeds customer expectations; in other words, how happy is the customer? It may be one type of customer attitude. Customer loyalty is a customer's preference for a business; in other words, how often does the customer purchase the business's goods or services? It is observed in customers' behavior. SOURCE: MK:019 SOURCE: MK LAP 3\u2014Just Do It\u2026Right (Company Actions and Results) "}, {"number": 51, "question": "Changes that occur in the marketplace may cause an established business to __________ its marketing strategies. ", "choices": ["A. implement ", "B. identify ", "C. redesign", "D. publicize"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Redesign. Marketing strategies are influenced by many factors not within the direct control of the business. These include the actions of competitors, the influences of governmental agencies, and changes in consumer attitudes. When any of these factors change, the business may need to change, or redesign, its marketing strategies in order to continue to meet company goals. The strategies should already have been identified and implemented in an established business. The business may publicize its goals or its achievements but would probably not publicize the strategies used to achieve those ends. SOURCE: MP:001 SOURCE: MP LAP 2\u2014Pick the Mix (Nature of Marketing Strategies) "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Which of the following is an example of market segmentation on the basis of product usage: ", "choices": ["A. What a person's heritage is ", "B. How often a person attends the opera ", "C. What activities a person enjoys", "D. How old a person is"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "How often a person attends the opera. This example is determining the frequency with which a product is being used. It is the only example of product usage. A person's heritage and age are demographic characteristics. The activities in which a person participates is an example of psychographic segmentation. SOURCE: MP:003 SOURCE: MP LAP 3\u2014Have We Met? (Market Identification) "}, {"number": 53, "question": "Why is it important for a business to conduct a situational analysis during the marketing planning process? ", "choices": ["A. To identify customers ", "B. To ward off problems ", "C. To forecast expenses", "D. To redesign products"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "To ward off problems. Businesses conduct situational analyses to obtain information about changes or trends that are beginning to develop in the environment or marketplace. This procedure allows businesses to identify changes at an early stage and ward off potential problems. It is important for businesses to understand changes in their external environment in order to adapt and avoid problems. Without this information, businesses may be unprepared to deal with problems that might cause them to lose their competitiveness or even fail. A business would not conduct a situational analysis to identify customers, forecast expenses, or redesign products. However, a business might redesign products after conducting a situational analysis and finding that they were losing their appeal in the marketplace. SOURCE: MP:008 SOURCE: Etzel, M.J., Walker, B.J., & Stanton, W.J. (2007). Marketing (14th ed.) [p. 564]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin "}, {"number": 54, "question": "One way for businesses to obtain needed information efficiently is to ", "choices": ["A. read a book. ", "B. schedule an interview. ", "C. access a database.", "D. contact a competitor."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Access a database. A database is computerized storage for information and facts. Most businesses maintain a database of information that is relevant to the business, such as lists of customers and vendors, inventory levels, prices of materials, etc. When businesses need information, they access the database to obtain the data efficiently. For example, a business could access a database to find out how many customers in a certain area purchased a specific product during a specified time period. Scheduling an interview, reading a book, and contacting a competitor are not ways for businesses to obtain needed information efficiently. SOURCE: NF:078 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., Thill, J.V., & Mescon, M.H. (2007). Excellence in business (3rd ed.) [pp. 134-135]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 55, "question": "When developing a computer-based presentation, it is important that each slide contain ", "choices": ["A. numerical data. ", "B. colorful graphics. ", "C. key points.", "D. creative transitions."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Key points. Employees use presentation software to develop computer-operated visual aids that support an oral presentation. Slides for the presentation should include key points that highlight or reinforce the most important information, which may or may not include numerical data. Colorful graphics and creative transitions often make a presentation more interesting, but they are not necessary elements for each slide. SOURCE: NF:008 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 537]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 56, "question": "What must businesses determine during the phases of record keeping? ", "choices": ["A. Which clients will be excluded from the records", "B. Why employees dislike record keeping", "C. Where competitors keep their records", "D. Who will be responsible for record keeping"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Who will be responsible for record keeping. The phases of record keeping include getting started, implementing the process, and monitoring/adjusting the process. At the \"how to keep them\" point (in the \"getting started\" phase of record keeping), the business must set policies and practices, deciding whether or not the records should be kept digitally and who should be responsible for creating, maintaining, and destroying the records. Where competitors keep their records is not an issue in a firm's own record keeping. Employees may or may not dislike record keeping. No client should be excluded from the records. SOURCE: NF:001 SOURCE: NF LAP 1\u2014Record It (Business Records) "}, {"number": 57, "question": "Which of the following is an ongoing population trend that affects how businesses market their goods and services: ", "choices": ["A. Lifestyle ", "B. Consumption ", "C. Behavior", "D. Migration"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Migration. Migration is a population trend that indicates movement of people throughout the country as well as into and out of the country. Migration trends are important to businesses because businesses need to know where their customers are located. For example, many people are leaving colder climates and migrating to what is considered the Sunbelt. This movement affects businesses because the types of products they sell and the way they sell them will change. Also, the increased migration of ethnic groups into the country creates a need for new goods and services that meet the needs of a multicultural population. Lifestyle, consumption, and behavior are not population trends; however, these factors also affect how businesses market their goods and services. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: OECD. (2004, January 21). Trends in international migration reflect increasing labour-related immigration and persistent integration problems. Retrieved August 13, 2009, from http://www.oecd.org/document/50/0,2340,en_2649_201185_24968882_1_1_1_1,00.html "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Companies obtain internal information about their various business activities to operate effectively by monitoring ", "choices": ["A. industry trends. ", "B. trade publications. ", "C. internal records.", "D. government statistics."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Internal records. Companies keep many types of internal records about their various business activities. These records might contain information about sales, agreements with vendors, financial status, etc. Management and employees use the records to make decisions about day-to-day and future actions. For example, records that indicate that sales are increasing and the company is profitable might encourage the business to decide to expand. Businesses monitor their activities on an internal basis. Trade publications, industry trends, and government statistics are examples of external data. SOURCE: NF:014 SOURCE: Burrow, J.L. (2006). Marketing (2nd ed.) [pp. 120-121]. Mason, OH: South-Western. "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about the term \u201cenvironment\u201d: ", "choices": ["A. It has no affect on your performance. ", "B. It refers only to the earth and its resources. ", "C. It consists of your surroundings.", "D. It applies to individuals, not businesses."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "It consists of your surroundings. The term \"environment\" refers to your surroundings. This could mean anything\u2014your living room, a classroom, the mall, etc. Although the term is often used to refer to the earth and its resources, its true meaning is much broader. Your environment has an effect on your performance and your decisions. Businesses exist within environments just as individuals do. SOURCE: NF:015 SOURCE: NF LAP 2\u2014Get the 411 (Environmental Scanning) Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Which of the following is an ethical issue that might affect the operations function: ", "choices": ["A. Flexibility ", "B. Utility ", "C. Creativity", "D. Quality"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Quality. Quality is the degree of excellence of a good or service\u2014how good it is. Quality is an ethical issue that might affect the operations function because businesses decide the quality of the products they provide. For example, a business might decide to use low-quality materials to make products that are of low quality. Also, the business might decide to cut corners in the production process to save money. The result is low-quality products. However, it is unethical if the business does not make it clear to customers that the products are of low quality and may not be durable. Utility is usefulness. Creativity is the ability to generate unique ideas, approaches, and solutions. Flexibility is the ability to adapt to changes as they occur. SOURCE: OP:190 SOURCE: Pride, W.M., Hughes, R.J., & Kapoor, J.R. (2008). Business (9th ed.) [pp. 293-295]. Boston: Houghton Mifflin. "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Determine whether the following statement is true or false: Accidents in the workplace cannot be prevented or reduced. ", "choices": ["A. False, employees can be trained in accident prevention.", "B. True, employees are always going to make mistakes.", "C. True, accidents result from human and mechanical error.", "D. False, accidents caused by malfunctions can be prevented."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "False, employees can be trained in accident prevention. While it is true that machines can't be prevented from malfunctioning and employees are always going to make mistakes, workers can be trained to use safe work habits, to report hazards and unsafe conditions, and to be ready to handle accidents that do occur. SOURCE: OP:009 SOURCE: Spears, M.C., & Gregoire, M.B. (2004). Foodservice organizations: A managerial and systems approach (5th ed.) [pp. 320-323]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Protecting company information and intangibles often involves following the rules established to control access to ", "choices": ["A. cash registers. ", "B. inventory methods. ", "C. computer systems.", "D. storage facilities."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Computer systems. Company information is a type of intangible property that most businesses want to protect. Today, most of this information is stored on internal computer networks or systems. As a result, businesses establish rules to control access to computer systems to protect confidential or sensitive company information from being stolen or destroyed. Employees are expected to follow the rules, such as regularly changing passwords or not opening suspicious e-mails, to help protect the information. Protecting company information and intangibles does not involve following the rules established to control access to inventory methods, cash registers, or storage facilities. The inventory kept in storage facilities and the money in cash registers are tangibles rather than intangibles. SOURCE: OP:153 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 722). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 63, "question": "Raw materials are transformed into finished goods in the __________ process. ", "choices": ["A. production ", "B. promotion ", "C. purchasing", "D. distribution"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Production. Production is the creation of goods or services from economic resources. Promotion communicates information about goods, services, images, and/or ideas to achieve a desired outcome. Purchasing involves the planning and procedures necessary to obtain products for use in the operation of a business. Distribution is responsible for moving, storing, locating, and/or transferring ownership of goods and services. SOURCE: OP:017 SOURCE: OP LAP 4\u2014Can You Make It? (Nature of Production) "}, {"number": 64, "question": "Many businesses have eliminated free services in order to ", "choices": ["A. increase customer satisfaction. ", "B. control inventory shrinkage. ", "C. be more competitive.", "D. reduce operating expenses."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Reduce operating expenses. Operating expenses, or overhead expenses, are the amounts of money a business pays out in order to produce and/or sell its goods and services. Since operating expenses include salaries and wages, as well as equipment, eliminating free services would reduce operating expenses. The business would save the costs of delivery vans/trucks, the expense of packing for delivery, and the wages paid to delivery personnel. This would not control inventory shrinkage which is caused by employee theft and shoplifting. It would be likely to decrease customer satisfaction and to make the business less competitive if its competitors do offer free delivery. SOURCE: OP:024 SOURCE: Etzel, M.J., Walker, B.J., & Stanton, W.J. (2007). Marketing (14th ed.) [pp. 325-330]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 65, "question": "The most important reason that a business's public restrooms should be thoroughly cleaned on a regular basis is to ", "choices": ["A. protect the health of customers/clients. ", "B. make the fixtures last longer. ", "C. make the restrooms attractive.", "D. give the business a good image."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Protect the health of customers/clients. Public restrooms are a breeding ground for fungi, bacteria, and germs that are harmful to people. Regular, thorough cleaning helps to keep these elements under control and to protect the health of all who use the restrooms. Keeping restrooms clean does make them look better, helps to preserve the fixtures, and may create a good image. However, none of these reasons is as important as sanitation. SOURCE: OP:032 SOURCE: CanadianCentre for Occupational Health & Safety. (2008, June 23). Workplace housekeeping\u2014Basic guide. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://www.ccohs.ca/oshanswers/hsprograms/house.html "}, {"number": 66, "question": "Before you can reach a goal, you must first __________ an appropriate one. ", "choices": ["A. select ", "B. complete ", "C. fulfill", "D. adjust"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Select. The first step in achieving goals is to choose one that is meaningful to you. You may want to start with a single goal or a set of goals. Before you can reach a goal, you must have a clear idea of your goal from the beginning in order to achieve it. To complete or to fulfill a goal is to achieve it. It is not necessary to adjust an appropriate goal. SOURCE: PD:018 SOURCE: PD LAP 16\u2014Go for the Goal (Goal Setting) "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Which of the following is a technique that you can use to become more creative: ", "choices": ["A. Goal manipulation ", "B. Strong cooperation ", "C. Forced association", "D. Idea implementation"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Forced association. Forcing associations means making a connection between two things where an obvious connection doesn't already exist. By forcing associations, you make yourself think differently, which results in more creativity. For example, making associations with the color yellow might result in developing connections with taxis, school buses, daisies, bumblebees, the sun, etc. Cooperation is working together toward a common goal. Implementation is carrying out an idea or activity. Manipulation involves controlling or managing people or circumstances. SOURCE: PD:012 SOURCE: Innovative Styles. (n.d.). Tools and techniques: Generating innovative solutions. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://innovationstyles.com/isinc/content/toolstechniques0.aspx "}, {"number": 68, "question": "One of the most effective methods of locating job leads is asking for tips from ", "choices": ["A. nonworkers. ", "B. retirees. ", "C. minors.", "D. friends."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Friends. Letting friends and acquaintances know that you are looking for a job is one of the most effective methods of locating job leads. These people often will be willing to pass on information about new openings, resignations, and retirements they learn about. Retirees, nonworkers, and minors usually are out of the mainstream of the employment scene and would not have information concerning job leads. SOURCE: PD:026 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 112-113). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Which of the following are the best references to list in a r\u00e9sum\u00e9: ", "choices": ["A. Family members ", "B. Former employers ", "C. Coworkers", "D. Classmates"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Former employers. The reference section of a r\u00e9sum\u00e9 should list two or three people who can provide information about you. The best references are former employers, because they can accurately describe your work habits, abilities, and attitudes towards the job. Prospective employers will want to contact these references to find out if you performed satisfactorily in former positions. Potential employers usually do not want to contact your classmates, family members, and coworkers because they are personal references who may be unable to provide unbiased information about you. SOURCE: PD:031 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed.) [pp. 49-50]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Membership in a local chamber of commerce is __________ for marketing businesses. ", "choices": ["A. unimportant ", "B. necessary ", "C. required", "D. voluntary"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Voluntary. A chamber of commerce is an organization that supports businesses and business growth in the community. It also helps local businesses resolve common problems. Membership is voluntary, not required or necessary. Member businesses often display their membership plaques because they feel it benefits them for customers to know they are part of the organization. SOURCE: PD:036 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 789-790). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 71, "question": "A business that refuses to raise the price of its goods and services that are in high demand in a certain part of the country because of a natural disaster is being ", "choices": ["A. politically correct. ", "B. economically unsound. ", "C. legally reasonable.", "D. socially responsible."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Socially responsible. Social responsibility is the duty of business to contribute to the well-being of society. Businesses are being socially responsible if they refuse to take advantage of unfortunate situations, such as damage caused by natural disasters, by raising the prices of goods and services that people need in order to rebuild. Businesses that focus on contributing to society usually build goodwill within the community and develop long-term relationships that are far more profitable than the quick money they earn by raising prices during a disaster. Therefore, refusing to raise prices is not economically unsound because the business will profit in the future from its responsible actions. Refusing to raise prices during a natural disaster is not a political or legal issue. SOURCE: PI:015 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 139-140). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 72, "question": "What technological advancement has allowed consumers to collect the most information for pricecomparison shopping? ", "choices": ["A. Internet ", "B. Newspaper ", "C. Catalog", "D. Telephone"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Internet. More than a new way to take orders and deliver merchandise, the Internet has proven valuable to consumers as a source of information and a new way to compare prices and products. The Internet provides customers with more information about more products in less time than they can obtain from making telephone calls or by reading the newspaper or a catalog. SOURCE: PI:016 SOURCE: Khurana, A. (n.d.). Advantages of e-commerce. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://ecommerce.about.com/od/eCommerce-Basics/tp/Advantages-Of-Ecommerce.htm "}, {"number": 73, "question": "Why is it necessary for a business to price its products very carefully? ", "choices": ["A. To create goodwill in the community ", "B. To get a fair share of the market ", "C. To track competitors' activities", "D. To attract employees to the business"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "To get a fair share of the market. Gaining market share is often an important pricing goal. Businesses may lower prices in order to attract new customers and increase their market share. This could create goodwill in the community, but that is not the purpose of the tactic. Price levels are not used to attract employees. Competitors' activities would be tracked before prices were set. SOURCE: PI:002 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong, G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [p. 285]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. "}, {"number": 74, "question": "Which of the following is the purpose of screening ideas for new products: ", "choices": ["A. To perform a thorough business analysis ", "B. To generate new ideas ", "C. To prepare market research", "D. To eliminate some ideas"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To eliminate some ideas. Screening ideas for new products is intended to eliminate obviously bad ideas and recognize the value of good ideas. It is a quick look at ideas to see if they have value, not a careful or thorough analysis. New ideas must already be generated before screening can occur. Market research would be done to determine if consumers will purchase the good or service. SOURCE: PM:001 SOURCE: PM LAP 17\u2014Rapping Up Products (Nature of Product/Service Management) "}, {"number": 75, "question": "What technological advancement has had the greatest impact on the travel, hospitality, recreation, and insurance industries? ", "choices": ["A. Fax machine ", "B. Internet ", "C. Electronic key card", "D. Interactive television"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Internet. The Internet allows businesses in the travel, hospitality, recreation, and insurance industries to bypass intermediaries (agents and brokers). Consumers can easily go directly to the service business to make the purchase. This enables the businesses to reach more customers and sell at any time of the day or night. Fax machines are widely used as a means of sending information quickly rather than as a selling tool. Key card entry systems are used mainly in the hospitality industry. Interactive television is not as widely used by consumers as the Internet. SOURCE: PM:039 SOURCE: Etzel, M.J., Walker, B.J., & Stanton, W.J. (2001). Marketing (12th ed.) [pp. 309-310]. New York: Irwin/McGraw-Hill. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 76, "question": "Businesses often identify product opportunities by conducting ", "choices": ["A. idea analysis. ", "B. trend research. ", "C. trial runs.", "D. production tests."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Trend research. Identifying product opportunities often involves research. One type of research is trend research to find out the general direction in which people or events are moving. For example, trend research might indicate that people want smaller cars or larger televisions. As a result of trend research, businesses are often able to identify product opportunities. Once the opportunity is identified, businesses usually analyze the idea. If the idea is feasible, businesses may conduct trial runs and production tests. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2006). Marketing dynamics (pp. 279-280). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox. "}, {"number": 77, "question": "What does the following statement illustrate: The shelf should be 12\" inches long and weigh 14 ounces. ", "choices": ["A. Standards ", "B. Grades ", "C. Warranties", "D. Testimonials"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Standards. Standards are statements that specify a product's size, contents, and/or quality. Grades are ratings that tell to what extent the standards are met. Warranties are promises made by the seller to the consumer that the seller will repair or replace a product that does not perform as expected. Testimonials are statements by an identified user of a product, proclaiming the benefits received from the use of the product. SOURCE: PM:019 SOURCE: PM LAP 8\u2014Raising the Bar (Grades and Standards) "}, {"number": 78, "question": "When a manufacturer provides a full warranty with a product, it is the manufacturer's responsibility to ", "choices": ["A. limit the time that an implied warranty is good.", "B. replace or repair a faulty product.", "C. repair only specific parts if they fail to function.", "D. refund the purchase price if the product is misused."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Replace or repair a faulty product. A warranty is a promise made by the seller to the consumer that the seller will repair or replace a product that does not perform as expected. A full warranty provides that if the product does not work properly, is defective, or does not live up to the warranty, it must be made good within a reasonable time. The company providing the warranty may not put time limits on any implied warranties the product may have. A limited warranty would only cover specific parts rather than the whole product. Most warranties state that improper use or handling of the product will void the warranty. SOURCE: PM:020 SOURCE: PM LAP 4\u2014Promises, Promises (Warranties and Guarantees) "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Which of the following is an example of product bundling: ", "choices": ["A. Garden shop discounting prices of seasonal merchandise", "B. Business selling computer, printer, and scanner as a unit", "C. Theme park charging admission and selling ride tickets", "D. Lumber company selling wood chips as small-animal bedding"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Business selling computer, printer, and scanner as a unit. Product bundling involves combining several products and offering them to customers as one product. Usually, the bundled products are offered for one, all-inclusive price. An example is a business selling a computer, a printer, and a scanner as a unit. In many cases, the bundle is less expensive than the cost of each item sold separately. Sometimes, the products can only be purchased as a unit and are not available separately. A lumber company selling wood chips as small-animal bedding is an example of selling by-products. A theme park charging admission and then selling ride tickets is an example of two-part pricing. A garden shop discounting prices of seasonal merchandise is an example of adjusting prices. SOURCE: PM:041 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong, G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [p. 356]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. "}, {"number": 80, "question": "A business that positions its products as the ones offering the best quality and service for the price might gain a ", "choices": ["A. geographic benefit. ", "B. promotional consideration. ", "C. competitive advantage.", "D. marketing incentive."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Competitive advantage. Businesses often gain a competitive advantage over competitors by offering customers a value or benefit that their competitors do not provide. If a business offers the best quality and service at a reasonable price, it has a competitive advantage over competitors that provide lower quality or higher prices. When businesses position themselves as providers of quality and service, customers often think of them in those terms and prefer to buy from those businesses. Businesses do not gain promotional consideration, geographic benefits, or marketing incentives by positioning products as the ones offering the best quality and service for the price. SOURCE: PM:042 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [pp. 220-224]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 81, "question": "Walt Disney has sold the rights to Mickey Mouse and other Walt Disney characters to a company that makes stuffed animals. This is an example of brand ", "choices": ["A. repositioning. ", "B. positioning. ", "C. extension.", "D. licensing."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Licensing. Licensing allows a brand name to be used by another company for a fee. Brand positioning attempts to create a certain image or impression of a brand as compared to competitive brands. Brand extension is the use of successful brands to launch new brands. Brand repositioning reevaluates and changes the brand in order to change the ways consumers see the brand. SOURCE: PM:021 SOURCE: PM LAP 6\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (Nature of Product Branding) "}, {"number": 82, "question": "Corporate branding provides a variety of products and product lines with a common ", "choices": ["A. strategy. ", "B. platform. ", "C. ranking.", "D. identity."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Identity. Corporate branding refers to the combined impressions, images, or experiences associated with a company or parent entity. A corporate brand may include a variety of products, but the name or corporate brand provides all products with a common identity. For example, PepsiCo is a corporate brand under which its Pepsi, Quaker Oats, Tropicana, Gatorade, and Frito Lay products are sold. Corporate brands do not necessarily provide a common platform, ranking, or strategy for products. SOURCE: PM:206 SOURCE: Dhruv, G., & Levy, M. (2008). Marketing (p. 284). New York: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 83, "question": "In promotional communication, the feedback that buyers (consumers) give to senders (businesses) is usually in the form of ", "choices": ["A. purchases. ", "B. complaints. ", "C. referrals.", "D. suggestions."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Purchases. Promotion is the communication of information about goods, services, images, and/or ideas to achieve a desired outcome. Businesses use promotion to inform buyers about goods and services in order to encourage them to buy. By purchasing the goods or services, buyers give feedback to senders. Buyers let the senders know that they received the promotional message and respond by making purchases. A complaint is a customer's expression of a dissatisfaction. A suggestion is a recommendation. Referrals are individuals or businesses to whom salespeople are recommended. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: PR LAP 2\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Promotion) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Which of the following newspaper ads would be considered promotional rather than institutional: ", "choices": ["A. A January white sale ", "B. A salute to public-service workers ", "C. A commitment to the United Fund", "D. A special program on public television"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "A January white sale. A January white sale is an example of product promotion that aims to persuade customers to buy a good or service. The alternatives are examples of institutional promotion that aim to create a certain image in the eyes of consumers; also known as corporate promotion. SOURCE: PR:002 SOURCE: PR LAP 4\u2014Know Your Options (Types of Promotion) "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a business using unethical promotion: ", "choices": ["A. Developing an advertising campaign about environmental issues", "B. Exaggerating a product's attributes in an advertisement", "C. Using several testimonials in a print advertisement", "D. Placing a product's price in an advertisement"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Exaggerating a product's attributes in an advertisement. When a business exaggerates a product's attributes or benefits, such as stating that a product is \u201cthe best\u201d or that it can \u201cwork miracles,\u201d the business is engaging in puffery. This practice is an unethical advertising practice because it is misleading and provides unproven information. Developing an advertising campaign about environmental issues, using testimonials in print advertising, and placing product pricing in an advertisement are ethical actions. SOURCE: PR:099 SOURCE: Arens, W.F. (2004). Contemporary advertising (9th ed.) [pp. 72-73]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 86, "question": "Which of the following is typically NOT a penalty imposed upon marketers who run false or deceptive advertisements: ", "choices": ["A. Incarceration ", "B. Cease and desist orders ", "C. Monetary fines", "D. Corrective advertising"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Incarceration. While the penalties upon marketers who run false or deceptive advertisements may be severe, these marketers are rarely criminally charged or sentenced to jail time. A cease and desist order requires marketers to stop running the offensive advertisements. If these same marketers run false or deceptive ads in the future, regulators may impose monetary fines on the marketers. If regulators determine that a company is running deceptive advertising, that company may be required to run corrective advertising. SOURCE: PR:101 SOURCE: Fawkner, E. (2012). Not just 6 lines, 65 characters. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://www.ahbbo.com/adsftc.html Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 87, "question": "What does a business's customers recommending the business to their friends exemplify? ", "choices": ["A. Providing a testimonial ", "B. Word-of-mouth communication ", "C. Verbal assertiveness", "D. One-on-one selling"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Word-of-mouth communication. This is promotion and publicity for a business provided by customers who tell others of their satisfaction with the business. Therefore, customers recommending the business to their friends is an example of word-of-mouth communication. In many cases, these recommendations lead to additional sales because people tend to believe their friends and take their advice. A testimonial is a statement by an identified user of a product proclaiming the benefits received from the use of the product. Verbal assertiveness is a confident attitude that involves the use of words. Recommending a business to friends is not an example of one-on-one selling. SOURCE: PR:247 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [pp. 662-666]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 88, "question": "In what communications channels are holding press conferences and giving interviews used? ", "choices": ["A. Corporate management ", "B. Public relations ", "C. Personal selling", "D. Target marketing"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Public relations. Public relations is a function of business designed to establish good relations between the business and the public. One way to establish good relations is to communicate with the public. Businesses often hold press conferences and give interviews to communicate information and pass on positive news about the business. Corporate management involves managing the business. Personal selling is the form of promotion that determines client needs and wants and responds through planned, personalized communication that influences purchase decisions and enhances future business opportunities. Target marketing is the identification and selection of markets for a business or for a product. SOURCE: PR:250 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [p. 652]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following parts of a print ad often creates an image that people come to associate with that business: ", "choices": ["A. Photograph ", "B. Illustration ", "C. Headline", "D. Logotype"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Logotype. The logotype is the name and/or symbol used by a business. Businesses believe that having a unique logotype creates an image that people will come to recognize and associate with that business. The logotype clearly identifies the product's brand or advertiser to consumers. An illustration is a photograph, drawing, painting, or graphic such as a chart, table, or graph. A headline is text set in large type and usually positioned at the top of an advertisement. A photograph is an illustration. SOURCE: PR:014 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 427-428). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 90, "question": "Which of the following is an activity that is performed by a business's public-relations department: ", "choices": ["A. Selecting media for print and broadcast advertisements", "B. Researching and developing product prototypes", "C. Developing job descriptions for employees", "D. Coordinating speaking engagements for employees"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Coordinating speaking engagements for employees. The public-relations department is a division of a business that is responsible for establishing good relations between the business and its publics. The various publics include the business's target market, its stakeholders, the local business community, its employees, and local residents. One activity that a public-relations department coordinates is speaking engagements for the business's employees. For example, a local civic group might ask the publicrelations department if a member of the business's executive-management staff could speak to the group about a particular issue that is affecting the community. The public-relations department would work with the appropriate employee to schedule the speaking engagement. The research and development department conducts product research and develops product prototypes. Developing job descriptions is a human-resources activity. The advertising department selects media for the business's advertising. SOURCE: PR:252 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [p. 657]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 91, "question": "One reason why it is important for businesses to use public-relations activities to reach external audiences is to ", "choices": ["A. pass on positive information. ", "B. sell useful products. ", "C. measure the community response.", "D. compile customer databases."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Pass on positive information. One of the main functions of a business's public-relations activities is to reach external audiences, those groups that are outside of the company. These groups include the local community, government officials, customers, suppliers, creditors, etc. The external audience has a significant impact on the business because customers buy products, government officials enact rules and regulations, and creditors loan money. If the business does not maintain good relations with the external audience by providing positive information, it may have difficulty operating or even fail. Public-relations activities are not intended to sell useful products, measure the community response, or compile customer databases. SOURCE: PR:253 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [p. 652]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 92, "question": "Which of the following components of a promotional plan addresses exactly how a business will achieve its goals: ", "choices": ["A. Situation analysis ", "B. Budget ", "C. Strategy", "D. Evaluation"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Strategy. A promotional plan is the framework for the promotional activities of a business. The promotional plan includes several components. The strategy component provides information as to exactly how the business will achieve its established goals. The budget component outlines the financial resources the business will need to carry out the promotional activities. The situation analysis is a determination about the company's current business situation and the direction in which the business is headed. A promotional plan's evaluation component provides information about how the business will determine if its promotional activities are successful. SOURCE: PR:073 SOURCE: Small Business Notes. (n.d.). Promotion plan. Retrieved October 23, 2012, from http://www.smallbusinessnotes.com/marketing-your-business/promotion-plan.html "}, {"number": 93, "question": "Which of the following is a promotional activity that should be coordinated with an advertised sales event: ", "choices": ["A. Product displays ", "B. Marketing research ", "C. Stock handling", "D. Merchandise markdowns"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Product displays. Product displays are the ways in which goods and services are visually presented to prospective buyers. Businesses often display products in windows, on racks and tables, etc. Businesses often discount products and promote (advertise) these discounts to attract customers and stimulate sales. To encourage customers to buy during the sales event, the business should display the advertised products in an attractive way because customers are usually more willing to buy when the products are organized in a visually appealing manner. Marketing research is the systematic gathering, recording, and analyzing of data about a specific issue, situation, or concern. Stock handling is the loading, unloading, and movement of goods. Marking down merchandise is a pricing activity rather than a promotional activity. SOURCE: PR:076 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2006). Marketing essentials (p. 367). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 94, "question": "What should salespeople be prepared to use, when appropriate, to communicate with customers? ", "choices": ["A. Complex sentences ", "B. Technical terms ", "C. Slang words", "D. Foreign phrases"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Technical terms. When appropriate, salespeople will need to use technical terms and to be prepared to explain those terms in plain English. Some goods and services require a technical explanation, and salespeople must be able to adequately communicate that information to customers. Salespeople must be able to explain technical terms in a clear and simple way that customers will understand. Salespeople should avoid using complex sentences, slang words, or foreign phrases. SOURCE: SE:017 SOURCE: SE LAP 117\u2014Sell Away (The Nature and Scope of Selling) "}, {"number": 95, "question": "Because product quality and price can easily be matched, customer service becomes a key component in business ", "choices": ["A. careers. ", "B. competition. ", "C. communications.", "D. forecasts."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Competition. Because product quality and price can easily be matched, customer service becomes a key component in business competition. In selling, customer service is where the real competition among businesses begins. As a salesperson, you must have the ability to show your prospects that your company meets (and hopefully exceeds) customer service expectations. Customer service is not a key component in business careers, business communication, or business forecasts. SOURCE: SE:076 SOURCE: SE LAP 130\u2014Go Beyond the Sale (Customer Service in Selling) Test 1076 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 96, "question": "Selling policies not only benefit the company by providing guidelines for sales activities, employee actions, and services provided, they also help managers to ", "choices": ["A. assess sales staff performance. ", "B. direct salespersons' responses. ", "C. assist in determining regulations.", "D. explain policies to potential customers."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Assess sales staff performance. By assessing sales staff performance, managers can determine the success of the employees and the selling policies. Salespeople interact with potential customers and explain policies. Regulations are determined by federal and state governments along with regulatory agencies. Salespersons' responses are directed by the established selling policies. SOURCE: SE:932 SOURCE: Levy, M., & Weitz, B. A. (2007). Retailing management (6th ed.) [pp. 251-252]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 97, "question": "What is one way that businesses use the technology of electronic data interchange in the selling function? ", "choices": ["A. To identify potential accounts ", "B. To fax sales data to employees ", "C. To communicate with customers", "D. To access competitors' web sites"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To communicate with customers. An electronic data interchange (EDI) is a computerized information system. This technology allows a business's computers to communicate with customers' computers and share information. An advantage of using EDI is that the computers keep track of sales and inventory and automatically place orders when inventory reaches a certain level. The system facilitates the sales process, which usually results in more satisfied customers and more sales for the business. Businesses do not use electronic data interchange systems to identify potential accounts, fax sales data to employees, or access competitors' web sites. SOURCE: SE:107 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 510). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Which of the following sources of information might provide salespeople with the most information about actual product performance: ", "choices": ["A. Sales displays ", "B. Merchandise labels and tags ", "C. Manufacturers' pamphlets", "D. Customers"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Customers. An excellent source of information about what a product can or cannot do is customers who have actually used the product. The other alternatives provide excellent information about other aspects of the product such as care, proper usage, construction, price, and size. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: Manning, G.L., Reece, B.L., & Ahearne, M. (2010). Selling today: Creating customer value (11th ed.) [p. 130]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 99, "question": "During the feature-benefit selling process, it is important for the salesperson to remember that the customers are buying ", "choices": ["A. benefits. ", "B. features. ", "C. attitudes.", "D. characteristics."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Benefits. Benefits are the advantages that the product provides. Effective salespeople know that customers do not buy the product itself; rather, they are buying what the product can do for them. For example, customers do not buy weight-lifting equipment\u2014they buy the ability to workout in the privacy of their own homes. Therefore, the salesperson must translate the features (characteristics) of the product into benefits. A customer does not purchase a product because of a person's attitude. SOURCE: SE:109 SOURCE: SE LAP 113\u2014Find Features, Boost Benefits (Feature-Benefit Selling) "}, {"number": 100, "question": "Why should managers know how to do the work of the workers they supervise? ", "choices": ["A. To coordinate employees' efforts ", "B. To establish a chain of command ", "C. To create a team spirit among employees", "D. To have realistic expectations for workers"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To have realistic expectations for workers. Even though managers don't do the actual jobs, it is important for managers to understand the jobs of the workers they supervise. This helps managers to know how workers should do the work, to be realistic in the amount of work they expect workers to complete, or even to fill in when workers are absent or there is an emergency situation of some kind. Managers do not need to know how to do the work to establish a chain of command. Coordinating employees' efforts and creating a team spirit are managerial responsibilities that improve the output of workers but are not related to managers' knowledge of the jobs to be done. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: SM LAP 3\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}], "1103-MKT": [{"number": 1, "question": "Brix Beauty Salon used a celebrity's name and photograph in a recent newspaper advertisement, even though the celebrity had not given Brix permission to use her name and likeness. What tort did Brix Beauty Salon commit? ", "choices": ["A. Defamation", "B. Wrongful interference", "C. Appropriation", "D. Conversion"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Appropriation. Torts are civil wrongdoings that cause harm or injury to another party. Appropriation, wrongful interference, defamation, and conversion are four kinds of torts. Appropriation, which Brix Beauty Salon committed, involves a business or person who uses\u2014without permission\u2014another person's name, likeness, and other unique characteristics for the benefit or gain of the user. Brix Beauty Salon used the celebrity's name and picture to attract customers to the salon. Unfortunately, Brix had not obtained permission to use the celebrity's name or likeness. As a result, the celebrity could sue Brix for appropriation. Wrongful interference consists of predatory behavior undertaken by a business to draw either customers or employees away from a competitor. Defamation involves making false, malicious statements about a person or organization. Conversion occurs when personal property is taken from the owner and given to someone else to use. SOURCE: BL:069 SOURCE: Miller, R.L., & Jentz, G.A. (2006). Business law today: Standard edition (7th ed.) [p. 107]. Mason, OH: Thomson Learning. "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Which of the following forms of ownership is a group of individuals organized by a charter that is granted by a state: ", "choices": ["A. Corporation", "B. Proprietorship", "C. Partnership", "D. Cooperative"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Corporation. A corporation acts as a \"legal person\" in doing business and is owned by stockholders who have purchased stock. A partnership is a form of business ownership in which the business is owned by two or more persons. A sole proprietorship is a form of business ownership in which the business is owned by one person. A cooperative is owned and operated by its user-owners to supply goods and services to its members. SOURCE: BL:003 SOURCE: BL LAP 1\u2014Own It Your Way (Business Ownership) "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Computer manufacturers sell their products through retailers, such as Best Buy. This is an example of the __________ function of marketing. ", "choices": ["A. promotion", "B. channel management", "C. pricing", "D. product/service management"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Channel management. Channel management involves understanding the concepts and processes needed to identify, select, monitor, and evaluate sales channels. This example entails the transfer of ownership of the computers from the manufacturer to the retailer. Promotion involves understanding the concepts and strategies needed to communicate information about goods, services, images, and/or ideas to achieve a desired outcome. Pricing is the marketing function that involves determining and adjusting prices to maximize return and meet customers' perceptions of value. Product/service management is the marketing function that involves obtaining, developing, maintaining, and improving a product or service mix in response to market opportunities. SOURCE: CM:001 SOURCE: CM LAP 2\u2014Chart Your Channels (Channel Management) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Indirect channels of distribution are the only channels that involve ", "choices": ["A. producers.", "B. industrial consumers.", "C. intermediaries.", "D. ultimate consumers."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Intermediaries. Intermediaries are also called middlemen and include sales agents, wholesalers, and retailers who perform specific functions in the movement of goods from producers to consumers. Direct channels of distribution do not involve intermediaries. All channels of distribution involve producers and either industrial or ultimate consumers. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: CM LAP 1\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Packaging a product in a biodegradable or recyclable container is one way a channel member can participate in the ethical practice of ", "choices": ["A. international marketing.", "B. consumer protection.", "C. social awareness.", "D. green marketing."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Green marketing. Green marketing refers to the practice of pricing, promoting, and distributing products in such a way that they do not harm the natural environment. Most manufacturers choose to participate in this practice because of their code of ethics. Consumer protection deals with safety features and product labeling standards that protect the consumer. Social awareness is a term used to describe the practice of enlightening the community of business actions to promote social welfare. International marketing refers to marketing goods and services in foreign countries. SOURCE: CM:006 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 148). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "One aspect of coordinating channel management with pricing activities involves ", "choices": ["A. implementing accounting policies.", "B. setting appropriate prices.", "C. earning high profits.", "D. developing product standards."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Setting appropriate prices. Businesses not only need to make their products available, but they also must sell them at a price that customers are willing to pay. If a product is not priced appropriately, customers usually will not buy even if the product is widely distributed. Therefore, it is important for businesses to coordinate the pricing activities with the appropriate channel members. Businesses must set appropriate prices that customers are willing to pay and have the products in stock when customers want them in order to successfully sell to customers. Coordinating the channel-management function with pricing does not involve implementing accounting policies, earning high profits, or developing product standards. SOURCE: CM:007 SOURCE: Lake, L. (n.d.). Developing your marketing mix. Retrieved July 25, 2014, from http://marketing.about.com/od/marketingplanandstrategy/a/marketingmix.htm "}, {"number": 7, "question": "Why is it important to identify sources that provide relevant, valid written material? ", "choices": ["A. To understand business communication", "B. To compile a database", "C. To read useful information", "D. To prepare a routine message"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To read useful information. Business employees often read written material to obtain useful information that they can use to apply to a specific task or problem. For the information to be useful, the sources must provide relevant, valid written material. For example, employees might read industry publications to identify trends so the business can take steps to remain competitive. Industry information is relevant and valid and useful to businesses. It is not important to identify sources that provide relevant, valid written material to compile a database, understand business communication, or prepare a routine message. SOURCE: CO:054 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. xliii, xlvii-xlix, 681-683). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Which of the following is a company resource that employees often analyze to ascertain policies and procedures: ", "choices": ["A. Research documents", "B. Sales reports", "C. Promotional brochures", "D. Training materials"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Training materials. Employees are often expected to read a variety of company resources in order to learn about and understand policies and procedures. Training materials are a type of resource that companies often make available to employees. By analyzing the materials, employees learn about company structure, business strategies, operating policies and procedures, etc. The more employees know and understand about the company, the better able they are to perform effectively and advance in the organization. Sales reports, promotional brochures, and research documents usually do not contain information about company policies and procedures. SOURCE: CO:057 SOURCE: Clark, B., & Commers, J. (2013). Entrepreneurship (pp. 400-401). Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co. "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Jacob was nervous about making his valedictorian speech, but when he stood up to walk to the podium, the audience cheered and gave him a standing ovation, which helped him relax and enjoy the moment. What was the audience doing? ", "choices": ["A. Exhibiting unprofessional behavior", "B. Mocking the speaker", "C. Encouraging the speaker", "D. Engaging in passive listening"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Encouraging the speaker. In many cultures, a standing ovation is the ultimate show of support for a speaker. It indicates the audience's respect for the speaker, and its desire to hear what the speaker has to say. Because cheering provides positive feedback, the audience was not mocking or insulting the speaker. Some cultures might view the audience's behavior as unruly or disrespectful; however, this situation involves a school event, rather than a business event, so the audience isn't exhibiting unprofessional behavior. Because Jacob has not started speaking, the audience is not actively listening to what he is saying. SOURCE: CO:082 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 101]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 10, "question": "A message which is as short and to the point as possible is referred to as ", "choices": ["A. complete.", "B. courteous.", "C. correct.", "D. concise."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Concise. Concise messages are clear and short. A courteous message addresses others with respect. Completeness in communication means giving all the information required. Carefully checking all facts and figures for accuracy before delivering a message should ensure correctness. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Hyden, J. S., Jordan, A. K., Steinauer, M. H., & Jones, M. J. (2006). Communicating for success (3rd ed.) [pp. 117-118]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western. Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Writing key points on notecards and then placing the cards in order of their importance is one way to ", "choices": ["A. organize information.", "B. access files.", "C. revise facts.", "D. verify accuracy."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Organize information. Organizing information helps you to communicate your message to your audience in a meaningful way. One way to organize information is to write down key points on notecards (index cards). Then, you can place the cards in their order of importance or categories. The advantage to using notecards to organize information is that you can move them around and reorganize as needed. When you have the information in the order that you want it in, you can efficiently write an outline, report, manual, or article, or prepare a presentation. Placing key points on notecards and placing the cards in a certain order will not help you access files, revise facts, or verify the information's accuracy. SOURCE: CO:086 SOURCE: eHow.com. (1999-2014). How to organize a research paper. Retrieved July 24, 2014, from http://www.ehow.com/how_138072_organize-research-paper.html "}, {"number": 12, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an effective subject line for a professional email: ", "choices": ["A. New product information", "B. Mtg. rescheduled for 3 p.m.", "C. One more thing . . .", "D. Can we talk for a minute?"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Mtg. rescheduled for 3 p.m. An effective subject line for a professional email should summarize the body of the message and make it easy for the recipient to understand the purpose of the email. \"Mtg. rescheduled for 3 p.m.\", for example, clearly communicates the focus of the email (the meeting) and provides enough information for the recipient to understand why the email was sent to him/her (to inform him/her that the new time for the meeting is 3 p.m.). \"New product information\" is not specific enough for the recipient to understand what product is the focus of the message. \"One more thing . . .\" and \"Can we talk for a minute?\" are vague and provide little information to help the recipient understand the reason for the email. SOURCE: CO:090 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 203). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 13, "question": "When writing informational messages, business employees should explain the situation and include sufficient data for the recipient to be able to ", "choices": ["A. make a decision.", "B. read the message.", "C. contact the business.", "D. agree with the content."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Make a decision. Informational messages are intended to inform and provide data to the recipients. In many cases, the purpose of an informational message is to help the recipient make a decision. For this to happen, the business employee should explain the situation and include sufficient data. If recipients clearly understand the who, what, where, when, why, and how of the situation, they usually have sufficient information to make a decision. Clear and concise writing enables a recipient to read the message. The letterhead usually includes the business's name, address, and phone number so recipients are able to contact the business. Explaining the situation and including sufficient data does not guarantee that the recipient will agree with the content. SOURCE: CO:039 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 430]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a simple written report that a business might prepare on a regular basis: ", "choices": ["A. Results of a research study", "B. Minutes of a staff meeting", "C. Findings of a major investigation", "D. Analysis of a publicity campaign"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Minutes of a staff meeting. Simple written reports are often intended to provide information to the business's employees. An example of a simple written report that a business might prepare on a regular basis is the minutes of a staff meeting. Businesses often have routine staff meetings and prepare a brief summary to distribute to all employees. This serves to remind employees of the topics discussed and provide that information to employees who may have been unable to attend. Results of a research study, findings of a major investigation, and analysis of a publicity campaign are examples of complex written reports. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 204-205). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Which is the most effective way for an employee to communicate interest in providing good service to customers? ", "choices": ["A. Informal product demonstration", "B. Body language", "C. Social status", "D. Closing statements"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Body language. Body language is gestures, facial expression, tone of voice, or any other form of communicating without words. An employee's body language conveys a message to customers. For example, if an employee is talking to one customer and ignores a new customer, the employee's body language is telling the new customer that s/he is not important. On the other hand, an employee who smiles or motions that s/he will be with the customer shortly is communicating an interest in providing good service. Employees usually do not communicate their social status to customers. The verbal and nonverbal communications employees use during the closing statements indicate their interest in being of service, not the closing statements themselves. Informal product demonstrations do not communicate interest in providing good service to customers. SOURCE: CR:005 SOURCE: Cheesebro, T., O'Connor, L., & Rios, F. (2007). Communication skills: Preparing for career success (3rd ed.) [pp. 46-47]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 16, "question": "A customer complains that an item purchased last week does not fit properly. The real reason for returning the item is that it is too expensive. This is an example of a __________ complaint. ", "choices": ["A. service", "B. sincere", "C. hidden", "D. business"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Hidden. Customers sometimes conceal the real complaint by stating another believable but secondary reason for their dissatisfaction. A sincere complaint is an honestly felt dissatisfaction. A service complaint results from poor service, and a business complaint is customer dissatisfaction with the business in general. SOURCE: CR:010 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 240-241). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Employees can reinforce their company's positive image by ", "choices": ["A. developing a broad product/service mix.", "B. delivering on the company's brand promise.", "C. sharing its intellectual property with competitors.", "D. advocating prestige pricing and price skimming."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Delivering on the company's brand promise. A brand promise is a business's agreement (spoken or unspoken) with customers that it will consistently meet their expectations and deliver on its brand characteristics and values. By delivering on their company's brand promise, employees can reinforce the company's positive image among customers. These employees become brand ambassadors, communicating the company's vision, mission, and brand through their actions and words, both on the job and off. Developing a broad product/service mix does not necessarily reinforce the company's positive image. Betraying a company by sharing its intellectual property with competitors does nothing to reinforce the company's positive image. Prestige pricing and price skimming do not reinforce a company's positive image in every case. SOURCE: CR:002 SOURCE: Lebard, P., Rendleman, K., & Dolan, K. (n.d.). Delivering the brand promise through employees. Retrieved July 25, 2014, from http://www.mmc.com/knowledgecenter/viewpoint/archive/lebard2006.php "}, {"number": 18, "question": "A local hardware store purchased a large shipment of snow shovels in November in order to prepare for winter weather. The hardware store is helping to create __________ utility. ", "choices": ["A. form", "B. place", "C. time", "D. possession"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Time. Time utility is created when products are available at the time they are needed or wanted by customers. Form utility is usefulness created by altering or changing the form or shape of a good to make it more useful to customers. Place utility is usefulness created by making sure that goods and services are available at the place where they are needed or wanted by customers. Possession utility is usefulness created when ownership of a product is transferred from the seller to the user. SOURCE: EC:004 SOURCE: EC LAP 13\u2014Use It (Economic Utility) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "A manufacturer wants to ensure that each product it makes meets certain standards so that customer complaints and product returns will be kept at minimal levels. Meeting this goal depends on the part of operations known as ", "choices": ["A. inventory management.", "B. strategic management.", "C. purchasing.", "D. quality control."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Quality control. Ensuring that products meet predetermined standards for excellence is known as quality control, and it is part of operations. Purchasing and inventory management are also part of operations, but purchasing refers to acquiring necessary goods and services, and inventory management means supervising inventory levels to make sure there is an appropriate balance. Strategic management refers to the business's plans and goals for the future. SOURCE: EC:071 SOURCE: EC LAP 19\u2014Strictly Business (Business Activities) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Which of the following factors has aided the most in creating a global business environment: ", "choices": ["A. Technology", "B. Government", "C. Cultural changes", "D. Exchange rates"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Technology. Technologies of all types have enabled global markets to function effectively. As examples, refrigeration has enabled perishable products to be transported between countries; and computers have facilitated communication and exchange of payments. Government, culture, and exchange rates have both facilitated and hampered global trade. SOURCE: EC:104 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., Burrow, J.L., & Kleindl, B. (2009). Intro to business (7th ed.) [pp. 60-61]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of private enterprise that enables consumers to buy quality products at fair prices: ", "choices": ["A. Unlimited resources", "B. Competition", "C. Inflation", "D. Profit motive"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Competition. Competition is the rivalry between two or more businesses to attract scarce (limited) customer dollars. In order to be competitive, businesses must try to offer consumers quality products at fair prices. The profit motive is the desire to make a profit, which moves people to invest in business. Inflation is a rapid rise in prices usually occurring when demand exceeds supply. Resources are limited in all economic systems. SOURCE: EC:009 SOURCE: EC LAP 15\u2014People Power (The Private Enterprise System) "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a tax that government collects from some businesses: ", "choices": ["A. Subsidy", "B. Excise", "C. Bond", "D. Discount"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Excise. Excise is a special government tax on certain items, such as gasoline. Government collects several kinds of taxes from businesses. Businesses are responsible for collecting income and social insurance taxes from employees and sales, excise, and duty taxes from customers. Businesses pay tax on their income and property, and they also pay fees for licenses and permits. Subsidy is government financial help given to a business. Bonds are interest-bearing certificates issued by government that promise to pay bond owners a certain sum at a specified time. Discount is the amount by which the price of something is reduced. SOURCE: EC:008 SOURCE: EC LAP 16\u2014Regulate and Protect (Government and Business) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Shelly is a union member who has been having problems with management. Shelly should report her problems to her union's ", "choices": ["A. mediator.", "B. president.", "C. steward.", "D. arbitrator."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Steward. Union stewards are called shop stewards, and they are union members elected by their peers to handle any grievances or problems members might have with management. A union president's responsibilities involve leading the union as a whole rather than assisting individuals. A mediator is involved in union negotiations, clarifying issues, and making suggestions concerning the contract. An arbitrator also assists with negotiations. In binding arbitration, this person's decisions regarding the contract are final and cannot be changed. SOURCE: EC:015 SOURCE: EC LAP 5\u2014Get United (Organized Labor) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of weak currency: ", "choices": ["A. It reduces business profits.", "B. It makes acquiring foreign companies more expensive.", "C. It negatively affects the balance of trade.", "D. It makes buying imports less expensive."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It makes acquiring foreign companies more expensive. One disadvantage of weak currency is making the acquisition of foreign companies more expensive since domestic currency doesn't go as far overseas. Reduction of business profits and a negative effect on the balance of trade are disadvantages of strong currency, not weak currency. Weak currency makes buying imports more expensive, not less expensive. SOURCE: EC:100 SOURCE: EC LAP 30\u2014Get Your Money's Worth (Exchange Rates) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "In some cultures, creating relationships during business negotiations is key; in other cultures, negotiators want a signed contract. This illustrates cultural differences in negotiating ", "choices": ["A. styles.", "B. attitudes.", "C. schedules.", "D. goals."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Goals. Different cultures have different goals when it comes to business negotiations. For some, only a signed contract will do. For others, creating relationships equals success. Different cultures also have different attitudes (win-win v. win-lose), schedules (open-ended v. time-sensitive), and styles (informal v. formal); however, achieving a contract v. achieving a relationship pertains to negotiation goals. SOURCE: EC:045 SOURCE: EC LAP 24\u2014On Top of the World (Impact of Culture on Global Trade) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Why is it sometimes difficult to be honest about strengths? ", "choices": ["A. No one likes to recognize strengths.", "B. We don't want to brag.", "C. Weaknesses are more significant than strengths.", "D. Few people have strengths."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "We don't want to brag. It's sometimes difficult to be honest about strengths. We don't want to seem as if we're bragging or \u201cstuck up.\u201d However, recognizing our talents, abilities, and the things we do well is a healthy and acceptable thing to do. Everyone has strengths. Weaknesses are not more significant than strengths. SOURCE: EI:002 SOURCE: EI LAP 17\u2014Assess for Success (Assessing Your Strengths and Weaknesses) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "As a sales representative for a large distributor, you hear a lot of information from your clients about the competition. Which of the following characteristics would help you to demonstrate initiative in this situation: ", "choices": ["A. Creativity and self-understanding", "B. Patience and resourcefulness", "C. Empathy and self-control", "D. Alertness and assertiveness"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Alertness and assertiveness. Alertness and assertiveness are two personal characteristics that are interdependent with initiative. A sales representative can show initiative by being alert to information about competitors and being assertive enough to express his/her views. Empathy is the ability to put yourself in another person's place. Resourcefulness helps you to make the best of any situation. Creativity is the ability to generate unique ideas, approaches, solutions, etc. Self-understanding is comprehending one's personal needs, interests, values, and motives and recognizing their effects on one's behavior. Patience is the ability to endure life's aggravations and difficulties calmly. SOURCE: EI:024 SOURCE: EI LAP 2\u2014Hustle! (Taking Initiative at Work) "}, {"number": 28, "question": "The night clerk in a local motel often complains to the manager about having to assist his/her coworkers. This is an example of an employee having a(n) __________ attitude. ", "choices": ["A. negative", "B. productive", "C. innovative", "D. indifferent"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Negative. People who have negative attitudes do not like to assist others. They are usually self-centered and focus only on their own needs. People who are productive and innovative are positive people. Indifferent people lack concern about or interest in things. SOURCE: EI:019 SOURCE: EI LAP 3\u2014Opt for Optimism (Positive Attitude) "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Instead of going through Jeff's files, Amanda waits until Jeff returns from lunch to obtain a file that she needs to review. This is an example of one coworker ________ of another coworker. ", "choices": ["A. respecting the privacy", "B. violating the workspace", "C. correcting the work", "D. reinforcing the efforts"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Respecting the privacy. When employees respect the privacy of others in the workplace, they are more likely to gain the trust and respect of their coworkers and managers. Respecting coworkers' privacy means that an employee does not read correspondence that is not addressed to him/her. In addition, the employee does not listen to others' private conversations or go through their personal belongings. In the example, Amanda waited until her coworker Jeff returned from lunch to obtain a file that she needed. Because she did not go through Jeff's workspace, she was respecting rather than violating his privacy. The example does not indicate that Amanda's intention was to correct Jeff's work or to reinforce his efforts\u2014she simply needed to review information in the file. SOURCE: EI:029 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 267). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Behavior that is characterized by a willingness to ignore the rights of others and to exploit them in order to achieve personal goals is __________ behavior. ", "choices": ["A. offensive", "B. passive", "C. assertive", "D. aggressive"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Aggressive. Offensive behavior is unpleasant or displeasing. Assertive behavior is characterized by respect for personal rights as well as for the rights of others. Passive behavior is characterized by a failure to exercise personal rights and a lack of respect for personal needs. SOURCE: EI:008 SOURCE: EI LAP 18\u2014Assert Yourself (Assertiveness) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "One of the reasons that teams are important to businesses is that they can increase ", "choices": ["A. procrastination.", "B. conflicts.", "C. costs.", "D. productivity."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Productivity. Productivity is the amount and value of goods and services produced (outputs) from set amounts of resources (inputs). The overall output of all employees is often increased when businesses use teams because workers who feel they are an important part of a team often work harder and produce more. Other reasons that teams are important to businesses are that they reduce costs and workplace conflicts. Teams do not increase procrastination\u2014putting off until tomorrow what should have been done today. SOURCE: EI:045 SOURCE: QS LAP 6\u2014Lean on Me (Teamwork Skills) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Which of the following statements is true about consensus building: ", "choices": ["A. The agreed upon option is not always each person's first choice.", "B. In most cases, consensus allows for a minority to rule.", "C. Each group member's opinion is less important than the leader's opinion.", "D. Consensus can be reached without everyone's agreement."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The agreed upon option is not always each person's first choice. Consensus is a decision-making outcome that requires the substantial agreement of each group member. This means that for everyone to agree, the option doesn't have to be each group member's first choice, but an option that has been presented and agreed upon as acceptable by all members of the group. Minority rule means that a few people in the group make the decision. Consensus is not minority rule, is not rule by a single leader, and cannot be reached without each group member's input and agreement, which often requires compromise. SOURCE: EI:011 SOURCE: EI LAP 19\u2014It's a Group Thing (Consensus Building) "}, {"number": 33, "question": "What is true about personal vision? ", "choices": ["A. Realistic visions are based on mission statements.", "B. Good visions have permanent results.", "C. Specific goals are necessary to determine your vision.", "D. Achievable visions are time bound."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Good visions have permanent results. A vision is a desire for the future that is achieved over time with determination and hard work. Good visions create positive results and may involve the input of many people over a long period of time. Visions are not based on mission statements, nor do they start out with specific goals. Visions are timeless rather than time bound. SOURCE: EI:063 SOURCE: QS LAP 11\u2014Picture This! "}, {"number": 34, "question": "Being a good listener is an example of what type of behavior that builds positive working relationships? ", "choices": ["A. Being cooperative", "B. Carrying your own weight", "C. Getting to know others on your work team", "D. Having a good attitude"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Being cooperative. Being a good listener is an example of being cooperative in the process of building positive working relationships. Being cooperative involves valuing the work of others as much as you value your own work. If someone needs help or is falling behind, you do your best to support him/her. This includes listening attentively when your coworker is communicating with you. Being a good listener is not an example of carrying your own weight. It may go along with getting to know others and having a good attitude, but it is best as an example of being cooperative. SOURCE: EI:037 SOURCE: EI LAP 5\u2014Can You Relate? (Positive Working Relationships) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Every pay period, Amanda places $100 from her paycheck into a savings account that earns 4.5 percent interest. In this situation, money functions as a ", "choices": ["A. store of value.", "B. medium of exchange.", "C. form of barter.", "D. measure of income."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Store of value. Money functions as a store of value when it is saved rather than spent. The money can be held over time, and it retains value for future purchasing power. In some situations, money is invested or placed in an account that generates more value. Money also serves as a medium of exchange. This occurs when money is used to obtain goods and services. Bartering involves trading one good or service for another good or service. Money also functions as a measure of value. When money functions as a measure of value, the individual holding the money assesses what s/he is willing to pay for a good or service, thereby communicating the product's value or worth. SOURCE: FI:060 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri, C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [p. 43]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co. "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Which of the following statements about understanding your spending habits is true: ", "choices": ["A. The first step in creating a financial plan", "B. A key aspect in exceeding financial goals", "C. A key aspect of opening a bank account", "D. The last step in creating a financial plan"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The first step in creating a financial plan. Knowing how you spend your money\u2014understanding your spending habits\u2014is the first step in creating a financial plan. Knowing your spending habits does not guarantee that you will exceed your financial goals. Although it's helpful to know how many checks you expect to write in a month, you don't need to understand your spending habits to open a bank account. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up (Setting Financial Goals) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 37, "question": "When Armand is comparing his checkbook balance with his bank statement, he must make sure that he has subtracted the ____________ from his checkbook. ", "choices": ["A. accumulated interest", "B. transaction fees", "C. payroll deposits", "D. check numbers"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Transaction fees. Reconciling bank statements involves comparing the entries in a checkbook with the entries listed on the bank statement. It is important to make these comparisons to determine inconsistencies and mistakes. If a check is not recorded correctly, and if the mistake is not caught, the individual runs the risk of having insufficient funds in his/her checking account, which results in bounced checks. Some financial institutions charge transaction fees for checking accounts, so it is important to make sure that those fees are subtracted from the checking account balance. Accumulated interest and payroll deposits are added to the checking account balance rather than subtracted from it. Check numbers are not subtracted from the checkbook when reconciling bank statements and checkbook balances. SOURCE: FI:070 SOURCE: Campbell, S.R. (2010). Foundations of personal finance: Teacher's Edition (pp. 193-195). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company. "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Which of the following is a type of financial-services provider: ", "choices": ["A. Taxation department", "B. Stock market", "C. Commercial bank", "D. Retirement community"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Commercial bank. A commercial bank provides a variety of financial services to individuals and businesses. Besides providing savings accounts and other savings options, banks also make loans and offer credit cards. Many large banks have trust departments and help individuals plan for retirement. Depending on the size of the bank, it may be possible to obtain all necessary financial services from that institution. The stock market itself does not provide financial services. A taxation department collects various types of taxes. A retirement community provides housing rather than financial services. SOURCE: FI:075 SOURCE: Campbell, S.R. (2010). Foundations of personal finance: Teacher's Edition (pp. 179-181). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company. "}, {"number": 39, "question": "A decrease in the availability of raw materials is an economic risk that may result in __________ for a business. ", "choices": ["A. high interest rates", "B. increased regulation", "C. financial loss", "D. lower turnover"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Financial loss. A decrease in the availability of raw materials, supplies, or products needed by a business are economic risks that can result in financial loss for the business. For example, a decrease in the availability of petroleum can cause business's transportation costs to skyrocket. High interest rates is a business condition that can create economic risks. The involvement of government in the regulation of business may cause financial loss for some businesses. High turnover, rather than low turnover, is an economic risk. SOURCE: FI:084 SOURCE: FI LAP 8\u2014Prepare for the Worst; Expect the Best (Nature of Risk Management) "}, {"number": 40, "question": "What do all businesses need to be aware of with regard to the accounting process? ", "choices": ["A. Legal considerations", "B. Management styles", "C. System specifications", "D. Research techniques"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Legal considerations. There are laws that regulate the reporting of financial information. Since accounting is the process of keeping and interpreting financial records, all businesses need to be aware of legal considerations and understand what is legal and what is not. For example, there are laws regulating the way that businesses report income and pay taxes. If businesses violate the law, they may be fined or face other types of legal action. With regard to the accounting process, it is not necessary for all businesses to be aware of management styles, system specifications, or research techniques. SOURCE: FI:353 SOURCE: SOX-Online. (2003-2012). Sarbanes-Oxley essential information. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.sox-online.com/basics.html "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Claudia is creating a balance sheet for her business. She lists the full value of all of her assets, even some office equipment she hasn't completely paid for. However, to find the true net worth of her business, Claudia must subtract the money she owes on the equipment, since the debt is considered a(n) ", "choices": ["A. liability.", "B. liquid asset.", "C. accounts receivable.", "D. dividend."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Liability. Liabilities are the financial obligations a business has. In Claudia's case, the money she still owes on her office equipment is considered a liability. To find the net worth of her business, she must subtract her total liabilities from her total assets. This gives her an accurate picture of her business's health. A liquid asset is cash or any asset that can be quickly converted into cash. Accounts receivable are money owed to the business for purchases made by customers. Dividends are sums of money paid to investors or stockholders as earnings on investments. SOURCE: FI:093 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 74). South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 42, "question": "A business should strive to keep its cash conversion cycle as short as possible so it ", "choices": ["A. can earn dividends.", "B. has cash available to use.", "C. can increase its profit margin.", "D. has fewer liquid assets."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Has cash available to use. The cash conversion cycle is the ratio that reflects the number of days between a company paying for raw materials and receiving cash from selling the products made from those raw materials. The longer this period of time, the longer the company's money is tied up and unavailable for other uses. Therefore, a financial manager strives to keep the cash conversion cycle as short as possible, so that the business has more free cash to work with. A dividend is the amount of money that a corporation pays to a stockholder as earnings on an investment. The profit margin is a product pricing consideration. The profit margin is the amount of money that a business earns on sales after expenses and is expressed as a ratio. Liquid assets are things of value that the business owns, which can be quickly converted to cash. SOURCE: FI:354 SOURCE: FI LAP 7\u2014Money Matters (Role of Finance) "}, {"number": 43, "question": "One reason why human resources management is important to the success of a business is because this process is responsible for ", "choices": ["A. creating jobs for the company.", "B. eliminating turnover.", "C. staffing the business.", "D. reducing compensation."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Staffing the business. Human resources management is the process of planning, staffing, leading, and organizing the employees of a business. Staffing is an important function because hiring and keeping qualified employees will contribute to the success of the business. Employees who are capable and hardworking usually help the business to achieve its goals and be successful. It is not possible to completely eliminate turnover. Management usually decides if it needs to expand and create more jobs. Human resources management administers the compensation package, but it is not responsible for reducing compensation. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: HR LAP 35\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management) "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Which of the following is a way that marketers can use data to \u201cfollow up\u201d on any problems or issues with a product: ", "choices": ["A. Providing salespeople with additional training", "B. Determining what new products to offer", "C. Deciding what wholesalers to use for distribution", "D. Budgeting for product development"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Providing salespeople with additional training. Data may show that salespeople need additional training for a certain product. This is something marketers want to provide so sales and profits can be as high as possible. Determining what new products to offer, deciding which wholesalers to use for distribution, and budgeting for product development are all activities that should take place before a product hits the market. SOURCE: IM:012 SOURCE: IM LAP 12\u2014Data Do It (Need for Marketing Data) "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Software that allows for real-time analysis of marketing information enables businesses to search many databases and identify ", "choices": ["A. obscure relationships.", "B. pricing strategies.", "C. hidden objections.", "D. distribution channels."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Obscure relationships. Advances in technology have created software that allows for real-time analysis of marketing information. The benefit of this software to businesses is that it enables them to search many databases and identify obscure relationships. The software allows businesses to analyze the data as it is collected and compare it with information stored in many other databases. For example, real-time analysis might discover that a customer applying for store credit has the same telephone number as another customer who recently declared bankruptcy. This information would be immediately made available to the credit manager. Pricing strategies are plans for setting prices. A hidden objection is a real objection the customer does not want brought out in the open. Distribution channels are paths, or routes, that goods or services take from the producer to the ultimate consumer or industrial user. SOURCE: IM:183 SOURCE: Kurtz, D. (2013). Contemporary marketing: 2013 edition (p. 261). Mason, OH: SouthWestern, Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 46, "question": "A business should decide at the beginning of a marketing-research project how much it can afford to spend in order to ", "choices": ["A. tell the researcher when to stop the project.", "B. narrow the focus of the research if necessary.", "C. cut the project in half if that is all it can afford.", "D. skip some of the research steps if it needs to save time."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Narrow the focus of the research if necessary. Many businesses allocate a specific amount in the budget for marketing research. If the amount will not cover the expense of the entire research project, then the business should stop at this point or narrow the focus of the project to the part that would be most useful at that time. The steps in the marketing-research process must be taken in a specific order, and none of them can be skipped. Starting a project and then telling the researcher to stop or cutting the project in half would not be effective. SOURCE: IM:010 SOURCE: IM LAP 5\u2014Seek and Find (Marketing Research) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 47, "question": "A business conducts marketing research when it needs to solve a problem or when it wants to ", "choices": ["A. identify a new market opportunity.", "B. increase its sales staff.", "C. coordinate activities.", "D. analyze financing options."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Identify a new market opportunity. Marketing research is the systematic gathering, recording, and analyzing of data about a specific issue, situation, or concern. To remain competitive in the marketplace, businesses conduct marketing research. One way to remain competitive in the marketplace is to identify, select, and distribute products to a new market segment, whose identification requires marketing research. If the business finds that a new market opportunity is feasible, it might decide to increase its sales staff, coordinate new marketing activities, or analyze financing options. Analyzing financing options is a business activity rather than a marketing-research activity. SOURCE: IM:282 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B. (2010). Essentials of marketing research (4th ed.) [pp. 14, 52]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Marketers may want to use research to study the economy, a factor that is subject to change. In this context, the economy can be described as a(n) ", "choices": ["A. variable.", "B. case study.", "C. experiment.", "D. hypothesis."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Variable. A variable is any factor that is subject to change. Sometimes, the economy is the variable that marketers want to study through research. A case study is an in-depth analysis of a person, group, or event. An experiment is a marketing-research method that tests cause and effect by test marketing new products or comparing test groups with control groups. A hypothesis is a proposed explanation for something. SOURCE: IM:284 SOURCE: IM LAP 14\u2014Better By Design (Marketing Research Design Methods) "}, {"number": 49, "question": "The purpose of semantic-differential rating scales is to measure ", "choices": ["A. talent.", "B. behavior.", "C. personality.", "D. attitude."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Attitude. Semantic-differential rating scales are used to measure attitude. Research participants are asked to check the box that best describes their feelings. Each box on the scale contains an adjective or phrase, such as courteous or discourteous. By checking a box, respondents indicate their attitude or how they feel about statements. Behavior is the manner in which individuals act. Personality is an individual's qualities or traits and behavior. Talent is an individual's aptitude for learning specific skills. SOURCE: IM:286 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 348-350]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 50, "question": "What data-collection method can be used to obtain product information during the point-of-purchase process? ", "choices": ["A. Statistical survey", "B. Photographic scanner", "C. Email survey", "D. Volume-tracking scanner"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Volume-tracking scanner. A scanner is an electronic device that reads or translates codes that are placed on products and enters the product information into a computer. Scanners are commonly used during a sales transaction, which is the point of purchase. This is a popular method of collecting information about customers' buying habits and inventory status because the scanning system can track large volumes of goods. Once enough data are collected, researchers evaluate the data to determine how fast or slow certain products are moving, which is information they can use to make business decisions. Photographic scanners, email surveys, and statistical surveys are not data-collection methods that researchers use during the point-of-purchase process. SOURCE: IM:289 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 256-257]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 51, "question": "Which of the following is an example of range: ", "choices": ["A. Consumers buy between four and eight widgets per week.", "B. Consumers buy an average of six widgets per week.", "C. Most consumers buy five widgets per week.", "D. Half of all consumers buy more than four widgets per week."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Consumers buy between four and eight widgets per week. Range is the distance between the smallest and largest value in a set of responses. In the example, four was the smallest number of widgets purchased, and eight was the largest number. The distance between four and eight is the range. Range is often used to describe the relation between numbers, such as the variation between the number of widgets purchased. Mean is the average, such as consumers buying an average of six widgets per week. Mode is the most common response, such as most consumers buy five widgets per week. Median is the exact middle, such as half of all consumers buying more than four widgets per week. SOURCE: IM:191 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [p. 445-446]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Which of the following is a source of error in the research process: ", "choices": ["A. Key summary", "B. Interview location", "C. Sample design", "D. Project purpose"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Sample design. When collecting information, researchers usually select a sample of the target population to contact or include in the study. The design of this sample may lead to errors in the research. Researchers need to make sure the sample they select accurately represents the target population. For example, errors may occur if all those in the sample are 20-year-old males who live in one small city, but the research involves all men between the ages of 18 and 50. Interview location, key summary, and project purpose are not sources of error in the research process. SOURCE: IM:292 SOURCE: Hair, J.F., Wolfinbarger, M, Ortinau, D.J., & Bush, R.P. (2008). Essentials of marketing research (p. 136). New York, McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 53, "question": "Which of the following is a possible weakness associated with a secondary-data source: ", "choices": ["A. Internet accessibility", "B. Recent industry approval", "C. Reasonable purchase price", "D. Inconsistent collection method"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Inconsistent collection method. Secondary data are information that have been collected for purposes other than the project at hand. Marketers collect secondary data from a variety of sources, such as business websites, research companies, trade associations, and industry journals. Although secondarydata sources can be inexpensive and provide current information, researchers must be careful to examine the way in which the source collected information. If the source publishes statistical data it has collected in an inconsistent or subjective way, the data may be skewed or exhibit bias. Industry approval, reasonable prices, and Internet accessibility are advantages associated with secondary-data sources. SOURCE: IM:428 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 164-165]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 54, "question": "The marketing function that best enables a company to make informed decisions about what to sell is ", "choices": ["A. promotion.", "B. product/service management.", "C. selling.", "D. marketing-information management."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Marketing-information management. This function involves gathering, accessing, synthesizing, evaluating, and disseminating information to aid in making marketing decisions. The findings from marketing-information management are used in product/service management to guide product development and improvement. The selling function involves determining customer needs and wants and responding through planned, personalized communication that influences purchase decisions and enhances future business opportunities. The promotion function is marketing function needed to communicate information about goods, services, images, and/or ideas to achieve a desired outcome. SOURCE: MK:002 SOURCE: MK LAP 1\u2014Work the Big Six (Marketing Functions) "}, {"number": 55, "question": "The owner of a business is meeting with the company's managers and supervisors to set objectives for the next year. This group is developing the company's ", "choices": ["A. business goals.", "B. channels of distribution.", "C. market share.", "D. promotional mix."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Business goals. The goals or objectives of a business are the things the business wants to attain. A particular share of the industry market might be a business's goal. The promotional mix is the combination of marketing communication channels that a business uses to send its messages to consumers. Channels of distribution are the paths, or routes, that goods or services take from the producer to the ultimate consumer or industrial user. SOURCE: MP:001 SOURCE: MP LAP 2\u2014Pick the Mix (Nature of Marketing Strategies) "}, {"number": 56, "question": "When a local athletic apparel store sells shoes, clothing, and accessories that are designed specifically for runners, it is using ____________ segmentation. ", "choices": ["A. demographic", "B. geographic", "C. psychographic", "D. rate of usage"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Psychographic. Market segmentation is dividing the market into groups that have similar characteristics. Segmenting markets helps businesses identify the people who are most likely to buy their products. Businesses segment markets in different ways. In the example, the athletic apparel store used psychographics to divide the market, which means that the market is divided on the basis of a lifestyle choice\u2014running. Geographic segmentation involves dividing a market on the basis of location (e.g., zip code). Demographics are the physical and social characteristics of the population. A business that segments the market on the basis of demographics considers factors such as the age, gender, and ethnicity of the population. Rate of usage is a type of behavioral segmentation, which involves dividing customers into groups according to their response to a product. SOURCE: MP:003 SOURCE: MP LAP 3\u2014Have We Met? (Market Identification) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 57, "question": "To evaluate an Internet source, what aspect would you consider when assessing whether its information is clearly laid out so that it is easy to read? ", "choices": ["A. Relevance", "B. Presentation", "C. Objectivity", "D. Timeliness"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Presentation. Presentation is the way in which the information is communicated. It addresses such factors as clarity of language used, sufficiency of font size, clarity of layout, effectiveness of colors, usefulness of graphics or photos, clarity of audio or video (if included), and helpfulness of any animation used. Presentation is particularly important on the Web since so much time is spent reading online. Relevance deals with whether the information pertains to the topic being researched. Objectivity deals with presenting unbiased information. Timeliness deals with how up to date the information is; however, the importance of timeliness will vary from topic to topic. SOURCE: NF:079 SOURCE: Cornell University Library. (2014, February 13). Evaluating web sites: Criteria and tools. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://olinuris.library.cornell.edu/ref/research/webeval.html "}, {"number": 58, "question": "What do businesses often develop to be able to store and analyze data for the purpose of making business decisions? ", "choices": ["A. Management policies", "B. Operating procedures", "C. Survey methods", "D. Information systems"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Information systems. An information system is a method of gathering, storing, and analyzing data for the purpose of making business decisions. Businesses acquire vast amounts of information that must be stored and analyzed to make it useful. An effective information system enables a business to quickly and accurately process information and use that information to make decisions. Businesses do not develop operating procedures, survey methods, or management policies to be able to store and analyze data for the purpose of making business decisions. SOURCE: NF:083 SOURCE: Rouse, M., & Martinez, C. (2011, March). IS (information system or information services). Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://whatis.techtarget.com/definition/IS-information-systemor-information-services "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following is available to all people around the world who have access to a computer that has connectivity: ", "choices": ["A. Extranet", "B. Intranet", "C. Internet", "D. Broadband"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Internet. The Internet is a worldwide network of computers that enables users to access information and communicate with others. The Internet is available to all people around the world who have access to a computer that has connectivity. Today, connectivity may be by dial-up to telephone lines, through broadband technology, or through wireless routers. All people around the world do not have access to an Intranet or an Extranet. Broadband is a type of technology. SOURCE: NF:086 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 223). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Many presentation software programs allow users to ", "choices": ["A. copyright their graphics.", "B. include voice narration.", "C. calculate numerical data.", "D. analyze organizational progress."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Include voice narration. Many multimedia software programs have options that allow sound (e.g., voice or ringing bell) to be included to add interest to the presentation. Sound should be appropriately placed and pertinent to the presentation theme. Businesses use spreadsheet software to make, document, and calculate numerical data. Businesses do not use presentation software to analyze organizational progress. SOURCE: NF:008 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 215). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 61, "question": "What is one reason that a local business would keep records of all its customer-sales transactions? ", "choices": ["A. To cancel orders", "B. To issue rebates", "C. To handle returns", "D. To budget expenses"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To handle returns. Businesses, such as retailers, keep a financial record of each sales transaction and give a copy of the record, a receipt, to the customer. When a customer returns an item, a business uses the information in the financial record to issue the customer a refund or a credit. The return transaction also becomes a part of the business's financial records. Businesses do not keep records of sales transactions in order to cancel orders. Rebates are a return of part of the price a customer pays for a good or service. They are usually offered by the product's manufacturer rather than by retailers. Expenses are monies the business spends, whereas sales transactions usually result in income. SOURCE: NF:001 SOURCE: NF LAP 1\u2014Record It (Business Records) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a current trend in business: ", "choices": ["A. Protecting consumer privacy", "B. Expanding economic growth", "C. Developing market research", "D. Promoting private enterprise"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Protecting consumer privacy. Businesses are becoming more concerned with ways of protecting consumer privacy because of the new technology that makes it easy to gather and disseminate personal information. The rapid growth of electronic commerce, which enables consumers to purchase products online, also enables businesses to collect information about credit cards, personal preferences, and buying habits that many consumers prefer to keep private. In response to a growing concern on the part of consumers, businesses are trying to develop techniques that will protect consumer privacy\u2014not only online\u2014but also from other types of abuses. Economic expansion and marketing research are fundamental business activities rather than current trends. Private enterprise is an economic system in which individuals and groups, rather than government, own or control the means of production. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 94-95]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 63, "question": "When conducting an environmental scan, which of the following is an economic factor that a business should consider: ", "choices": ["A. Local demographics", "B. Global trade regulations", "C. Consumer spending habits", "D. Restricted sales territories"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Consumer spending habits. An environmental scan is an analysis of external forces that influence a business's success. By examining economic, political, socio-cultural, and technological factors that affect the business, the business can take steps to ward off the threats and to take advantage of the opportunities based on the information that the scan provides. Consumer spending habits are an economic factor that might be a threat or an opportunity. If spending is increasing because the economy is healthy, businesses will be able to increase production and sell more. Global trade regulations are a political factor. Local demographics and restricted sales territories are not economic factors. SOURCE: NF:015 SOURCE: Boundless. (n.d.). Scanning and analysis. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from https://www.boundless.com/marketing/the-marketing-environment/the-marketingenvironment/scanning-and-analysis/ "}, {"number": 64, "question": "A clothing manufacturer checks one pair of pants out of every shipment to ensure the quality of its product. This process is known as quality ", "choices": ["A. inspection.", "B. guarantee.", "C. delivery.", "D. assurance."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Inspection. Checking a sample item for defects after it has already been produced is part of a process known as quality inspection. Quality assurance is a process businesses use to prevent defective products from being created, not just to eliminate or correct them after they've already been produced. Quality guarantee and quality delivery are not traditional terms used in operations or quality control. SOURCE: OP:189 SOURCE: OP LAP 3\u2014Smooth Operations (Nature of Operations) "}, {"number": 65, "question": "What should employees who are learning a new skill avoid doing? ", "choices": ["A. Acting safely", "B. Following rules", "C. Taking shortcuts", "D. Asking questions"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Taking shortcuts. Employees who are learning a new skill should work slowly and cautiously, and avoid taking shortcuts. The quickest way is not necessarily the best way to complete tasks. Employees should practice the new skill using the appropriate steps and following the order in which they were instructed to use them. Employees who are learning a new skill should ask questions, follow rules, and act safely. SOURCE: OP:007 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [p. 113]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 66, "question": "An author's new book is an example of a ", "choices": ["A. derivative project.", "B. breakthrough project.", "C. R&D project.", "D. platform project."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Platform project. An author's new book is an example of a platform project, one that creates something entirely new. A derivative project enhances, adds to, or extends an existing project. A breakthrough project relies on the use of new technology. An R&D project takes on new visions or pursuits for the business. SOURCE: OP:158 SOURCE: OP LAP 6\u2014Projected to Win (Nature of Project Management) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Before identifying the right people to work on a project, it is important to ", "choices": ["A. develop accurate job descriptions.", "B. select necessary supplies.", "C. ask organizations for contributions.", "D. prepare construction specifications."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Develop accurate job descriptions. Before identifying the right people to work on a project, it is important to develop accurate descriptions of the jobs these people will need to perform. The descriptions should explain exactly what is involved such as qualifications, education, or experience. Then, match the skills of project members to the job descriptions to find the people who will be able to do the work. It is not important to select necessary supplies, ask for contributions, or prepare specifications before identifying the right people to work on a project. SOURCE: OP:003 SOURCE: QS LAP 19\u2014Get What You Need "}, {"number": 68, "question": "When managing a project, the first activity is for the project leader to ", "choices": ["A. develop a schedule.", "B. set goals.", "C. negotiate terms.", "D. monitor progress."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Set goals. It is important to develop a clear understanding of the project's objectives or goals. Without a clear understanding of the desired outcome, a project manager cannot effectively develop a schedule, negotiate terms, or monitor project progress. SOURCE: OP:002 SOURCE: QS LAP 18\u2014Make It Happen "}, {"number": 69, "question": "A reason that many companies update or alter existing products is to ", "choices": ["A. be able to plan production quantities.", "B. make them competitive with similar products.", "C. create new products to put on the market.", "D. use a familiar production process."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Make them competitive with similar products. Updating or altering an existing product is a good way to compete effectively with similar products produced by other companies. Changing products is usually much less expensive than creating new products. Updated or altered products are not new products but new versions of old products. Changing products does not help the business to plan quantities since it does not know how well the revised product will sell. Being able to use a known production process would not be a valid reason for updating or altering products. SOURCE: OP:017 SOURCE: OP LAP 4\u2014Can You Make It? (Nature of Production) "}, {"number": 70, "question": "A focus on how things are done, rather than just outcomes, is known as ", "choices": ["A. continual improvement.", "B. lean production.", "C. process orientation.", "D. concurrent engineering."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Process orientation. Process orientation is a focus on how things are done, rather than just outcomes. It is a central principle of ISO 9000. Lean production is maximizing customer value while minimizing waste. Continual improvement is a focus on increasing efficiency and effectiveness in all areas of the organization. Concurrent engineering is performing the stages of product design and development simultaneously, instead of one after another. SOURCE: OP:163 SOURCE: OP LAP 8\u2014Take Control (Quality-Control Measures) "}, {"number": 71, "question": "When the LXT Audio-Book Company was founded 15 years ago, its target market was blind and visuallyimpaired individuals who enjoyed listening to nonfiction audio books. Recently, though, the company has begun marketing these same audio books as \u201clearning solutions\u201d for individuals with dyslexia and other learning disabilities. This is an example of __________ innovation. ", "choices": ["A. paradigm", "B. product", "C. process", "D. positioning"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Positioning. Innovation is the lifeblood of business, helping firms to stay competitive and to move forward. There are four specific types of innovation: product, process, positioning, and paradigm. Product innovation involves the development of totally new or improved products. Process innovation involves improving of some aspect of a process (e.g., manufacturing process). Positioning innovation involves identifying new, different ways to position a product or a company. LXT capitalized on positioning innovation by finding a different way to position its audio books in the marketplace. Paradigm innovation is a shift in the way of thinking that causes change. SOURCE: PD:126 SOURCE: PD LAP 18\u2014Ideas in Action (Innovation Skills) "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Which of the following is an example of gathering information before making a decision: ", "choices": ["A. Watching movies", "B. Writing letters", "C. Reading novels", "D. Asking questions"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Asking questions. Before individuals can make decisions, they need to obtain information about the problem or situation. One way of gathering information is to ask questions of friends, family, coworkers, or supervisors. Asking questions enables individuals to gather additional information that may be useful in helping them to make good decisions. Watching movies, writing letters, and reading novels are not ways of obtaining information to use in decision making. SOURCE: PD:017 SOURCE: PD LAP 10\u2014Weigh Your Options (Decision Making in Business) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 73, "question": "Employees who are unable to manage their time effectively often experience ", "choices": ["A. decreased pressure.", "B. increased stress.", "C. increased self-esteem.", "D. decreased tension."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Increased stress. Stress is a mental or emotional feeling of pressure or tension. Employees who do not manage their time effectively often experience increased levels of stress. They find that they do not have the time to complete their tasks at work, and feel overwhelmed and under pressure to get everything done. The stress may follow them home and impact on their relationships with family and friends. Employees who are unable to effectively manage their time often experience increased pressure and tension, and decreased self-esteem. SOURCE: PD:019 SOURCE: PD LAP 1\u2014About Time (Time Management) "}, {"number": 74, "question": "What should you avoid doing when filling out an employment application? ", "choices": ["A. Leaving blank spaces", "B. Specifying certain jobs", "C. Providing exact data", "D. Signing your name"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Leaving blank spaces. When completing an employment application, you should answer all the questions and fill in all the blanks. If the question does not pertain to you, write \"NA\" for not applicable. If you do not know the answer, write \"unknown.\" By filling in all the spaces, you indicate to the employer that you have read all the questions even if you don't have the answers. Employment applications usually require your signature. You should always specify the job for which you are applying and provide exact data on the employment application. SOURCE: PD:027 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 596). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 75, "question": "The basic purpose of writing a letter of application concerning a job opening is to ", "choices": ["A. interest the employer in interviewing you.", "B. describe your job skills in detail.", "C. tell the employer how you found out about the job.", "D. provide the employer with your complete work history."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Interest the employer in interviewing you. The purpose of a letter of application is to catch the interest of the prospective employer so that you will be called in for a personal interview. Few employees are hired without a personal interview. The letter of application should tell the employer how you found out about the job, but that is not a basic purpose of the letter. The letter should touch on your work history and job skills, but the complete details should be presented in your r\u00e9sum\u00e9. SOURCE: PD:030 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 125-126). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 76, "question": "The primary reason why many people engage in career-oriented networking activities is to ", "choices": ["A. connect with others who might help them accomplish professional goals.", "B. develop an extensive list of sales prospects and contacts.", "C. obtain letters of recommendation from previous employers.", "D. cultivate a wide circle of social and personal contacts."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Connect with others who might help them accomplish professional goals. People engage in networking activities by communicating with customers, friends, family, teachers, and former coworkers. Networking often provides people with information regarding work-related opportunities, such as job openings. Although networking is often used to develop a list of sales prospects and contacts, many people are not involved in selling activities in their occupation. Career-networking activities are primarily used to improve or enhance work-related situations rather than social standing. Obtaining letters of recommendation is often a result of networking activities. However, it is not always the primary reason why people network. SOURCE: PD:037 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Entering the world of work (pp. 138-140). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 77, "question": "A characteristic of effective prices is that they must be ", "choices": ["A. high.", "B. inflexible.", "C. competitive.", "D. low."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Competitive. When a similar product is offered by other businesses, a business needs to be aware of the prices of those businesses. If not, the business will probably lose customers because it is not competitive. Businesses must be willing to adjust their prices, depending on the circumstances faced by the business. Changes in the economy, demand, and other factors can affect pricing. SOURCE: PI:001 SOURCE: PI LAP 2\u2014The Price is Right (Nature of Pricing) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 78, "question": "Which of the following pricing practices is illegal in some countries because it may drive a company's competitors' out of business: ", "choices": ["A. Below-cost pricing", "B. One-price policies", "C. Price skimming", "D. Markup pricing"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Below-cost pricing. When a company prices its products below cost, it makes it difficult for other companies to compete with the low prices, which they cannot afford to charge, and might eventually force them out of business. To prevent this situation from happening, many governments have laws that make it illegal for businesses to use below-cost pricing. When a business charges one price for all items it sells, it is using a one-price policy. Price skimming is a pricing strategy that involves setting prices higher than those of the competition. Markup is the difference between the cost of a product and its selling price. SOURCE: PI:017 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2006). Marketing essentials (pp. 535-537, 544, 549-550). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 79, "question": "One way that advances in technology are impacting the product/service management function is by making it possible for businesses to ", "choices": ["A. improve existing products.", "B. eliminate human errors.", "C. simplify production systems.", "D. control customer preferences."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Improve existing products. As a result of advances in technology, new materials and operating techniques have been developed. These materials and techniques have made it possible for businesses to improve existing products. This impacts the product/service management function because it enables businesses to extend the life of existing products and keep them on the market. Businesses have found that it is usually less expensive to update existing products than to develop entirely new products. Advances in technology are allowing businesses to do this. Advances in technology often help to reduce human errors but cannot completely eliminate them. Advances in technology often make production systems more complex because they rely on complicated computer systems. Businesses are not able to control customer preferences. SOURCE: PM:039 SOURCE: BusinessKnowledgeSource.com. (2003-2010). Pros and cons of improving or changing existing products. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.businessknowledgesource.com/marketing/pros_and_cons_of_improving_or_chan ging_existing_products_023885.html "}, {"number": 80, "question": "Pick the best response: Where do product opportunities exist? ", "choices": ["A. Anywhere that people have had their needs satisfied", "B. Where people work", "C. Where people participate in their hobbies", "D. Anywhere there is an un- or under-met need"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Anywhere there is an un- or under-met need. People can recognize unmet or under-met needs wherever they are. This could be at work or where they are enjoying their hobbies. When people have their needs satisfied, product opportunities don't exist. It's when there's a problem or situation that isn't being taken care of that people can find product opportunities. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: Katz, J., & Green, R. (2011). Entrepreneurial small business (3rd ed.) [pp. 80-83]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. "}, {"number": 81, "question": "When using mind mapping to generate product ideas, you begin by writing down the main problem or ", "choices": ["A. situational analysis.", "B. supporting facts.", "C. primary associations.", "D. market opportunity."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Market opportunity. When a situation exists to fulfill a market's unmet needs, there is a market opportunity. Entrepreneurs and businesses use creative-thinking techniques during the productdevelopment process, which involves finding ways to take advantage of the market opportunity that presents itself. Mind mapping is a creative-thinking technique that involves generating ideas by making associations. To begin the mind-mapping process, you write the problem or market opportunity in the center of a large sheet of paper. From that starting point, you draw lines to other words or phrases that relate to the main idea (problem, or market opportunity), and continue the process by making associations, which generates ideas and identifies possible solutions. The mind-mapping starting point does not begin by writing down supporting facts or primary associations. A situational analysis is a determination of a firm's current business situation and the direction in which the business is headed. SOURCE: PM:127 SOURCE: PM LAP 11\u2014Unleash Your Oh! Zone (Techniques for Generating Ideas) "}, {"number": 82, "question": "True or False: Only express warranties hold up in court. ", "choices": ["A. False; express warranties must be in writing.", "B. True; implied warranties cannot be verified.", "C. False; implied warranties are valid.", "D. True; only written evidence can be submitted in court."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "False; implied warranties are valid. There was a time when only express warranties held up in court, but today's courts recognize implied warranties as valid. Express warranties are warranties that are in writing or expressed verbally. SOURCE: PM:020 SOURCE: PM LAP 4\u2014Promises, Promises (Warranties and Guarantees) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 83, "question": "What strategy can make or break a business's product mix? ", "choices": ["A. Positioning", "B. Contracting", "C. Altering", "D. Expanding"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Positioning. Positioning is a product-mix strategy in which a business creates a certain image or impression of a product in the minds of consumers. Businesses must determine the best position to seek for their products because correct positioning is necessary to sales and profits. Positioning can make or break a business's product mix. Contraction is a product-mix strategy in which a business removes, or deletes, product items or product lines from its product mix. Alteration is a product-mix strategy in which a business makes changes to its products or product lines. Expansion is a product-mix strategy in which a business expands its product mix by adding additional product items or product lines. SOURCE: PM:003 SOURCE: PM LAP 3\u2014Mix & Match (Nature of the Product Mix) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Text that continues or clarifies the thought expressed in the print ad's headline is referred to as the ", "choices": ["A. tag line.", "B. subhead.", "C. identification.", "D. white space."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Subhead. A subhead, or subheadline, adds information to that expressed in the headline. It is usually positioned below the headline and set in slightly smaller size type. The tag line is a slogan used in an advertisement. It may be part of the identification element, the part of the ad that identifies the product's brand or advertiser. White space is the blank space in a print advertisement that is unoccupied by text or illustrations. SOURCE: PR:014 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 471). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Why do companies use brands for their products? ", "choices": ["A. To demonstrate creativity", "B. To charge higher prices", "C. To encourage materialism", "D. To differentiate their products"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To differentiate their products. Companies want their products to be perceived as different from those of other companies. They can do this through the use of brands. Charging higher prices and encouraging materialism are seen by consumers as negative aspects of brands. Creating an appealing brand often requires creativity, but demonstrating creativity is not a purpose of using brands. SOURCE: PM:021 SOURCE: PM LAP 6\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (Nature of Product Branding) "}, {"number": 86, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a purchase experience touchpoint: ", "choices": ["A. Word-of-mouth", "B. Direct sales", "C. Customer satisfaction surveys", "D. Warranty programs"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Direct sales. Touchpoints are the interactions that customers have with the business, and they can be divided into three categories: pre-purchase, purchase, and post-purchase experiences. Direct sales would occur during a purchase experience. Other examples of purchase experience touchpoints are physical stores and contact with customer representatives. Word-of-mouth is an example of a prepurchase touchpoint. Customer satisfaction surveys, and warranty programs are examples of postpurchase experience touchpoints. SOURCE: PM:207 SOURCE: Flynn, J. (2013, October 31). Purchase touchpoints: Maximizing the brand experience. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://blog.hultmarketing.com/blog/purchase-touchpointsmaximizing-the-brand-experience "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Many of the town's residents have heard that this coming summer is predicted to be the hottest summer ever. As a result of hearing this, Tim, the owner of an appliance store, decided to do more advertising for air conditioners. Which of the following external factors has affected Tim and his business: ", "choices": ["A. Cultural and social trends", "B. Legal and political factors", "C. Technology", "D. Demand"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Demand. Demand for certain products tends to change with the seasons, such as air conditioners for summer. This means that Tim needs to adjust his promotion to meet this change. Technology deals with technological developments, not demand for a product. Legal and political factors deal with government regulations and restrictions, not demand for a product. Cultural and social trends deal with changes in attitudes, lifestyles, and tastes of the consumers, not demand for a product. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: PR LAP 2\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Nature of Promotion) "}, {"number": 88, "question": "The specific goal of product promotion is to ", "choices": ["A. persuade consumers to buy a particular good or service.", "B. inform consumers about the company.", "C. show the company's commitment to technology or research.", "D. change a particular attitude toward a firm or its products."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Persuade consumers to buy a particular good or service. Product promotion is used to stimulate consumer purchases of goods or services. Showing the company's commitment to technology or research, informing consumers about the company, and changing a particular attitude toward a firm or its product are goals of institutional promotion. SOURCE: PR:002 SOURCE: PR LAP 4\u2014Know Your Options (Types of Promotion) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is the most visible element of the promotional mix: ", "choices": ["A. Personal selling", "B. Sales promotion", "C. Publicity", "D. Advertising"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Advertising. Advertising is any paid form of nonpersonal presentation of ideas, images, goods, or services. It is the most visible element of the promotional mix because it can be delivered to a wide range of consumers through a variety of mass media. Sales promotion includes promotional activities other than advertising, personal selling, and publicity that stimulate consumer purchases. Publicity is any nonpersonal presentation of ideas, goods, or services that is not paid for by the company or individual which benefits from it. Personal selling is the form of promotion that uses planned, personalized communication in order to influence purchase decisions and enhance future business opportunities. SOURCE: PR:003 SOURCE: PR LAP 1\u2014Spread the Word (Nature of the Promotional Mix) "}, {"number": 90, "question": "What type of information are businesses that sponsor sales promotion sweepstakes and contests required to make available to the customers who participate in those promotions? ", "choices": ["A. Odds of winning", "B. Amount of rebate", "C. Value of coupon", "D. Samples of product"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Odds of winning. In order to operate ethically, businesses that sponsor sweepstakes and contests are required to inform potential participants about the odds of winning. By providing this type of information, businesses are not misleading or deceiving customers about the possibility of winning. Customers have the right to know what their chances of winning are in order to decide if they want to participate. A rebate is a return of part of the price a customer pays for a good or service. A coupon is a certificate or part of a printed advertisement entitling the holder to a reduced purchase price. A sample is a small amount of a product. SOURCE: PR:099 SOURCE: California Department of Consumer Affairs. (2014). Be smart, buy smart: What smart shoppers know about sweepstakes, contests, and lotteries. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.dca.ca.gov/publications/sweep.shtml "}, {"number": 91, "question": "Governments that have passed \u201cdo not call\u201d laws are restricting promotional activities related to ", "choices": ["A. contests.", "B. telemarketing.", "C. Internet downloads.", "D. direct mail."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Telemarketing. Telemarketing is an advertising medium that utilizes telephone service to promote a product either by phoning prospective customers or providing a number for them to call. In the past few years, consumer groups have complained that telemarketing has become intrusive, so many governments have started to regulate telemarketing practices. Some governments have developed \u201cdo not call\u201d laws. These laws allow consumers to register their phone numbers with a \u201cdo not call\u201d registry. Qualifying businesses must obtain this list and not call consumers who have registered with the program. If they violate these laws, the businesses may be fined. \u201cDo not call\u201d laws do not regulate contests, Internet downloads, or direct mail. SOURCE: PR:101 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [pp. 142-143]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 92, "question": "A local, exclusive business is having a sale. Which of the following advertising media would be most effective in promoting the sale to the business's clientele: ", "choices": ["A. Out-of-home", "B. Broadcast", "C. Magazine", "D. Direct mail"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Direct mail. Direct mail is a promotional medium that comes to consumers' homes in the form of letters, catalogs, postcards, and folders. Direct mail would be the most effective medium because the business can choose the clientele who will receive the promotional message. Broadcast and out-of-home media have limited selectivity. Magazine advertising is selective but costly, and the timing of the message may not be appropriate. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: PR LAP 3\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Promotional Media) "}, {"number": 93, "question": "What is the primary goal of viral marketing? ", "choices": ["A. Managing", "B. Staging", "C. Sharing", "D. Manipulating"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Sharing. Viral marketing is a promotional tactic that involves sending or forwarding promotional messages over the Internet (e.g., email, social-media websites, and blogs) to generate buzz about a brand, company, or product. Marketers often use humor, incentives, events, spoofs, videos, and other unusual techniques to spark conversations and encourage people to share their messages with others. It is important for marketers to prepare (stage) and manage the message content; however, staging, managing, and manipulating are not the primary goals of viral marketing. SOURCE: PR:247 SOURCE: Baeldal, T. (2006, November 23). 7 tricks to viral web marketing. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.baekdal.com/analysis/viral-marketing-tricks Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 94, "question": "What communication channels is a corporation's public-relations department most likely to use to maintain positive relationships with shareholders? ", "choices": ["A. News conferences, consumer blogs, and employee manuals", "B. Press releases, online social networks, and print advertisements", "C. Newsletters, annual reports, and the company's website", "D. Policy manuals, commercials, and sponsorships"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Newsletters, annual reports, and the company's website. Public relations involves establishing good relationships between the business and the public. A business tries to maintain positive relationships with different groups that make up the public, such as employees, local businesses, government officials, the media, and the business's shareholders. Because the shareholders are the owners of the company, it is important to develop and maintain positive relationships with them. The public-relations department does this by communicating with them through newsletters, annual reports, the company's website, and online social networks. Print advertisements and commercials are forms of nonpersonal advertising. Businesses use press releases and news conferences to convey information to the media. Policy manuals help guide employees' actions on the job. Consumer blogs can be developed by anyone to communicate positive and negative information about various goods and services. A sponsorship is a partnership in which a company pays a fee to affiliate itself with a team, league, or event. SOURCE: PR:250 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [pp. 432-435]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 95, "question": "Successful positioning appeals to customers' ", "choices": ["A. emotions.", "B. five senses.", "C. desire to save money.", "D. logic."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Emotions. Successful positioning appeals to customers' emotions. It connects with their feelings rather than just their logical or rational thoughts. Positioning is not a tangible experience that involves the five senses. A product may be positioned as a \u201cvalue item,\u201d or a way for customers to save money, but not all successful positioning depends on this desire. SOURCE: PM:042 SOURCE: PM LAP 19\u2014Getting Piece of Mind (Factors Used to Position Products/Services) "}, {"number": 96, "question": "When salespeople demonstrate the features and benefits of goods or services, they often are able to ", "choices": ["A. provide jobs for more employees.", "B. add usefulness to products.", "C. develop new and improved products.", "D. create desire for products."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Create desire for products. Through the selling process, salespeople are often able to create desire for products by demonstrating the features and benefits of goods or services. By presenting the features and benefits, salespeople can explain to customers how the particular products will satisfy their wants and needs. As a result of creating desire, salespeople are often able to sell the product. Demonstrating the features and benefits of goods or services does not add usefulness to products, develop new and improved products, or provide jobs for more employees. SOURCE: SE:017 SOURCE: SE LAP 117\u2014Sell Away (The Nature and Scope of Selling) "}, {"number": 97, "question": "Why do businesses try to build a clientele? ", "choices": ["A. Leads to repeat business", "B. Gives the business a new image", "C. Attracts well-to-do customers", "D. Provides continuing sources of new workers"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Leads to repeat business. A company's clientele consists of a body of customers upon which the organization can rely for significant repeat business. These are the customers who return to shop regularly. Other benefits of building a clientele include reduced selling costs, increased sales volume, and personal satisfaction. A loyal clientele does not change the business's image, provide it with a source of workers, or attract well-to-do customers. SOURCE: SE:828 SOURCE: SE LAP 115\u2014Keep Them Loyal (Key Factors in Building Clientele) "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Which of the following is a reason why the ethical and legal issues involved in selling activities are extremely important: ", "choices": ["A. Buyers avoid doing business with unethical salespeople.", "B. Sellers must understand how to criticize competitors.", "C. Sales staff must know when they can legally bend the truth.", "D. Sales managers are not responsible for what the sales staff does."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Buyers avoid doing business with unethical salespeople. Unethical salespeople often lose customers and create a negative image of their company. Making erroneous statements about competitors or bending the truth to make a sale are typical examples of unethical sales practices. Sales managers must monitor the practices of their sales staff because they are ultimately responsible for the actions and claims of their staff. SOURCE: SE:106 SOURCE: SE LAP 129\u2014Keep It Real\u2014In Sales (Legal and Ethical Considerations in Selling) Test 1103 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32 "}, {"number": 99, "question": "What type of law prevents salespeople from one company from interfering with their competitions' activities? ", "choices": ["A. Product safety", "B. Unfair trade", "C. Consumer credit", "D. Warranty liability"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Unfair trade. Activities such as stealing a competitor's trade secrets, or attempting to get a competitor's customer to breach a contract, are considered unfair trade practices and are illegal practices in many countries. Consumer protection laws address issues such as product safety, consumer credit, and warranties. SOURCE: SE:108 SOURCE: Investopedia (2014). Unfair trade practice. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/u/unfair-trade-practice.asp "}, {"number": 100, "question": "A restaurant server might obtain valuable information about the taste of a new menu item by talking to ", "choices": ["A. customers.", "B. the cooks.", "C. friends.", "D. suppliers."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Customers. Restaurant customers are often an important source of product information because they have tasted and eaten the menu items. Servers can ask customers if they enjoyed the new menu item and if they would order it again. Customers are usually willing to tell a server if the item was good or if they did not like it and why. Servers can use this information when selling the new menu item to other customers. Suppliers might have information about the various ingredients but not about the taste of a new menu item. The cooks would have an opinion, but it might be biased because they made the menu item. Friends would be able to provide the information only if they were customers. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: SE LAP 131\u2014Get Informed (Acquiring Product Information for Use in Selling"}], "1121-MKT-SAMPLE": [{"number": 1, "question": "One business promising to do something for another business in return for receiving compensation is an example of a ", "choices": ["A. contract.", "B. benefit.", "C. treaty.", "D. enterprise."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Contract. Contracts are agreements among two or more parties stating that one party is to do something in return for something provided by another party. If one business promises to do something for another business in return for receiving compensation, the two businesses have a contract. Then, the businesses are obligated to fulfill their part of the contract. In most cases, contracts benefit both parties, although promising to do something in return for receiving compensation is not necessarily a benefit. Treaties are trade agreements among two or more countries. An enterprise is another term for a business. SOURCE: BL:002 SOURCE: Beatty, J.F., & Samuelson, S.S. (2008). Essentials of business law (3rd ed.) [pp. 211-219]. Mason, OH: Thomson/South-Western. "}, {"number": 2, "question": "When an agent legally acts in the best interests of his/her client, the agent is establishing a(n) __________ relationship. ", "choices": ["A. authoritative", "B. fiduciary", "C. principal", "D. legislative"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Fiduciary. An agent is someone who acts on the behalf of another party. The agent often negotiates contracts and handles legal issues for another person with that person's consent. The agent who shows that s/he is loyal, trustworthy, and acting in the best interest of his/her client (principal) is fostering a fiduciary relationship. Authoritative relationships are based on a particular level of control. Principal is a legal term that describes the client. Legislative processes involve the procedures in which people or governments establish laws. SOURCE: BL:072 SOURCE: Beatty, J.F., & Samuelson, S.S. (2008). Essentials of business law (3rd ed.) [p. 625]. Mason, OH: Thomson/South-Western. "}, {"number": 3, "question": "What do business owners consider when they select a business ownership structure? ", "choices": ["A. Product versatility, advertising strategies, and personal circumstances", "B. Product versatility, financial needs, and advertising strategies", "C. Personal circumstances, type of business, and product mix", "D. Personal circumstances, financial needs, and the type of business"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Personal circumstances, financial needs, and the type of business. Because each business owner's situation is unique, the owner must consider the type of business being operated, the amount of capital that is needed to start the business, and the owner's personal circumstances. For example, an independently wealthy, single person who starts a consulting business has different needs than a chef who has little capital and wants to open a full-service restaurant. Product versatility, advertising strategies, and product mix are not generally considered when determining the appropriate business ownership structure. SOURCE: BL:003 SOURCE: BL LAP 1\u2014Own It Your Way (Types of Business Ownership) "}, {"number": 4, "question": "When businesses want to make their products available to customers but do not want to over-distribute their goods and services, they are seeking ", "choices": ["A. exclusive marketing channels.", "B. ideal market exposure.", "C. direct distribution capabilities.", "D. intense segment coverage."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Ideal market exposure. When a business takes steps to ensure that a product is available to the target market without over-distributing the product, it is seeking ideal market exposure. If product supply is higher than demand, the business loses money on the unsold products. Therefore, businesses strive to obtain ideal market exposure to satisfy demand but not have a surplus of goods. Exclusive and intensive are distribution patterns. The type of distribution pattern that a business uses depends on its ideal market exposure. Direct distribution is a type of distribution channel in which goods and services move directly from the producer to the consumer or industrial user. SOURCE: CM:001 SOURCE: CM LAP 2\u2014Chart Your Channels (Channel Management) "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Cindy's lemonade stand sells lemonade to customers. The route that the lemonade is taking from the producer to the final consumer is ", "choices": ["A. roundabout.", "B. indirect.", "C. direct.", "D. intermediary."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Direct. Direct is a channel of distribution in which goods and services move directly from the producer to the consumer. Indirect is a channel of distribution in which goods and services move from the producer to the channel members and then to consumers or industrial users. Roundabout is not a method of distribution. Intermediaries are channel members who perform the activities needed in getting a good or service from those who produce it to those who consume it. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: CM LAP 3\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15 "}, {"number": 6, "question": "Which of the following often makes it difficult for small manufacturers that have limited budgets to receive an equal opportunity to distribute their new products: ", "choices": ["A. Gray marketing", "B. Slotting allowances", "C. Channel strategies", "D. Targeted advertising"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Slotting allowances. A slotting allowance is a cash premium that manufacturers pay to businesses to cover the costs involved in carrying a new product. In many cases, the cash premium is substantial because there is a lot of competition among manufacturers to encourage businesses to carry their products. Often, the manufacturer that offers the largest allowance is the one that gets shelf space for its new product. This may be unethical because small manufacturers that cannot afford to pay large slotting allowances do not have an equal opportunity to distribute their products. The gray market involves buying from unauthorized distributors. Channel strategies are distribution plans. Targeted advertising involves focusing on a specific group. SOURCE: CM:006 SOURCE: Boone, L.E., & Kurtz, D.L. (2009). Contemporary marketing (p. 446). Mason, OH: SouthWestern Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 7, "question": "A manufacturer that decides to sell directly to large retailers rather than through wholesalers might create __________ conflict within its distribution channel. ", "choices": ["A. formal", "B. horizontal", "C. vertical", "D. conventional"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Vertical. Conflict in a distribution channel occurs when there is disagreement among the various channel members. Vertical conflict occurs when there is disagreement between different levels of the same channel. An example of a vertical channel is a manufacturer selling to wholesalers who then sell to retailers. If the manufacturer decides to bypass the wholesalers and sell directly to retailers or stores, conflict may develop within that vertical channel of distribution because the wholesalers are being eliminated. Horizontal conflict occurs among businesses at the same channel level, such as between different franchisees for the same business competing in the same city. Formal and conventional are not types of channel conflict. SOURCE: CM:008 SOURCE: Etzel, M.J., Walker, B.J., & Stanton, W.J. (2007). Marketing (14th ed.) [pp. 396-400]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin "}, {"number": 8, "question": "The office photocopier is jammed again! Fortunately, there is an instruction manual to guide you through the process of removing the jammed paper. What is the best way to use the manual to clear the photocopier? ", "choices": ["A. Read the entire manual in sequential order and then perform all of the steps in reverse order to\nremove the jammed paper.", "B. Read step one and then perform step one. Repeat this process in sequential order until all of the\nsteps are completed and you have removed the paper.", "C. Briefly skim the manual in reverse order and then follow the steps in sequential order to remove\nthe jammed paper.", "D. Perform the first step, and then verify that you have performed it correctly in the manual. Repeat"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Read step one and then perform step one. Repeat this process in sequential order until all of the steps are completed, and you have removed the paper. When assembling or fixing equipment, it is usually easier to understand directions by reading the step, performing the step, and then moving on to the next step in the sequence. By doing so, you are less likely to hurt yourself or the machine. You are more likely to make mistakes (and more likely to hurt yourself or the machine) if you briefly skim the manual, read the manual before performing the steps, perform the steps in reverse order, or perform the step before reading the instructions. SOURCE: CO:056 SOURCE: eHow. (1999-2015). How to follow written instructions. Retrieved September 3, 2015, from http://www.ehow.com/how_2251998_follow-written-instructions.html "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Asking questions is important because it ", "choices": ["A. helps you become a passive participant in the conversation.", "B. gives you a chance to voice your opinion.", "C. can clear up misunderstandings.", "D. helps your brain process speech more quickly."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Can clear up misunderstandings. Asking questions can help you clarify, understand, and clear up misunderstandings. When you're attempting to listen, it's not the time to voice your opinion. By asking questions, you become an active, not passive, participant in the conversation. While asking questions is beneficial, it doesn't help your brain process speech more quickly. Your brain is actually very efficient already; it can process speech four times as fast as people can talk. SOURCE: CO:017 SOURCE: QS LAP 1\u2014Listening: An Active Process Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16 "}, {"number": 10, "question": "Your supervisor has asked you to prepare a marketing status report for each of the company's six regional offices. The most appropriate way to organize the information is ", "choices": ["A. by site location.", "B. by sales function.", "C. in chronological order.", "D. in reverse sequence."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "By site location. When preparing reports, you should organize the content in the way that will make the most sense to the reader. In the example, the supervisor is asking for a status report for different offices, which indicates that the supervisor will likely want to scan the information by location to quickly review the status of each office or site. Another way to organize the information might be by listing each activity (e.g., advertising, sales) with each site's status included in each activity; however, this format may be cumbersome and difficult to determine each site's status at a glance. Presenting facts in chronological order involves describing steps or historical events in the sequence in which they occur. Reverse sequence involves describing steps or historical events in the opposite order. SOURCE: CO:086 SOURCE: University of Washington. (n.d.). Patterns of organization. Retrieved September 2, 2015, from http://faculty.washington.edu/ezent/impo.htm "}, {"number": 11, "question": "What does an enclosure notation at the bottom of a business letter signify? ", "choices": ["A. Something is being sent with the letter.", "B. Copies of the letter were sent to others.", "C. The sender wishes a reply.", "D. The sender prepared the letter."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Something is being sent with the letter. The word \"Enclosure\" at the bottom of the page indicates that other material accompanies the letter. This lets the recipient know s/he should look for additional material and lets the sender know if the material was not enclosed. Reference initials indicate who prepared a letter. The copy notation (cc) preceding a name (or names) signifies that copies of the letter were sent to persons other than the addressee. A request for a reply is usually included within the body of the letter. SOURCE: CO:133 SOURCE: Purdue Online Writing Lab. (1995-2011). Writing the basic business letter. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/653/01/ "}, {"number": 12, "question": "An effective executive summary ", "choices": ["A. is written for people who won't read the whole document.", "B. includes every point from the business report.", "C. uses technical terminology to show the writer's expertise.", "D. features complex compound sentences."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Is written for people who won't read the whole document. The executive summary is often read by people who simply don't have time to read the entire report. That's why it's so important to make sure your executive summary is as accurate and error-free as possible. You don't need to include every point from the business report\u2014an executive summary should only be about 1/10th the length of the original document. Focus on including only the main points. Avoid using too much technical terminology. The executive summary is often read by people who aren't experts in the field, and it needs to be easily understood by everyone. For the same reason, it's also important to avoid using complex sentences. Remember that the executive summary will often be skimmed by busy people. Help them understand your executive summary by making it as easy-to-read as possible. SOURCE: CO:091 SOURCE: eHow. (2014, October 6). How to write an executive summary. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://www.ehow.com/how_16566_write-executive-summary.html "}, {"number": 13, "question": "A memo on the bulletin board from a supervisor to staff members is an example of __________ communication. ", "choices": ["A. downward", "B. formal", "C. upward", "D. horizontal"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Downward. Downward communication passes information down the chain of command to employees. This is a frequently used form of communication because supervisors must often provide general information to all workers. Horizontal communication is between persons or departments on an equal level. Upward communication moves from employees up to management. Formal communication may move in any direction, but it would be in the form of a letter, report, etc., rather than a bulletin board memo. SOURCE: CO:014 SOURCE: Everard, K.E., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business principles and management (12th ed.) [pp. 247-248]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 14, "question": "When the meeting leader asked the group participants if they had any suggestions for the new product catalog, Lily pulled out a list of notes that she had compiled and talked for the remaining 20 minutes of an hour-long meeting. In this situation, Lily ", "choices": ["A. provided positive feedback.", "B. monopolized the discussion.", "C. followed parliamentary procedure.", "D. expressed her opinions clearly."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Monopolized the discussion. When participating in a staff meeting, it is important to provide information or make suggestions when appropriate. When one person dominates the discussion, others do not have an opportunity to provide their input. Because Lily spoke for a long time during the meeting, she monopolized the discussion. There isn't enough information provided to determine if Lily provided positive feedback, followed parliamentary procedure, or expressed her opinions clearly. SOURCE: CO:063 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (pp. 47-48). Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17 "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Thomas does not know the answer to Mr. O'Malley's question about a complex product. Which of the following is the best way for Thomas to respond to Mr. O'Malley's inquiry: ", "choices": ["A. \"I'll need to read the product manual before I can answer your question, Mr. O'Malley. I'll get\nback to you next week.\"", "B. \"Let me give you the manufacturer's website address. The information is probably available on\nthe product-specifications page.\"", "C. \"I'm not sure, Mr. O'Malley. My coworker, Reggie, knows a lot about this model. If you can wait a\nmoment, I will have him speak with you.\"", "D. \"I don't know. We do have a customer who just purchased this model. I'll get Mrs. Thompson's"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "\"I'm not sure, Mr. O'Malley. My coworker, Reggie, knows a lot about this model. If you can wait a moment, I will have him speak with you.\" If employees do not know the answers to customers' questions, they should try to find another employee who does. This person may be a coworker, supervisor, or an individual who works in another department. To provide good customer service, Thomas should do his best to answer Mr. O'Malley's question as soon as possible. Providing the manufacturer's website address and reading the product manual at a later time are not options that provide prompt customer service. It is inappropriate to give out customers' telephone numbers to others without their permission. SOURCE: CR:006 SOURCE: Arringdale, C. (2009). Respond to customer inquiries and complaints promptly. Retrieved September 2, 2015, from www.hr.com/en/app/blog/2009/04/respond-to-customer-inquiriesand-complaints-promp_ft078ka1.html "}, {"number": 16, "question": "Negative word-of-mouth advertising due to unresolved customer complaints can cost a business its ", "choices": ["A. facilities.", "B. employees.", "C. reputation.", "D. licenses."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Reputation. Negative word-of-mouth advertising due to unresolved customer complaints can cost a business its reputation. Once a reputation has been damaged, it is very difficult to rebuild. Customer complaints should not necessarily cost a business its employees, its facilities, or its licenses. SOURCE: CR:010 SOURCE: CR LAP 10\u2014Righting Wrongs (Handling Customer Complaints) "}, {"number": 17, "question": "How can a business build its customers' trust and communicate its commitment to ethical practices? ", "choices": ["A. Develop liberal business policies", "B. Publish its confidentiality statement", "C. Hire employees who have a positive attitude", "D. Post its earnings on its website"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Publish its confidentiality statement. A business can build its customers' trust by communicating that it will not share its customers' confidential information with third parties and that it will take measures to secure online transactions. One way to communicate this commitment is by publishing its confidentiality statement in company brochures, in email messages, and on its website. Developing liberal business policies, hiring employees who have a positive attitude and posting its earnings on its website may help build trust with customers; however, these actions do not communicate the business's commitment to adhering to its ethics. SOURCE: CR:017 SOURCE: The Vanguard Group. (2014, December). Confidentiality statement. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from https://institutional.vanguard.com/VGApp/iip/site/institutional/confidentialitystatement "}, {"number": 18, "question": "An example of a natural resource is ", "choices": ["A. an electrician.", "B. physical ability.", "C. iron ore.", "D. office equipment."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Iron ore. Natural resources include those things that are provided to us by nature. Office equipment is a capital good. Capital goods are materials used in the production of other goods and services. Physical ability is an example of a labor resource. An electrician is a human resource. SOURCE: EC:003 SOURCE: EC LAP 14\u2014Be Resourceful (Economic Resources) "}, {"number": 19, "question": "Marcy is ready to buy a new computer, and she has saved up enough money to buy the model she wants. Which of the following describes the quantity that Marcy is prepared to buy: ", "choices": ["A. Supply", "B. Elasticity", "C. Demand", "D. Market price"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Demand. In order for demand to exist, consumers must have both the desire and the ability to purchase the product. Supply is the amount of the product that sellers are willing and able to offer for sale at a specified price in a given time period. Market price is the actual price that prevails in a market at any particular moment. Elasticity is an indication of how changes in price will affect changes in the amounts demanded and supplied. SOURCE: EC:005 SOURCE: EC LAP 11\u2014It's the Law (Supply and Demand) "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Businesses are being socially responsible to their customers when they ", "choices": ["A. contribute to community causes.", "B. provide safe working environments.", "C. offer employees job training.", "D. test the safety of their products."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Test the safety of their products. Every business has the responsibility of producing and/or offering safe, quality products. If businesses fail to be sensitive to the well-being of their product users, the businesses will probably fail. Providing safe working environments and offering job training are ways businesses can be socially responsible to their employees. Contributing to community causes demonstrates social responsibility toward the community. SOURCE: EC:070 SOURCE: EC LAP 70\u2014Business Connections (Business and Society) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18 "}, {"number": 21, "question": "One of the freedoms provided to individuals by the private enterprise system is the freedom to choose ", "choices": ["A. which taxes they will pay.", "B. how their employers pay them.", "C. where they will work.", "D. which laws they will obey."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Where they will work. U.S. citizens are free to choose the kind of work they would like to do in order to make a living. They are limited by their own interests, abilities, and training. They are not, however, free to choose which taxes to pay, which laws to obey, or how their employers pay them (e.g., weekly or monthly). SOURCE: EC:009 SOURCE: EC LAP 15\u2014People Power (The Private Enterprise System) "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Operating expenses are defined as the ", "choices": ["A. start-up expenses of a business.", "B. salaries paid to managers.", "C. cost of goods sold.", "D. costs of running a business."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Costs of running a business. Operating expenses are all the costs of running a business on an everyday basis and include such expenditures as payroll, rent, and utilities. Cost of goods sold is the amount of money a business pays for the products it sells or for the raw materials from which it produces goods to sell. Start-up expenses are the costs of opening a new business. Salaries paid to managers are sometimes considered as part of operating expenses. SOURCE: EC:010 SOURCE: EC LAP 2\u2014Risk Rewarded (Factors Affecting Profit) "}, {"number": 23, "question": "How does increased business productivity benefit consumers? ", "choices": ["A. More goods and services become available, so prices go down.", "B. More goods and services become available, so prices go up.", "C. Costs of labor and prices increase, so inflation goes up.", "D. The gross domestic product goes down, so inflation goes up."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "More goods and services become available, so prices go down. Increased business productivity can create a greater variety of goods and services, and as more products become available, prices are likely to drop. Increased business productivity reduces inflation and increases the gross domestic product per capita. SOURCE: EC:013 SOURCE: EC LAP 18\u2014Make the Most of It (Productivity) "}, {"number": 24, "question": "Long-term unemployment may affect an individual by ", "choices": ["A. improving mental health.", "B. eroding his/her skills.", "C. increasing protectionism.", "D. building savings."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Eroding his/her skills. Long-term unemployment may affect an individual by eroding his/her skills, making it even more difficult to find a job in the future. Unemployment usually does not help a person to build savings or improve her/his mental health. Increased protectionism is an effect of unemployment on the nation and the economy. SOURCE: EC:082 SOURCE: EC LAP 29\u2014Help Wanted? (Impact of Unemployment Rates) "}, {"number": 25, "question": "During periods of economic expansion, businesses are likely to ", "choices": ["A. increase their production.", "B. reduce their profits.", "C. stop hiring workers.", "D. benefit from high interest rates."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Increase their production. Expansion is a phase of the business cycle characterized by increased spending and borrowing, increased demand for goods and services, increased employment rates, and decreased interest rates on loans. During an expansion phase, businesses are likely to increase their production in order to meet increased consumer demand. Increased production usually results in increased profits. SOURCE: EC:018 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 64-67). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Which of the following is a reason to avoid drawing distinctions between people: ", "choices": ["A. Certain people don't deserve respect.", "B. Discrimination is illegal.", "C. Some people aren't \"normal.\"", "D. Everyone is unique."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Everyone is unique. There's no reason to draw distinctions between people because everyone is unique. There's no such thing as \"normal.\" Everyone deserves to be treated with kindness and respect. In many cases, discrimination is illegal, but drawing distinctions between people is something that happens on a personal level and can only be controlled by ourselves. SOURCE: EI:021 SOURCE: EI LAP 21\u2014Make the Honor Role (Acting Responsibly) "}, {"number": 27, "question": "People with a positive attitude are open-minded, which helps them to ", "choices": ["A. develop patience.", "B. remain cheerful.", "C. learn new skills.", "D. be intolerant."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Learn new skills. People with a positive attitude are open-minded and receptive to new ideas and new ways of doing things. This makes it easier for them to learn new skills, techniques, and methods. Being open-minded does not help individuals to remain cheerful or to develop patience. Being intolerant is the result of a negative attitude. SOURCE: EI:019 SOURCE: EI LAP 3\u2014Opt for Optimism (Positive Attitude) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19 "}, {"number": 28, "question": "Ideally, in business, feedback should be ", "choices": ["A. all positive.", "B. all negative.", "C. positive and negative.", "D. avoided if possible."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Positive and negative. Too much positive feedback provides no guidance for improvement in job performance. At the same time, too much negative feedback becomes depressing and creates a poor attitude in workers. Therefore, there should be a mix of positive and negative feedback. SOURCE: EI:003 SOURCE: EI LAP 15\u2014Grin and Bear It (Using Feedback for Personal Growth) "}, {"number": 29, "question": "The main reason many individuals resist change is ", "choices": ["A. decisiveness.", "B. fear.", "C. discipline.", "D. self-confidence."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Fear. Regardless of whether the change is great or small, many people seem to fear and resist change. Any change has the potential to threaten a person's security. People who are decisive, disciplined, and self-confident may still fear change, but these traits help them to overcome their fears and make necessary changes. SOURCE: EI:026 SOURCE: Quast, L. (2012, November 26). Overcome the 5 main reasons people resist change. Retrieved September 14, 2015, from http://www.forbes.com/sites/lisaquast/2012/11/26/overcome-the-5-main-reasons-peopleresist-change/ "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Molly offers to take her new coworker out to lunch. She remembers what it was like when she was a new employee two years ago, and she wants to help her new coworker feel comfortable and welcome. What trait is Molly showing towards her new coworker? ", "choices": ["A. Tact", "B. Empathy", "C. Sympathy", "D. Judgment"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Empathy. Empathy is the ability to put yourself in another person's place or to see a situation from another person's point of view. Molly can understand how her coworker feels because she was in the same situation two years ago\u2014that's empathy. Tact is the ability to do or say the right thing in any circumstances. When you speak tactfully, you consider your words carefully before saying them. It's important that Molly speak tactfully to her new coworker, but that's not what she's doing in this example. Sympathy is the ability to recognize another person's feelings. If Molly simply felt sorry for her coworker's situation, she would be sympathetic. However, Molly actually understands what it's like to be in her coworker's position, so she's being empathetic. Molly is not judging her new coworker\u2014being empathetic means not being judgmental. SOURCE: EI:030 SOURCE: EI LAP 12\u2014Have a Heart (Showing Empathy for Others) "}, {"number": 31, "question": "When Cynthia, a credit analyst with Houghton Software, heard rumors of a company layoff, she asked her manager Todd if the rumors were true and if her job was in jeopardy. Although Todd knew that some lay-offs were coming, he told Cynthia not to worry about things. The following week, Cynthia's job was eliminated. In this situation, ethical issues regarding company information occurred because ", "choices": ["A. Todd misled Cynthia.", "B. Cynthia asked irrelevant questions.", "C. Todd was completely honest with Cynthia.", "D. Cynthia started the rumors."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Todd misled Cynthia. Although Todd may have meant well when he told Cynthia not to worry, he misled her by making Cynthia think that her job was safe. A better response may have been that he didn't have all the facts about the layoffs and did not want to speculate about Cynthia's position. This statement would have been true if Todd did not know who was going to be laid off. While Cynthia's questions put Todd in an uncomfortable position, they were relevant to the rumors. Cynthia heard about the layoff rumors\u2014she didn't start them. SOURCE: EI:038 SOURCE: Tahmincioglu, E. (2009, November 30). Recession adds fuel to workplace gossip. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/34149723/ns/businesscareers/t/recession-adds-fuel-workplace-gossip/ "}, {"number": 32, "question": "When trying to persuade others, it is often helpful to use stories and anecdotes because they ", "choices": ["A. exaggerate the benefits.", "B. make people feel comfortable.", "C. add energy to your explanation.", "D. reinforce your message."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Reinforce your message. Use stories and anecdotes to reinforce your message with word pictures and examples that others can understand easily. If you can paint a picture in people's minds, they will be able to understand your ideas. Also, stories are interesting and easy to remember. People are often able to relate to them on a personal level. The use of appropriate body language often makes people feel comfortable. Use your voice to add energy to your explanation. You should not exaggerate the benefits. SOURCE: EI:012 SOURCE: EI LAP 121\u2014Win Them Over (Persuading Others) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20 "}, {"number": 33, "question": "\"I can't agree to your terms until I discuss the situation with my manager.\" This is an example of the __________ negotiating strategy. ", "choices": ["A. limited authority", "B. good cop/bad cop", "C. deadline-driven", "D. bargaining"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Limited authority. Limited authority is a negotiating strategy in which one person claims that s/he does not have the authority to make a decision and must consult another person who is not present during the negotiation process. Good cop/Bad cop is a negotiating strategy that involves at least two people on one side of the negotiation; of the two people, one person is reasonable and agrees with the opposing party, while the other is unreasonable and disagrees with the opposing party. The deadline-driven strategy involves one party giving the other party a time limit to take action. Bargaining is a negotiating technique that involves giving one person something s/he wants, and receiving something desired in return. SOURCE: EI:062 SOURCE: EI LAP 8\u2014Make It a Win-Win (Negotiation in Business) "}, {"number": 34, "question": "When Trish learned that her company was switching to a new computer-software program, she accepted the change and worked overtime to become familiar with the new program. Trish exhibited __________ behavior. ", "choices": ["A. adaptable", "B. stubborn", "C. passive", "D. irresponsible"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Adaptable. An adaptable person has the ability to adjust to changing conditions. To adjust to changes, a person must accept the fact that changes happen all the time under many types of circumstances. Once you accept that changes happen all the time, you learn to feel more comfortable when changes occur. In the example, Trish was adaptable because she understood that changes occur at work, and she took steps to adjust to the change by working overtime to become familiar with the new computer program. A stubborn person might resist change for a variety of reasons such as fear, contentment, or a lack of trust. Not only did Trish exhibit adaptable behavior, she exhibited assertive, responsible behavior by working to become familiar with the software. SOURCE: EI:006 SOURCE: EI LAP 23\u2014Go With the Flow (Demonstrating Adaptability) "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Mike is thinking about expanding his manufacturing business internationally. Which of the following is a risk he might encounter: ", "choices": ["A. Dealing with cultural and language barriers", "B. Encountering new markets", "C. Dealing with fewer government regulations", "D. Saving money on taxes"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Dealing with cultural and language barriers. If Mike expands his business internationally, he may run into problems if he doesn't do enough research into the other country's culture. He may also have a problem if he doesn't know the other country's language. Encountering new markets would be an advantage of expanding internationally. Depending on which country he expands to, Mike could have fewer government regulations and he could save money on taxes, but these would be considered advantages. SOURCE: EN:041 SOURCE: Arthur, L. (2015). The advantages and disadvantages of international franchises. Retrieved September 3, 2015, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/advantages-disadvantagesinternational-franchises-22488.html "}, {"number": 36, "question": "About a week before her 16th birthday, Kimberly got a phone call from her grandparents. They explained that they wanted to give her $1,000 to put toward college expenses as a birthday present, but they weren't sure if she wanted the money now or in two years, when she would be starting college. Kimberly decided to get the $1,000 from her grandparents right away and put it into an interest-bearing savings account for two years. Kimberly based her decision on ", "choices": ["A. the capital gains potential.", "B. the concept of absolute advantage.", "C. the time value of money.", "D. foreign exchange rate."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "The time value of money. Kimberly understands that the $1,000 available to her now is worth more than the same $1,000 two years from now. By placing the $1,000 in a savings account now, she can earn interest on that $1,000. So, in two years, she will have more than $1,000 to put toward her college expenses. The absolute advantage is the advantage achieved when a nation can produce a good or service for less than another nation. Capital gains are earnings from the appreciation of a stock investment, and Kimberly is not purchasing stock with the money. The foreign exchange rate is the value of a currency in relation to another currency at a given time. SOURCE: FI:062 SOURCE: Kapoor, J.R., Dlabay, L.R., & Hughes, R.J. (2009). Personal finance (9th ed.) [pp. 15-19, 30-36]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21 "}, {"number": 37, "question": "When the Silvers purchased their new car, the dealership representative sold their contract to another company in exchange for cash. To what type of business would the dealership have sold the Silvers' contract? ", "choices": ["A. Commercial bank", "B. Savings and loan association", "C. Finance company", "D. Credit union"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Finance company. To receive cash in exchange for the Silvers' contract, the dealership dealt with a sales finance company. This is a business that purchases borrowers' contracts from sellers and receives the borrowers' payments. A credit union is a financial cooperative set up to provide savings and credit services to its members. It usually operates within a business or a labor union. A savings and loan association is a financial institution that offers savings accounts and makes loans to borrowers. Most of the loans are for real estate purchases. Commercial banks are full-service banks offering a variety of banking services, including checking and savings accounts, secured and unsecured loans, installment credit, and bank credit cards. SOURCE: FI:002 SOURCE: Crawford, C. (2015). What are the primary functions of finance companies? Retrieved September 2, 2015, from http://smallbusiness.chron.com/primary-functions-financecompanies-40480.html "}, {"number": 38, "question": "A good way to prioritize your financial goals is to ", "choices": ["A. rank every goal in numerical order.", "B. rank goals according to what needs to be done first.", "C. assign each goal to a general category.", "D. recognize that all the goals are equally important."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Assign each goal to a general category. A good way to prioritize your financial goals is to assign each goal to a general category, such as \"must do,\" \"important but not critical,\" or \"not so important.\" Ranking according to what needs to be done first and ranking every goal in numerical order are two common pitfalls. Another pitfall is ranking everything as very important or thinking that all the goals are equally important. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up "}, {"number": 39, "question": "Caitlin has three credit cards. She receives her credit card statement for one of the cards and has to decide how to pay the $500 she spent with that card. To pay the least for use of the credit, she should pay with __________ and make the __________ payment. ", "choices": ["A. cash; full", "B. cash; minimum", "C. another card; full", "D. another card; minimum"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Cash; full. Paying the statement in full will assure that she does not have to pay extra interest on the balance and will help improve her credit history. Paying in cash is better for her credit history's health than paying with another card, because eventually she will have to pay the money owed on the other card. Paying for one card with another can lead to a downward spiral of credit card debt. SOURCE: FI:071 SOURCE: Evolve Money. (2014, August 13). 5 simple ways for college students to stay out of credit trouble. Retrieved September 2, 2015, from www.evolvemoney.com/2014/08/13/bad-creditcollege-students "}, {"number": 40, "question": "Kendra 's financial goal is to build wealth over time by making diversified investments. Which of the following financial services providers is most likely to help Kendra achieve her goal: ", "choices": ["A. Financial-auditing firm", "B. Mortgage company", "C. Investment bank", "D. Asset-management firm"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Asset-management firm. Asset-management firms invest their clients' money in different (diversified) securities by pooling assets. This is beneficial to investors who do not have the financial resources and expertise to obtain securities on their own. Asset-management firms typically manage mutual funds, hedge funds, and pension plans. An investment bank is a financial intermediary that underwrites securities and facilitates mergers. Mortgage companies process loans specifically designed for the purchase of real estate\u2014land, residences, and other types of buildings. Certified Public Accounting firms perform independent financial audits for different types of businesses (e.g., public corporations). SOURCE: FI:075 SOURCE: Finance Maps of the World. (2012, May 4). Top asset management firms. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://finance.mapsofworld.com/financial-institutions/stockbrokerage/top-asset-management-firms.html "}, {"number": 41, "question": "One of the basic risks in marketing is the possibility of __________ loss. ", "choices": ["A. impersonal", "B. political", "C. financial", "D. promotional"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Financial. Financial loss, or the loss of money, is the basic risk in marketing. While it is impossible to eliminate all risk in marketing, there are several ways to reduce risk including developing effective marketing plans, information systems, financial plans, and loss-prevention plans. To the owner of a marketing business, any risk is personal rather than impersonal. Promotional expenditures could cause financial loss in some cases. Most marketing businesses are not involved in political activities. SOURCE: SM:075 SOURCE: FI LAP 8\u2014Prepare for the Worst; Expect the Best (Nature of Risk Management) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22 "}, {"number": 42, "question": "What technology is the most effective way to interview a job applicant who is located 1,500 miles away from the company's corporate office? ", "choices": ["A. Text messaging", "B. Videoconferencing", "C. Web-based email", "D. Intranet"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Videoconferencing. Holding a video conference allows the interviewer to see the applicant and his/her reactions to the questions. Text messaging and email applications involve typing on a smartphone or a computer. These methods are time consuming and do not allow the interviewer to see or hear the applicant. An intranet is a business's internal computer network. SOURCE: HR:412 SOURCE: eHow.com (2015). How to prepare for a Skype interview. Retrieved September 9, 2015, from http://www.ehow.com/how_5648281_prepare-skype-interview.html "}, {"number": 43, "question": "To protect the integrity of the marketing information they gather, businesses should avoid ", "choices": ["A. working with a publisher.", "B. paying for the data.", "C. surveying a lot of people.", "D. manipulating the research."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Manipulating the research. Businesses can protect the integrity of the marketing information they collect by interpreting the research correctly and not manipulating it in such a way that it agrees with a predetermined conclusion. Protecting the integrity of marketing information is sometimes difficult because businesses often can make the research support either side of an issue depending on how they interpret it. Most businesses try to interpret the research correctly because consumers are sometimes suspicious of research findings that seem to support the opinions of the business that sponsors the research. Many businesses pay research organizations to collect and analyze data. Surveying a lot of people usually adds to the integrity of marketing information because a broad audience was involved. Working with a publisher does not affect the integrity of marketing information. SOURCE: IM:025 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [p. 95]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 44, "question": "What is the device that a business's employees use to obtain information about customers who access the business's website? ", "choices": ["A. Bookmarks", "B. Browsers", "C. Spiders", "D. Cookies"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Cookies. Some website computers place information, a \"cookie,\" on a user's hard drive when the user visits the site. The next time a user visits that site, the site's computer recognizes the user because of the cookie. Marketing-information employees use cookies to maintain user information and track how many times a user visits a specific website or buys a product. This type of data allows marketing-information employees to customize websites in order to appeal to the preferences and habits of the consumers who are visiting their sites. A browser is software that allows a computer to access information on the Internet. Spiders are a type of search tool. A bookmark is a term used to describe a website that is marked for later reference. SOURCE: IM:183 SOURCE: Indiana University. (2015, March 12). What are cookies? Retrieved September 2, 2015, from https://kb.iu.edu/d/agwm "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Which of the following is essential to all marketing research: ", "choices": ["A. Secondary data", "B. Primary data", "C. Frequency", "D. Accuracy"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Accuracy. Accuracy is absolutely essential in gathering, recording, and analyzing marketing-research data if the data are to be of value to the business. Inaccurate data can cause the business to make incorrect or unwise decisions. The frequency with which research is conducted would depend upon the needs of the business. Primary data are facts collected specifically for the problem or project at hand. Secondary data are facts that have been collected for purposes other than the project at hand. A marketing-research project may require either or both kinds of data. SOURCE: IM:010 SOURCE: IM LAP 5\u2014Seek and Find (Nature of Marketing Research) "}, {"number": 46, "question": "Which of the following is a true statement about marketing-research studies: ", "choices": ["A. Lower level employees should not be involved in marketing-research studies.", "B. Marketing-research studies should be conducted once per year.", "C. Each marketing-research study is unique.", "D. Marketing-research studies are difficult to conduct."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Each marketing-research study is unique. Each business and marketing-research study is unique, but there are a few common ways that managers and researchers work together to define the problem clearly and correctly. Marketing-research studies can be conducted more or less than once per year. Lower level employees may be very helpful with marketing-research studies. Marketing-research studies need not be difficult to conduct, especially with experienced researchers on hand. SOURCE: IM:282 SOURCE: IM LAP 13\u2014What's the Problem (Marketing-Research Problems) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23 "}, {"number": 47, "question": "Which of the following is true about a survey-sampling plan: ", "choices": ["A. Tends to have extremely low error rates", "B. Eliminates respondent bias", "C. Is more reliable than observation", "D. Represents a larger group"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Represents a larger group. A sampling plan is the course of action for gathering marketing information from a section or portion of a target market. A business gathers data from a portion of the target market because the market is often too large to obtain data from each market member. Therefore, researchers use the sample group's responses to represent the larger group's opinions and ideas. Sampling plans use different methods to select and gather information. The marketing-research issue or problem and the way the sample data are collected influence but do not eliminate the respondents' bias and error rates. Observation is a method of collecting primary data, which may or may not be more reliable than other research methods. SOURCE: IM:285 SOURCE: IM LAP 16\u2014Take Your Pick (Sampling Plans) "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Which of the following is an example of quantitative data: ", "choices": ["A. \"Tara is a great tutor.\"", "B. \u201cTara is one of the smartest kids in school.\u201d", "C. \u201cI heard Tara is applying to Harvard!\u201d", "D. \u201cTara graduated first in her class.\u201d"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "\"Tara graduated first in her class.\" Tara's class ranking is quantitative data. It's a statistical fact. The other statements are based on opinion or experience. They are examples of qualitative data. SOURCE: IM:289 SOURCE: IM LAP 17\u2014Hunting and Gathering (Data-Collection Methods) "}, {"number": 49, "question": "What device helps to ensure that direct-observation research is collected in a neutral way? ", "choices": ["A. Fax machine", "B. Global-orientation system", "C. Video camera", "D. DVD player"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Video camera. Direct-observation research is a type of marketing research that involves watching customers' in real time to assess their behaviors. For example, a business may want to watch its customers' shopping habits and browsing patterns to determine if the business is merchandising its products effectively. The business may have a researcher use a video camera to record the customers' behavior so that the researcher can review it later in detail. A global-orientation system, a fax machine, and a DVD player are not direct-observation methods that researchers use to collect data in a neutral way. SOURCE: IM:418 SOURCE: Cerka, M. (2008, May 19). What is observation in marketing research? Retrieved September 2, 2015, from www.observation360.blogspot.com "}, {"number": 50, "question": "Out of 25 survey respondents, 16 people rate a product's durability at five on a rating scale ranging from one to seven. What measure of central tendency does the number five represent? ", "choices": ["A. Disbursement", "B. Median", "C. Mode", "D. Deviation"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Mode. Mode is the answer to a question that respondents give most often. In the situation described, most respondents rated the product's durability at five on the marketing research survey, which makes the number five the mode. A median is the middle value of the established sample criteria. This means that half of the data or responses are below the median value and half are above the median value. Disbursement and deviation are not measures of central tendency. SOURCE: IM:191 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 444-446]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 51, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a response error: ", "choices": ["A. Lydia provides her opinion about a new soft drink during a focus group.", "B. Jack does not provide his telephone number when he fills out an online survey.", "C. Rosanna checks two response options for one question on a paper questionnaire.", "D. Jack pauses for a moment before he answers the interviewer's question."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Rosanna checks two response options for one question on a paper questionnaire. A response error occurs when a respondent provides an incorrect answer or response. Response errors often occur when respondents do not understand the question or when they hurry to complete the survey and do not read instructions or questions carefully. Because Rosanna provides two responses or answers for one question, the questionnaire contains a response error. A non-response error occurs when a respondent does not answer all of the questions in a survey. Because Jack does not provide his telephone number, the survey contains a non-response error. Providing an opinion during a focus group and pausing before answering a question are not examples of errors. SOURCE: IM:292 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 491-496]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24 "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Marketing has an effect on the quality of life and general living conditions of consumers, referred to as their ", "choices": ["A. value system.", "B. buying power.", "C. buying habits.", "D. standard of living."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Standard of living. Standard of living is the way or manner in which people live. It is usually measured by the quality and quantity of the goods and services that people own and use. Consumers' buying power is the amount of money they have available to spend. Buying habits are the customary ways in which people make purchases. A value system is based on ethics or principles. SOURCE: MK:001 SOURCE: MK LAP 4\u2014Have It Your Way! (Nature of Marketing) "}, {"number": 53, "question": "Increasing membership by 25% during the next year might be one of the __________ of a health club. ", "choices": ["A. principles", "B. strategies", "C. tactics", "D. goals"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Goals. Goals are things or objectives that businesses want to attain. Increasing membership by 25% during the next year is a specific goal. Strategies are plans of action for achieving goals and objectives. Tactics are specific actions that will be used to carry out strategies. Principles refer to rules of conduct. SOURCE: MP:001 SOURCE: MP LAP 2\u2014Pick the Mix (Marketing Strategies) "}, {"number": 54, "question": "Maria is developing her marketing plan for her small, but growing, business. She notes that one of the advantages of her company is that her staff is highly creative and flexible; however, a primary limitation that she faces is that she does not have sufficient financial resources to expand her product line. In which component of the marketing plan would Maria place this information? ", "choices": ["A. Financial statement", "B. Promotional plan", "C. Marketing mix", "D. SWOT analysis"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "SWOT analysis. A marketing plan is a set of procedures or strategies for attracting the target customer to a business. A component of the marketing plan is the SWOT analysis, which describes the businesses strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats. Because Maria is describing one of her business's strengths (highly creative and flexible staff) and one of her business's weaknesses (lack of financial resources), she is working on the SWOT analysis. The promotional plan is the set of procedures or strategies for the business's promotional efforts. The marketing mix is the four elements of marketing\u2014 product, place, promotion, and price. A financial statement is a summary of accounting information. SOURCE: MP:007 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [pp. 544, 548-549]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. "}, {"number": 55, "question": "Which of the following is one element of a situation analysis: ", "choices": ["A. Marketing planning", "B. Environmental scanning", "C. Sales positioning", "D. Organizational testing"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Environmental scanning. A situation analysis is a determination of a firm's current business situation and the direction in which the business is headed. One element of a situation analysis is environmental scanning which involves collecting information about the environment surrounding the business. By scanning the external environment, the business can identify changes that may have an impact on the business. These changes may present threats to the business or opportunities for the business that the business considers during the marketing planning process. Businesses conduct a situation analysis as part of the marketing planning process. Sales positioning and organizational testing are not elements of a situation analysis. SOURCE: MP:008 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (p. 35). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 56, "question": "One way for businesses to obtain needed information efficiently is to ", "choices": ["A. read a book.", "B. schedule an interview.", "C. access a database.", "D. contact a competitor."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Access a database. A database is computerized storage for information and facts. Most businesses maintain a database of information that is relevant to the business, such as lists of customers and vendors, inventory levels, prices of materials, etc. When businesses need information, they access the database to obtain the data efficiently. For example, a business could access a database to find out how many customers in a certain area purchased a specific product during a specified time period. Scheduling an interview, reading a book, and contacting a competitor are not ways for businesses to obtain needed information efficiently. SOURCE: NF:078 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., Thill, J.V., & Mescon, M.H. (2007). Excellence in business (3rd ed.) [pp. 134-135]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25 "}, {"number": 57, "question": "Using a computer-generated slideshow to highlight product information would be most appropriate in which of the following business situations: ", "choices": ["A. Union contract negotiations", "B. Project-team status meeting", "C. Employee performance review", "D. Formal sales presentation"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Formal sales presentation. Presentation software is often used to provide visual support for oral presentations. Presentation software is often used during sales presentations to provide customers or prospective customers with visual information about the product's attributes and benefits. Graphic depictions of products are especially useful for items that cannot be easily transported to other locations because the audience can see an image of the product. Status meetings, employee performance reviews, and union contract negotiations are not the most appropriate business situations in which to use a computer-generated slideshow to highlight product information. The purpose of a status meeting is to update the team about various aspects of a project. An employee performance review is a tool to provide workers with feedback about their work efforts. Union contract negotiations occur when management and labor representatives meet to reach agreement about the workers' pay, benefits, working conditions, etc. SOURCE: NF:080 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2009). Marketing essentials (pp. 201-202). Woodland Hills, CA: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 58, "question": "Information usually comes in either physical form or __________ form. ", "choices": ["A. electronic", "B. book", "C. note card", "D. verbal"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Electronic. Information usually comes in either physical form (anything on paper) or electronic form (emails, videos, spreadsheets, etc.). Book, note card, and verbal are not typical forms of information that a business must manage. SOURCE: NF:110 SOURCE: NF LAP 3\u2014In the Know (Nature of Information Management) "}, {"number": 59, "question": "After The IWP Company receives online orders from its customers, it quickly replies to all of its customers with the following email message: \"Thank you for your order. It will be processed within the next 48 hours.\" The email function that generates these types of messages is called a(n) ", "choices": ["A. instant message.", "B. autoresponder.", "C. mechanical reaction.", "D. timed reply."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Autoresponder. Autoresponder is a computer program that automatically returns a specified message to anyone who emailed a particular address. The autoresponder function is a way for a business to quickly acknowledge the customer's message and to let him/her know that the company is going to take action within a certain timeframe. It is a way to provide customer service. Instant messaging is a computer program that allows one or more individuals to send typed messages via the computer in real time. Mechanical-reaction and timed reply are fictitious terms. SOURCE: NF:004 SOURCE: PCMAG.com. (n.d.). Auto-responder. Retrieved December 22, 2009, from http://www.pcmag.com/encyclopedia/term/38228/auto-responder "}, {"number": 60, "question": "What type of software program do businesses use to create text documents? ", "choices": ["A. Communications", "B. Web-page editor", "C. Word processing", "D. Presentation"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Word processing. Most word-processing software programs are designed to be used to create text documents, although some have limited graphic capabilities. Businesses use word-processing software programs to write letters, memos, reports, business plans, and sales contracts. There are many different word-processing software programs available that enable businesses to create, edit, and store important text documents. Presentation software programs are used to develop visual presentations. Web-page editors are software applications that businesses use to create web pages. Communications software programs allow computers to communicate with other computers. SOURCE: NF:007 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 213-216). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 61, "question": "Why is it important for hospitality and tourism businesses to be aware of, and react to, trends and changes in the marketplace? ", "choices": ["A. To identify resources", "B. To increase advertising", "C. To hire personnel", "D. To remain competitive"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To remain competitive. The business world is constantly changing, and new trends come and go on a regular basis. Businesses need to pay attention to trends and adjust accordingly in order to remain competitive. Business as usual is not effective in today's fast-paced and changing environment. The businesses that adapt and keep up with new trends are the ones that remain successful. Experimenting with new types of advertising is usually more effective than merely increasing the amount of advertising. Businesses do not need to be aware of new trends in order to hire personnel or identify resources. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Perreault, W.D., Cannon, J.P., & McCarthy, E.J. (2008). Basic marketing: A marketing strategy planning approach (16th ed.) [p. 654]. Boston: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26 "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Which of the following would be done first in an environmental scan: ", "choices": ["A. Identifying and analyzing important trends and issues", "B. Carrying out scanning activities", "C. Selecting trends and issues to act on", "D. Identifying participants and responsibilities"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Identifying participants and responsibilities. The first step in conducting an environmental scan is to identify participants and their responsibilities. Every employee should participate, although some employees may have more formal duties than others. After this step has been completed, businesses can move on to carrying out scanning activities, identifying and analyzing important trends and issues, and selecting trends and issues to act on. SOURCE: NF:015 SOURCE: NF LAP 2\u2014Get the 411 (Environmental Scanning) "}, {"number": 63, "question": "The difference between service providers' and manufacturers' operations activities is that service providers produce __________ outputs. ", "choices": ["A. expensive", "B. intangible", "C. useful", "D. tangible"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Intangible. The difference between service providers' and manufacturers' operations activities is that service providers produce intangible outputs, rather than the tangible goods that manufacturers create. The outputs may or may not be expensive or useful. SOURCE: OP:189 SOURCE: OP LAP 189\u2014Smooth Operations (Nature of Operations) "}, {"number": 64, "question": "What should an employee do when s/he accidentally spills coffee in the tile hallway? ", "choices": ["A. Tell others about the spill", "B. Wait for the floor to dry", "C. Wipe it up immediately", "D. Leave it for the cleaning crew"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Wipe it up immediately. Spills may make the floor slippery and create a safety hazard. Others may not notice the spill, fall on the wet surface, and suffer injuries. All employees are responsible for helping to maintain a safe environment. They should not wait for the floor to dry, tell others about the spill, or leave it for the cleaning crew. SOURCE: OP:007 SOURCE: Root, G.N. III. (2015). What are some workplace safety issues? Retrieved September 2nd, 2015, from smallbusiness.chron.com/workplace-safety-issues-1303.html "}, {"number": 65, "question": "The most important reason why workplace accidents which do not result in injuries should be reported to supervisors is because ", "choices": ["A. the next accident could result in an injury.", "B. this is required by state law.", "C. the report prevents future liability.", "D. this is an OSHA requirement."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The next accident could result in an injury. The fact that one accident does not result in an injury does not ensure that the next accident will have the same results. An accident that does not cause an injury should be reported to a supervisor so that the circumstances causing the accident can be corrected if possible. This may save someone else from injury. Government regulations vary from state to state and for different industries. Reporting a noninjurious accident does not prevent future liability. SOURCE: OP:009 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [pp. 565-566]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co. "}, {"number": 66, "question": "A business can protect its confidential computer information from unauthorized users by ", "choices": ["A. developing Internet message boards.", "B. encrypting computer files.", "C. conducting annual virus scans.", "D. classifying business data."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Encrypting computer files. Encryption is the process of transforming information into a secret code so that only specified individuals can read it. By encrypting confidential computer files, the business protects the information from unauthorized access by internal and external sources. For optimal protection from computer viruses, businesses should conduct computer virus scans continuously rather than once a year. Activities such as classifying information and developing Internet message boards do not protect the information from unauthorized users. SOURCE: OP:153 SOURCE: Stemp, M. (2015, January 27). Protect confidential information\u2014encrypt it! Retrieved September 14, 2015, from http://stempsystems.com/protect-confidential-client-informationencrypt/ "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Which of the following is a purpose of the competitive bidding process: ", "choices": ["A. To attract product champions", "B. To increase competition for products", "C. To obtain lower prices from bidders", "D. To limit the number of vendors to pick from"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To obtain lower prices from bidders. By using a competitive bidding process, businesses can obtain lower prices from vendors, thereby decreasing their overall product costs. Competitive bidding occurs between businesses so that businesses obtain better services as well as better products/materials/components. The process should encourage as many vendors as possible to attempt to get a contract rather than limiting the number of vendors to pick from. Competition and product champions are not related to the competitive bidding process. SOURCE: OP:160 SOURCE: Universal Service Administrative Company. (1997-2015). Competitive bidding. Retrieved September 14, 2015, from http://www.usac.org/sl/applicants/step02/competitive-bidding.aspx Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27 "}, {"number": 68, "question": "Which of the following expenses should Charlene categorize as a fixed cost: ", "choices": ["A. Cost of goods sold", "B. Delivery charges", "C. Rent", "D. Commissions"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Rent. Fixed costs are business expenses that do not change with changes in sales volume. Fixed costs include items such as salaries, rent, mortgage, and property taxes. Variable costs are business costs that change and include commission, delivery charges, and cost of goods sold. SOURCE: OP:024 SOURCE: Business Owners Toolkit. (1995-2011). Fixed and variable costs. Retrieved March 3, 2011, from http://www.toolkit.com/small_business_guide/sbg.aspx?nid=P06_7510 "}, {"number": 69, "question": "Employees who never take company supplies or equipment, such as pens or tools, for their own use help the business to ", "choices": ["A. control expenses.", "B. increase profits.", "C. control shoplifting.", "D. reduce external theft."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Control expenses. Employees can play a role in controlling business expense by not appropriating company property. The business should explain to employees that controlling expenses helps the business to increase its profits. External theft occurs when items are stolen by persons outside the company or shoplifted by customers. SOURCE: OP:025 SOURCE: OP LAP 5\u2014Buck Busters (Employee Role in Expense Control) "}, {"number": 70, "question": "Which of the following do businesses often expect employees to make on their own: ", "choices": ["A. Operating plans", "B. Policy changes", "C. Routine decisions", "D. Personnel choices"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Routine decisions. Employees need to make routine decisions every day on the job. Businesses expect them to be capable of making many of these decisions on their own without asking a manager what to do. Businesses do not want to waste valuable time directing every action that employees take. They expect employees to make routine decisions that will allow them to work effectively, oftentimes with little supervision. Businesses do not expect employees to make policy changes, operating plans, or personnel choices. SOURCE: PD:017 SOURCE: PD LAP 10\u2014Weigh Your Options (Decision Making) "}, {"number": 71, "question": "Beau is really stressed out because he agreed to take on three new clients that he really didn't have room for. Which time-management principle does he need to learn? ", "choices": ["A. Divide large projects into smaller parts", "B. Get enough sleep", "C. Focus on goals, not on tasks", "D. Don't bite off more than you can chew"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Don't bite off more than you can chew. Beau needs to learn not to bite off more than he can chew. Taking on more clients than he can handle means he really won't give his best effort to any of them. Beau's problem isn't relating to focusing on goals, getting enough sleep, or dividing a large project into smaller parts. SOURCE: PD:019 SOURCE: PD LAP 1\u2014About Time (Time Management) "}, {"number": 72, "question": "What type of information is it acceptable to leave out of a job application? ", "choices": ["A. Contact information", "B. Educational background", "C. Salary requirements", "D. Professional experience"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Salary requirements. It is not necessary for applicants to specify their salary requirements on a job application. Applicants usually want to have the opportunity to discuss salary in person rather than run the risk of asking for too much or too little before obtaining an interview. Educational background, contact information, and professional experience are examples of the types of information that should be included in a job application. SOURCE: PD:027 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed.) [p. 47]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. "}, {"number": 73, "question": "Why will it benefit you to learn as much as possible about a prospective employer before you go for a job interview? ", "choices": ["A. It ensures that you'll be considered for the job.", "B. It shows that you do a lot of reading.", "C. It prepares you to ask good questions.", "D. It gives you something to discuss during the interview."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "It prepares you to ask good questions. As a job applicant, you should find out as much as possible about the business before a job interview so that you are prepared to ask intelligent questions about the company. This does not ensure that you'll be considered for the available job, but it does indicate your interest in the company and the job. It does not necessarily indicate that you have done a lot of reading, since you may have obtained information about the company from other sources such as current employees or television news. It is not necessary for you to have something to discuss with the interviewer as the interviewer decides what will be discussed. SOURCE: PD:028 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed.) [pp. 65-66]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28 "}, {"number": 74, "question": "Many businesspeople are required to take continuing education classes to ", "choices": ["A. maintain their professional certifications.", "B. improve their standard of living.", "C. demonstrate their emotional intelligence.", "D. supplement their existing income."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Maintain their professional certifications. Many professions\u2014accounting, finance, medical, and education\u2014require certification to work in their fields. Because these fields are always changing, workers are required to update their knowledge and skills to maintain their certifications. Continuing education often involves taking classes and attending seminars and workshops. Professionals are not required to take continuing education classes to improve their standard of living, demonstrate their emotional intelligence, or supplement their existing income. SOURCE: PD:033 SOURCE: Britt, D. (2012, August). The importance of continuing education. Retrieved September 14, 2015, from http://source.southuniversity.edu/the-importance-of-continuing-education98201.aspx "}, {"number": 75, "question": "By reading trade journals, business professionals can learn about ", "choices": ["A. internal policies.", "B. corporate changes.", "C. industry trends.", "D. organizational sales performance."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Industry trends. Trends are the direction in which things are moving. Businesspeople can keep up with the trends and changes that affect their professions and/or industries by reading trade journals. By keeping up with trends, businesspeople can help their employers develop strategies to keep up with the dynamic marketplace. Trends and changes affect many types of business structures\u2014corporations, partnerships, LLCs, sole proprietorships, etc. Employees learn about internal policies by reading their employee handbooks or company newsletters rather than a trade journal. Employees can learn about the organization's sales performance by reviewing the company's internal sales reports. SOURCE: PD:036 SOURCE: VirginiaTech. (2014). Magazines, trade journals, and scholarly journals. Retrieved January 27, 2014, from http://www.lib.vt.edu/help/research/types-sources.html "}, {"number": 76, "question": "What are salespeople expected to be able to do in order to sell goods and services to customers? ", "choices": ["A. Control expenses", "B. Arrange displays", "C. Answer questions", "D. Develop brochures"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Answer questions. Professional salespeople are expected to be able to answer questions and provide further information in order to sell goods and services to customers. To do this successfully, they must be experts in the goods or services they sell and be able to develop long-term relationships with customers. Salespeople are not expected to develop brochures, although they may use them as a selling tool. Salespeople do not need to control expenses in order to sell. Arranging displays is the responsibility of the visual merchandising department. SOURCE: PD:024 SOURCE: PD LAP 21\u2014Career Opportunities in Marketing "}, {"number": 77, "question": "A retailer that overcharges customers for small items at the point of purchase may be engaging in the unethical practice of ", "choices": ["A. retail price maintenance.", "B. predatory pricing.", "C. scanner fraud.", "D. price fixing."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Scanner fraud. Businesses occasionally make honest pricing mistakes. An employee may forget to key in the sale price of an item or key it incorrectly into the computer system. When this happens the customer is charged an incorrect amount for the item when it is scanned at the checkout counter. On the other hand, scanner fraud is a deliberate action that involves overcharging customers, usually for smaller goods, with the expectation the customer will not notice or fuss about it. This is unethical behavior because the business is acting in a deceptive, intentional way to pad the business's bottom line. Predatory pricing is the practice of pricing goods extremely low with the goal of driving the competition out of business. Retail price maintenance involves producers pressuring retailers to sell goods at the suggested retail price, which is unethical and, in some jurisdictions, an illegal practice. Price fixing is an illegal agreement in which businesses agree on prices of their goods or services, resulting in little choice for customers. SOURCE: PI:015 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [pp. 326-327]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29 "}, {"number": 78, "question": "Computers have given marketers the ability to calculate pricing functions such as break-even points and elasticity of demand by using __________ programs. ", "choices": ["A. presentation", "B. word-processing", "C. spreadsheet", "D. communication"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Spreadsheet. Spreadsheet software programs are designed to calculate and analyze numerical data. Spreadsheets are very useful for business owners as they evaluate numerical data that relates to pricing issues. Presentation software is used to create visual aids that are commonly used in sales or other types of presentations. Word-processing programs are used to create written documents. Communication software programs (e.g., email) are used to facilitate the distribution of messages. SOURCE: PI:016 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 213-216). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 79, "question": "Which of the following is a decision a company might make during the decline stage of the product life cycle: ", "choices": ["A. How to increase awareness of the product", "B. Whether to change the product", "C. How to fend off the competition", "D. What production schedule to follow"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Whether to change the product. Whether to change the product is one of the choices that needs to be made during the decline stage. During this stage in the product life cycle, the producer also has to decide whether to sell or license the product, recommit to the product line, discount the product, or regionalize the product. Increasing awareness occurs during the introductory stage. Fending off the competition occurs during the maturity stage. The company does not need to decide the production schedule. SOURCE: PM:024 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 718-719). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 80, "question": "As a result of ongoing product updates and changes, businesses must address ethical issues associated with ", "choices": ["A. international markets.", "B. planned obsolescence.", "C. demographics.", "D. taxation."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Planned obsolescence. Business ethics are the basic principles that govern a company's actions. Planned obsolescence occurs when a business releases a product and plans to discontinue it and replace it with an updated version of the item. This often occurs with technology-based products such as video games and computer software. When a business plans product updates on an annual basis, its customers are often required to purchase the new version in order to use the core product. This can be a financial burden on consumers and can present an ethical situation for the business. International markets, demographics, and taxation are not ethical issues that businesses often encounter when planning product updates and changes. SOURCE: PM:040 SOURCE: Kotler, P., & Armstrong, G. (2008). Principles of marketing (12th ed.) [pp. 574, 576-577]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall. "}, {"number": 81, "question": "Real market opportunity occurs when ", "choices": ["A. supply exceeds demand.", "B. entrepreneurs brainstorm ideas.", "C. an identified want exists.", "D. a good or service can be produced efficiently."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "An identified want exists. Market opportunity exists when an economic want exists, and there is an idea for a good or service for which people are willing and able to pay to fulfill that want. Market opportunity does not necessarily exist because an entrepreneur brainstorms ideas or when supply exceeds demand. In addition, the level of productivity does not necessarily affect the level of demand. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: The Duke Entrepreneurship Manual. (n.d.). Market opportunity. Retrieved September 2, 2015, from http://www.dukeven.com/Home/Evaluation/Market-Opportunity "}, {"number": 82, "question": "Which of the following departments in many businesses is responsible for generating product ideas: ", "choices": ["A. Sales and marketing", "B. Information technology", "C. Executive management", "D. Research and development"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Research and development. Many large businesses have research and development departments that are responsible for generating ideas for new products. These departments conduct research, analyze information, and review new technology to generate ideas. They often begin with a problem or an issue and generate ideas to solve the problem or address the issue. The sole function of these departments is to develop new products or update existing products. Information technology deals with the sharing of information. Executive management is responsible for the overall operation of the business. Sales and marketing is responsible for selling the product. SOURCE: PM:128 SOURCE: Clark, B., Sobel, J., & Basteri, C.G. (2010). Marketing dynamics: Teacher's edition (2nd ed.) [p. 279]. Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company, Inc. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30 "}, {"number": 83, "question": "How food products can be used generally is determined by their ", "choices": ["A. traits.", "B. grades.", "C. labels.", "D. brands."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Grades. Grades are ratings assigned to certain products. The U.S. Department of Agriculture has identified different grades for about 300 food products. These grades determine how the products can be used. Some lower grades indicate that the foods must be used as ingredients in other food products rather than for straight human consumption. Traits are distinguishing characteristics. A label is information attached to or printed on a product by the manufacturer. A brand is a name, term, symbol, or design that identifies a product and distinguishes it from competitors' products. SOURCE: PM:019 SOURCE: PM LAP 8\u2014Raise the Bar (Grades and Standards) "}, {"number": 84, "question": "What can a pharmaceutical manufacturer do to help ensure that its pain reliever and allergy medications are safe for consumer use? ", "choices": ["A. Include vague product labels", "B. Price the products competitively", "C. Use protective packaging", "D. Display a disclaimer on the package"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Use protective packaging. To reduce the risk of product tampering, businesses package their products in ways that ensure that the products are safe for consumption. For example, pharmaceutical companies often use heat seals, blister packs, and bottle safety caps to make it difficult to alter the product before it is sold to the end user. Consumers feel more confident about using the product when they open the package and the item is sealed and protected. Governments often require businesses to place clear, detailed labels on product packages that indicate the ingredients and the proper way to use or administer the products. Competitive pricing and a disclaimer on the package do not ensure a product's safety. SOURCE: PM:017 SOURCE: Inline Filling Systems. (2014, June 17). Why do you need tamper evident packaging? Retrieved September 14, 2015, from http://www.fillers.com/why-do-you-need-tamperevident-packaging/ "}, {"number": 85, "question": "The assortment of merchandise that a firm sells is called its product ", "choices": ["A. demand.", "B. mix.", "C. depth.", "D. classification."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Mix. The product mix is the particular assortment of products that a business offers in order to meet its market's needs and its company's goals. Depth refers to the quantity of goods offered in the product line. Demand is the quantity of a good or service that buyers are ready to buy at a given price at a particular time. Product classification refers to the type of product, whether consumer or industrial. SOURCE: PM:003 SOURCE: PM LAP 3\u2014Mix & Match (Nature of Product Mix) "}, {"number": 86, "question": "Ensuring that customers have the correct perception of a product is one of the goals of product ", "choices": ["A. development.", "B. positioning.", "C. management.", "D. screening."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Positioning. Product positioning is the consumer's image or impression of a product as compared to that of competitive products. One of the goals of product positioning is to make sure that consumers perceive a product in the way that the business intended. This involves communicating information about the product's attributes and characteristics so customers will have a clear perception of its image. Product screening is the process of considering each idea for a new product and discarding those that seem unworkable. Product development is the stage in the creation of a new product in which a working model may be tested, modified, and retested, and production costs are estimated and final details of the product are planned. Product management involves monitoring and developing one or more existing products. SOURCE: PM:042 SOURCE: Richards, L. (2015). The importance of product positioning to the marketing plan. Retrieved September 2, 2015, from smallbusiness.chron.com/importance-product-positioningmarketing-plan-24275.html "}, {"number": 87, "question": "When a customer is willing to purchase only one specific brand, this is referred to as brand ", "choices": ["A. strategy.", "B. recognition.", "C. preference.", "D. insistence."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Insistence. When consumers are in the brand insistence stage, they will not buy a substitute brand. Brand recognition is the stage of brand loyalty in which consumers are made aware of a brand's existence. Brand preference is the stage of brand loyalty in which consumers prefer to purchase a certain brand but will accept substitutes if the brand is not available. A brand strategy is the action a business takes with a brand in order to accomplish its goals. SOURCE: PM:021 SOURCE: PM LAP 6\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (Nature of Product Branding) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31 "}, {"number": 88, "question": "For most businesses, the ultimate goal of using promotion is to ", "choices": ["A. control consumer demand.", "B. introduce new products.", "C. sell goods or services.", "D. get people into the business."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Sell goods or services. The major purpose of using promotion for most businesses is to increase their sales. Promotion helps to do this by informing, reminding, and persuading customers. Promotion is also used to introduce new products and to attract customers to a business. Consumer demand can be created but not controlled. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: PR LAP 2\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Nature of Promotion) "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is a use of product promotion: ", "choices": ["A. Informing customers about product features", "B. Highlighting social or environmental issues", "C. Recruiting new employees", "D. Changing attitudes toward the company"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Informing customers about product features. Informing customers about product features is a use of product promotion. Product promotion is an attempt to persuade customers to buy a particular good or service. It can be used to create customers awareness of a good or service, inform customers about product features, encourage interest in and inquiries about a good or service, inform customers where a product can be purchased, build a reputation for a product, and create excitement and motivate retailers and salespeople. Recruiting new employees, highlighting social or environmental issues, and changing attitudes toward the company are all uses of institutional promotion, not product promotion. SOURCE: PR:002 SOURCE: PR LAP 4\u2014Know Your Options (Product and Institutional Promotion) "}, {"number": 90, "question": "One reason advertising prescription drugs online might be considered an ethical issue is because the advertisements might persuade customers to ", "choices": ["A. use drugs they do not need.", "B. obtain drugs from the manufacturer.", "C. buy drugs they cannot afford.", "D. order drugs that are inexpensive."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Use drugs they do not need. Advertising prescription drugs is often a controversial topic. Those who feel it is ethical to advertise drugs believe that the ads are simply providing information. Those who feel that this type of advertising might be unethical believe that it persuades customers to ask their doctors for drugs they do not need. If customers see ads for certain drugs, they may decide they would like to try them. Oftentimes, doctors will write prescriptions for patients if they are persistent, even if the doctors don't think the drugs are necessary. Also, promoting name-brand prescription drugs encourages customers to ask for them rather than comparable generic drugs that are less expensive. Customers usually are unable to buy drugs they cannot afford. Prescription drugs usually must be purchased from a licensed pharmacy rather than from the manufacturer. Persuading customers to order inexpensive drugs is not an ethical issue. SOURCE: PR:099 SOURCE: Woodard, L. (2010, February 24). Pharmaceutical ads: good or bad for consumers? Retrieved September 14, 2015, from http://abcnews.go.com/Business/Wellness/pharmaceutical-ads-good-badconsumers/story?id=9925198 "}, {"number": 91, "question": "How has the Internet enhanced a business's ability to promote its products? ", "choices": ["A. Consumers can access the business's website at any time.", "B. The business is able to update online product information less frequently.", "C. Consumers can choose to disregard or ignore online advertising.", "D. The business is able to sell higher volumes of goods or services quickly."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Consumers can access the business's website at any time. Because consumers have access to the Internet 24/7, they can access product information on websites when it is convenient for them to do so. Not only do businesses have the ability to promote their products through their websites, they can place online advertisements on the websites of other businesses, which increases the business's exposure to potential customers. Most businesses must update their websites on a continuous basis, although the frequency depends on the type of business and its products. Businesses don't want consumers to ignore their promotions. Promoting products on the Internet may increase sales, but it does not always happen quickly. SOURCE: PR:100 SOURCE: Arens, W.F., Weigold, M.F., & Arens, C. (2013). Contemporary advertising and integrated marketing communications (14th ed.) [pp. 466-472]. New York: McGraw-Hill/Irwin. "}, {"number": 92, "question": "An advantage of newspaper advertising over television and radio promotion is more ", "choices": ["A. consumer interest in the ads.", "B. effective use of color.", "C. sensory appeal.", "D. prestige from being local."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Consumer interest in the ads. Many people read newspapers as much for the advertisements as for the news content. In radio and television, large numbers of consumers \"tune out\" the commercials because they have little or no interest in the advertisements. Color reproduction in newspapers has become very good, but it cannot compete with television color. Both newspaper advertising and radio promotion are often aimed at a local audience. Television has more sensory appeal than newspapers because it can appeal to more of the senses than newspapers. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: PR LAP 3\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Promotional Media) Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32 "}, {"number": 93, "question": "Why is it important to coordinate the elements in advertisements? ", "choices": ["A. To strengthen the theme", "B. To analyze the objective", "C. To simplify the message", "D. To locate the audience"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "To strengthen the theme. The elements of an advertisement include the headline, copy, illustrations, and signature. It is important to coordinate these elements to strengthen the theme of the advertisement. All of the elements should reinforce and promote the theme in order for the advertisement to be effective. It is not important to coordinate the elements in advertisements to analyze the objective, simplify the message, or locate the audience. SOURCE: PR:251 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 471-475). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill. "}, {"number": 94, "question": "The component of the promotional plan that determines the funds available for promotion is the promotional ", "choices": ["A. budget.", "B. method.", "C. mix.", "D. objectives."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Budget. The promotional budget establishes the amount of money that the business plans to spend on its promotional efforts. There are a number of ways the business can determine how much to allocate to promotion. One method is to base the promotional budget on the firm's expected sales and adjust it during the year if sales are higher or lower than expected. The promotional mix is the combination, or blend, of marketing communication channels that a business uses to send its messages to consumers. The promotional method is the particular medium or media chosen to deliver the promotional message. The promotional objectives are the goals the firm wishes to achieve through its promotional efforts. SOURCE: PR:073 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri, C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [p. 74]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Wilcox Co. "}, {"number": 95, "question": "Duane makes sure that as he is interacting with customers, he is also actively listening so that he can better respond to their questions and objections. Which characteristic of a successful salesperson does Duane display? ", "choices": ["A. Persistence and patience", "B. Ethics", "C. Communication skills", "D. Education and training"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Communication skills. Duane displays communication skills when he actively listens to his customers. He knows that good communication isn't just a one-way street. Ethics, persistence and patience, and education and training are all characteristics of successful salespeople, but they are not displayed by Duane in this situation. SOURCE: SE:017 SOURCE: SE LAP 117\u2014Sell Away (Nature of Selling) "}, {"number": 96, "question": "Which of the following is an example of how building a clientele benefits the business: ", "choices": ["A. Increased selling costs", "B. Increased sales volume", "C. Increased knowledge", "D. Personal satisfaction"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Increased sales volume. A clientele is a group of regular, repeat customers. An increase in sales is a direct result of building a clientele. Loyal customers return to buy regularly, thus providing the financial backbone for a growing business. Building a clientele helps to reduce selling costs, not increase them. Personal satisfaction and increased knowledge are salesperson benefits of building a clientele, not business benefits. SOURCE: SE:828 SOURCE: SE LAP 115\u2014Keep Them Loyal (Building Clientele) "}, {"number": 97, "question": "Salespeople who withhold negative product information from customers might be guilty of ", "choices": ["A. negligence.", "B. exaggeration.", "C. guessing.", "D. reciprocity."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Negligence. Some salespeople are tempted to withhold negative product information to avoid turning the customer away from a purchase. Since withholding information could be considered misrepresentation or negligence, salespeople should resist the temptation to tell only part of the story. Exaggeration involves overstating, or stretching, the truth. Guessing involves providing information without knowing the facts. Reciprocity is a method of doing business in which sellers buy from their customers. SOURCE: SE:106 SOURCE: SE LAP 129\u2014Keep It Real\u2014In Sales (Selling Ethics) "}, {"number": 98, "question": "A pharmaceutical company fails to warn the public about the possible side effects associated with a new medication. This is an example of a business violating selling regulations through ", "choices": ["A. exclusivity.", "B. exaggeration.", "C. branding.", "D. misrepresentation."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Misrepresentation. By omitting important facts about a product, the business is misrepresenting the product and misleading consumers, which is illegal in many countries. Businesses that misrepresent their products often face lawsuits and fines. When a business overstates the capabilities of a product, it is exaggeration. Branding is the process of creating certain images about a product or business in the minds of consumers. In a sponsorship agreement, exclusivity is the sponsor's privilege of being the only company in its particular category of goods or services. SOURCE: SE:108 SOURCE: Spiro, R.L., Rich, G.A., & Stanton, W.J. (2008). Management of a sales force (12th ed.) [pp. 493-496]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin. Test 1121 MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 33 "}, {"number": 99, "question": "What type of product information might a salesperson obtain from reading a business's promotional materials? ", "choices": ["A. Aptitudes", "B. Demographics", "C. Objectives", "D. Characteristics"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Characteristics. A business's promotional materials often contain information about a product's characteristics or features that salespeople can use to sell the product. By reading a business's brochures, pamphlets, and print advertisements, salespeople can obtain information about a product's characteristics that will be useful in convincing customers that a product has the features that will provide the benefits for which they are looking. Aptitudes are natural talents for learning specific skills. Demographics are information used to describe a population. Objectives are goals to be reached. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: SE LAP 131\u2014Get Informed (Acquiring Product Information for Use in Selling) "}, {"number": 100, "question": "A manager evaluates the production output of a department by checking it against the production goals for that time period. This is an example of the __________ function of management. ", "choices": ["A. controlling", "B. directing", "C. organizing", "D. planning"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Controlling. Controlling is the management function that monitors the work effort. Planning is the management function of deciding what will be done and how it will be accomplished. Directing is the management function of providing guidance to workers and work projects. Organizing is the management function of setting up the way the business's work will be done. SOURCE: SM:001 SOURCE: SM LAP 3\u2014Manage This! (Concept of Management"}], "2012-MKT-SAMPLE": [{"number": 1, "question": "Brix Beauty Salon used a celebrity's name and photograph in a recent newspaper advertisement, even though the celebrity had not given Brix permission to use her name and likeness. What tort did Brix Beauty Salon commit? ", "choices": ["A. Defamation", "B. Wrongful interference", "C. Appropriation", "D. Conversion"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Appropriation. Torts are civil wrongdoings that cause harm or injury to another party. Appropriation, wrongful interference, defamation, and conversion are four kinds of torts. Appropriation, which Brix Beauty Salon committed, involves a business or person who uses\u2014without permission\u2014another person's name, likeness, and other unique characteristics for the benefit or gain of the user. Brix Beauty Salon used the celebrity's name and picture to attract customers to the salon. Unfortunately, Brix had not obtained permission to use the celebrity's name or likeness. As a result, the celebrity could sue Brix for appropriation. Wrongful interference consists of predatory behavior undertaken by a business to draw either customers or employees away from a competitor. Defamation involves making false, malicious statements about a person or organization. Conversion occurs when personal property is taken from the owner and given to someone else to use. SOURCE: BL:069 SOURCE: Miller, R.L., & Jentz, G.A. (2006). Business law today: Standard edition (7th ed.) [p. 107]. Mason, OH: Thomson Learning.  "}, {"number": 2, "question": "Which of the following forms of ownership is a group of individuals organized by a charter that is granted by a state: ", "choices": ["A. Corporation", "B. Proprietorship", "C. Partnership", "D. Cooperative"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Corporation. A corporation acts as a \"legal person\" in doing business and is owned by stockholders who have purchased stock. A partnership is a form of business ownership in which the business is owned by two or more persons. A sole proprietorship is a form of business ownership in which the business is owned by one person. A cooperative is owned and operated by its user-owners to supply goods and services to its members. SOURCE: BL:003 SOURCE: BL LAP 1\u2014Own It Your Way (Business Ownership)  "}, {"number": 3, "question": "Computer manufacturers sell their products through retailers, such as Best Buy. This is an example of the __________ function of marketing. ", "choices": ["A. promotion", "B. channel management", "C. pricing", "D. product/service management"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Channel management. Channel management involves understanding the concepts and processes needed to identify, select, monitor, and evaluate sales channels. This example entails the transfer of ownership of the computers from the manufacturer to the retailer. Promotion involves understanding the concepts and strategies needed to communicate information about goods, services, images, and/or ideas to achieve a desired outcome. Pricing is the marketing function that involves determining and adjusting prices to maximize return and meet customers' perceptions of value. Product/service management is the marketing function that involves obtaining, developing, maintaining, and improving a product or service mix in response to market opportunities. SOURCE: CM:001 SOURCE: CM LAP 2\u2014Chart Your Channels (Channel Management)  "}, {"number": 4, "question": "Indirect channels of distribution are the only channels that involve ", "choices": ["A. producers.", "B. industrial consumers.", "C. intermediaries.", "D. ultimate consumers."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Intermediaries. Intermediaries are also called middlemen and include sales agents, wholesalers, and retailers who perform specific functions in the movement of goods from producers to consumers. Direct channels of distribution do not involve intermediaries. All channels of distribution involve producers and either industrial or ultimate consumers. SOURCE: CM:003 SOURCE: CM LAP 1\u2014Channel It (Channels of Distribution)  "}, {"number": 5, "question": "Packaging a product in a biodegradable or recyclable container is one way a channel member can participate in the ethical practice of ", "choices": ["A. international marketing.", "B. consumer protection.", "C. social awareness.", "D. green marketing."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Green marketing. Green marketing refers to the practice of pricing, promoting, and distributing products in such a way that they do not harm the natural environment. Most manufacturers choose to participate in this practice because of their code of ethics. Consumer protection deals with safety features and product labeling standards that protect the consumer. Social awareness is a term used to describe the practice of enlightening the community of business actions to promote social welfare. International marketing refers to marketing goods and services in foreign countries. SOURCE: CM:006 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 148). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 14  "}, {"number": 6, "question": "One aspect of coordinating channel management with pricing activities involves ", "choices": ["A. implementing accounting policies.", "B. setting appropriate prices.", "C. earning high profits.", "D. developing product standards."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Setting appropriate prices. Businesses not only need to make their products available, but they also must sell them at a price that customers are willing to pay. If a product is not priced appropriately, customers usually will not buy even if the product is widely distributed. Therefore, it is important for businesses to coordinate the pricing activities with the appropriate channel members. Businesses must set appropriate prices that customers are willing to pay and have the products in stock when customers want them in order to successfully sell to customers. Coordinating the channel-management function with pricing does not involve implementing accounting policies, earning high profits, or developing product standards. SOURCE: CM:007 SOURCE: Lake, L. (n.d.). Developing your marketing mix. Retrieved July 25, 2014, from http://marketing.about.com/od/marketingplanandstrategy/a/marketingmix.htm  "}, {"number": 7, "question": "Why is it important to identify sources that provide relevant, valid written material? ", "choices": ["A. To understand business communication", "B. To compile a database", "C. To read useful information", "D. To prepare a routine message"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To read useful information. Business employees often read written material to obtain useful information that they can use to apply to a specific task or problem. For the information to be useful, the sources must provide relevant, valid written material. For example, employees might read industry publications to identify trends so the business can take steps to remain competitive. Industry information is relevant and valid and useful to businesses. It is not important to identify sources that provide relevant, valid written material to compile a database, understand business communication, or prepare a routine message. SOURCE: CO:054 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. xliii, xlvii-xlix, 681-683). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 8, "question": "Which of the following is a company resource that employees often analyze to ascertain policies and procedures: ", "choices": ["A. Research documents", "B. Sales reports", "C. Promotional brochures", "D. Training materials"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Training materials. Employees are often expected to read a variety of company resources in order to learn about and understand policies and procedures. Training materials are a type of resource that companies often make available to employees. By analyzing the materials, employees learn about company structure, business strategies, operating policies and procedures, etc. The more employees know and understand about the company, the better able they are to perform effectively and advance in the organization. Sales reports, promotional brochures, and research documents usually do not contain information about company policies and procedures. SOURCE: CO:057 SOURCE: Clark, B., & Commers, J. (2013). Entrepreneurship (pp. 400-401). Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co.  "}, {"number": 9, "question": "Jacob was nervous about making his valedictorian speech, but when he stood up to walk to the podium, the audience cheered and gave him a standing ovation, which helped him relax and enjoy the moment. What was the audience doing? ", "choices": ["A. Exhibiting unprofessional behavior", "B. Mocking the speaker", "C. Encouraging the speaker", "D. Engaging in passive listening"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Encouraging the speaker. In many cultures, a standing ovation is the ultimate show of support for a speaker. It indicates the audience's respect for the speaker, and its desire to hear what the speaker has to say. Because cheering provides positive feedback, the audience was not mocking or insulting the speaker. Some cultures might view the audience's behavior as unruly or disrespectful; however, this situation involves a school event, rather than a business event, so the audience isn't exhibiting unprofessional behavior. Because Jacob has not started speaking, the audience is not actively listening to what he is saying. SOURCE: CO:082 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 101]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 10, "question": "A message which is as short and to the point as possible is referred to as ", "choices": ["A. complete.", "B. courteous.", "C. correct.", "D. concise."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Concise. Concise messages are clear and short. A courteous message addresses others with respect. Completeness in communication means giving all the information required. Carefully checking all facts and figures for accuracy before delivering a message should ensure correctness. SOURCE: CO:147 SOURCE: Hyden, J. S., Jordan, A. K., Steinauer, M. H., & Jones, M. J. (2006). Communicating for success (3rd ed.) [pp. 117-118]. Mason, OH: Thomson South-Western.  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 15  "}, {"number": 11, "question": "Writing key points on notecards and then placing the cards in order of their importance is one way to ", "choices": ["A. organize information.", "B. access files.", "C. revise facts.", "D. verify accuracy."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Organize information. Organizing information helps you to communicate your message to your audience in a meaningful way. One way to organize information is to write down key points on notecards (index cards). Then, you can place the cards in their order of importance or categories. The advantage to using notecards to organize information is that you can move them around and reorganize as needed. When you have the information in the order that you want it in, you can efficiently write an outline, report, manual, or article, or prepare a presentation. Placing key points on notecards and placing the cards in a certain order will not help you access files, revise facts, or verify the information's accuracy. SOURCE: CO:086 SOURCE: eHow.com. (1999-2014). How to organize a research paper. Retrieved July 24, 2014, from http://www.ehow.com/how_138072_organize-research-paper.html  "}, {"number": 12, "question": "Which of the following is an example of an effective subject line for a professional email: ", "choices": ["A. New product information", "B. Mtg. rescheduled for 3 p.m.", "C. One more thing . . .", "D. Can we talk for a minute?"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Mtg. rescheduled for 3 p.m. An effective subject line for a professional email should summarize the body of the message and make it easy for the recipient to understand the purpose of the email. \"Mtg. rescheduled for 3 p.m.\", for example, clearly communicates the focus of the email (the meeting) and provides enough information for the recipient to understand why the email was sent to him/her (to inform him/her that the new time for the meeting is 3 p.m.). \"New product information\" is not specific enough for the recipient to understand what product is the focus of the message. \"One more thing . . .\" and \"Can we talk for a minute?\" are vague and provide little information to help the recipient understand the reason for the email. SOURCE: CO:090 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 203). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 13, "question": "When writing informational messages, business employees should explain the situation and include sufficient data for the recipient to be able to ", "choices": ["A. make a decision.", "B. read the message.", "C. contact the business.", "D. agree with the content."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Make a decision. Informational messages are intended to inform and provide data to the recipients. In many cases, the purpose of an informational message is to help the recipient make a decision. For this to happen, the business employee should explain the situation and include sufficient data. If recipients clearly understand the who, what, where, when, why, and how of the situation, they usually have sufficient information to make a decision. Clear and concise writing enables a recipient to read the message. The letterhead usually includes the business's name, address, and phone number so recipients are able to contact the business. Explaining the situation and including sufficient data does not guarantee that the recipient will agree with the content. SOURCE: CO:039 SOURCE: Bov\u00e9e, C.L., & Thill, J.V. (2008). Business communication today (9th ed.) [p. 430]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 14, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a simple written report that a business might prepare on a regular basis: ", "choices": ["A. Results of a research study", "B. Minutes of a staff meeting", "C. Findings of a major investigation", "D. Analysis of a publicity campaign"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Minutes of a staff meeting. Simple written reports are often intended to provide information to the business's employees. An example of a simple written report that a business might prepare on a regular basis is the minutes of a staff meeting. Businesses often have routine staff meetings and prepare a brief summary to distribute to all employees. This serves to remind employees of the topics discussed and provide that information to employees who may have been unable to attend. Results of a research study, findings of a major investigation, and analysis of a publicity campaign are examples of complex written reports. SOURCE: CO:094 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 204-205). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 16  "}, {"number": 15, "question": "Which is the most effective way for an employee to communicate interest in providing good service to customers? ", "choices": ["A. Informal product demonstration", "B. Body language", "C. Social status", "D. Closing statements"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Body language. Body language is gestures, facial expression, tone of voice, or any other form of communicating without words. An employee's body language conveys a message to customers. For example, if an employee is talking to one customer and ignores a new customer, the employee's body language is telling the new customer that s/he is not important. On the other hand, an employee who smiles or motions that s/he will be with the customer shortly is communicating an interest in providing good service. Employees usually do not communicate their social status to customers. The verbal and nonverbal communications employees use during the closing statements indicate their interest in being of service, not the closing statements themselves. Informal product demonstrations do not communicate interest in providing good service to customers. SOURCE: CR:005 SOURCE: Cheesebro, T., O'Connor, L., & Rios, F. (2007). Communication skills: Preparing for career success (3rd ed.) [pp. 46-47]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 16, "question": "A customer complains that an item purchased last week does not fit properly. The real reason for returning the item is that it is too expensive. This is an example of a __________ complaint. ", "choices": ["A. service", "B. sincere", "C. hidden", "D. business"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Hidden. Customers sometimes conceal the real complaint by stating another believable but secondary reason for their dissatisfaction. A sincere complaint is an honestly felt dissatisfaction. A service complaint results from poor service, and a business complaint is customer dissatisfaction with the business in general. SOURCE: CR:010 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (pp. 240-241). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 17, "question": "Employees can reinforce their company's positive image by ", "choices": ["A. developing a broad product/service mix.", "B. delivering on the company's brand promise.", "C. sharing its intellectual property with competitors.", "D. advocating prestige pricing and price skimming."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Delivering on the company's brand promise. A brand promise is a business's agreement (spoken or unspoken) with customers that it will consistently meet their expectations and deliver on its brand characteristics and values. By delivering on their company's brand promise, employees can reinforce the company's positive image among customers. These employees become brand ambassadors, communicating the company's vision, mission, and brand through their actions and words, both on the job and off. Developing a broad product/service mix does not necessarily reinforce the company's positive image. Betraying a company by sharing its intellectual property with competitors does nothing to reinforce the company's positive image. Prestige pricing and price skimming do not reinforce a company's positive image in every case. SOURCE: CR:002 SOURCE: Lebard, P., Rendleman, K., & Dolan, K. (n.d.). Delivering the brand promise through employees. Retrieved July 25, 2014, from http://www.mmc.com/knowledgecenter/viewpoint/archive/lebard2006.php  "}, {"number": 18, "question": "A local hardware store purchased a large shipment of snow shovels in November in order to prepare for winter weather. The hardware store is helping to create __________ utility. ", "choices": ["A. form", "B. place", "C. time", "D. possession"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Time. Time utility is created when products are available at the time they are needed or wanted by customers. Form utility is usefulness created by altering or changing the form or shape of a good to make it more useful to customers. Place utility is usefulness created by making sure that goods and services are available at the place where they are needed or wanted by customers. Possession utility is usefulness created when ownership of a product is transferred from the seller to the user. SOURCE: EC:004 SOURCE: EC LAP 13\u2014Use It (Economic Utility)  "}, {"number": 19, "question": "A manufacturer wants to ensure that each product it makes meets certain standards so that customer complaints and product returns will be kept at minimal levels. Meeting this goal depends on the part of operations known as ", "choices": ["A. inventory management.", "B. strategic management.", "C. purchasing.", "D. quality control."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Quality control. Ensuring that products meet predetermined standards for excellence is known as quality control, and it is part of operations. Purchasing and inventory management are also part of operations, but purchasing refers to acquiring necessary goods and services, and inventory management means supervising inventory levels to make sure there is an appropriate balance. Strategic management refers to the business's plans and goals for the future. SOURCE: EC:071 SOURCE: EC LAP 19\u2014Strictly Business (Business Activities)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 17  "}, {"number": 20, "question": "Which of the following factors has aided the most in creating a global business environment: ", "choices": ["A. Technology", "B. Government", "C. Cultural changes", "D. Exchange rates"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Technology. Technologies of all types have enabled global markets to function effectively. As examples, refrigeration has enabled perishable products to be transported between countries; and computers have facilitated communication and exchange of payments. Government, culture, and exchange rates have both facilitated and hampered global trade. SOURCE: EC:104 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., Burrow, J.L., & Kleindl, B. (2009). Intro to business (7th ed.) [pp. 60-61]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 21, "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of private enterprise that enables consumers to buy quality products at fair prices: ", "choices": ["A. Unlimited resources", "B. Competition", "C. Inflation", "D. Profit motive"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Competition. Competition is the rivalry between two or more businesses to attract scarce (limited) customer dollars. In order to be competitive, businesses must try to offer consumers quality products at fair prices. The profit motive is the desire to make a profit, which moves people to invest in business. Inflation is a rapid rise in prices usually occurring when demand exceeds supply. Resources are limited in all economic systems. SOURCE: EC:009 SOURCE: EC LAP 15\u2014People Power (The Private Enterprise System)  "}, {"number": 22, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a tax that government collects from some businesses: ", "choices": ["A. Subsidy", "B. Excise", "C. Bond", "D. Discount"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Excise. Excise is a special government tax on certain items, such as gasoline. Government collects several kinds of taxes from businesses. Businesses are responsible for collecting income and social insurance taxes from employees and sales, excise, and duty taxes from customers. Businesses pay tax on their income and property, and they also pay fees for licenses and permits. Subsidy is government financial help given to a business. Bonds are interest-bearing certificates issued by government that promise to pay bond owners a certain sum at a specified time. Discount is the amount by which the price of something is reduced. SOURCE: EC:008 SOURCE: EC LAP 16\u2014Regulate and Protect (Government and Business)  "}, {"number": 23, "question": "Shelly is a union member who has been having problems with management. Shelly should report her problems to her union's ", "choices": ["A. mediator.", "B. president.", "C. steward.", "D. arbitrator."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Steward. Union stewards are called shop stewards, and they are union members elected by their peers to handle any grievances or problems members might have with management. A union president's responsibilities involve leading the union as a whole rather than assisting individuals. A mediator is involved in union negotiations, clarifying issues, and making suggestions concerning the contract. An arbitrator also assists with negotiations. In binding arbitration, this person's decisions regarding the contract are final and cannot be changed. SOURCE: EC:015 SOURCE: EC LAP 5\u2014Get United (Organized Labor)  "}, {"number": 24, "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of weak currency: ", "choices": ["A. It reduces business profits.", "B. It makes acquiring foreign companies more expensive.", "C. It negatively affects the balance of trade.", "D. It makes buying imports less expensive."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "It makes acquiring foreign companies more expensive. One disadvantage of weak currency is making the acquisition of foreign companies more expensive since domestic currency doesn't go as far overseas. Reduction of business profits and a negative effect on the balance of trade are disadvantages of strong currency, not weak currency. Weak currency makes buying imports more expensive, not less expensive. SOURCE: EC:100 SOURCE: EC LAP 30\u2014Get Your Money's Worth (Exchange Rates)  "}, {"number": 25, "question": "In some cultures, creating relationships during business negotiations is key; in other cultures, negotiators want a signed contract. This illustrates cultural differences in negotiating ", "choices": ["A. styles.", "B. attitudes.", "C. schedules.", "D. goals."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Goals. Different cultures have different goals when it comes to business negotiations. For some, only a signed contract will do. For others, creating relationships equals success. Different cultures also have different attitudes (win-win v. win-lose), schedules (open-ended v. time-sensitive), and styles (informal v. formal); however, achieving a contract v. achieving a relationship pertains to negotiation goals. SOURCE: EC:045 SOURCE: EC LAP 24\u2014On Top of the World (Impact of Culture on Global Trade)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 18  "}, {"number": 26, "question": "Why is it sometimes difficult to be honest about strengths? ", "choices": ["A. No one likes to recognize strengths.", "B. We don't want to brag.", "C. Weaknesses are more significant than strengths.", "D. Few people have strengths."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "We don't want to brag. It's sometimes difficult to be honest about strengths. We don't want to seem as if we're bragging or \u201cstuck up.\u201d However, recognizing our talents, abilities, and the things we do well is a healthy and acceptable thing to do. Everyone has strengths. Weaknesses are not more significant than strengths. SOURCE: EI:002 SOURCE: EI LAP 17\u2014Assess for Success (Assessing Your Strengths and Weaknesses)  "}, {"number": 27, "question": "As a sales representative for a large distributor, you hear a lot of information from your clients about the competition. Which of the following characteristics would help you to demonstrate initiative in this situation: ", "choices": ["A. Creativity and self-understanding", "B. Patience and resourcefulness", "C. Empathy and self-control", "D. Alertness and assertiveness"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Alertness and assertiveness. Alertness and assertiveness are two personal characteristics that are interdependent with initiative. A sales representative can show initiative by being alert to information about competitors and being assertive enough to express his/her views. Empathy is the ability to put yourself in another person's place. Resourcefulness helps you to make the best of any situation. Creativity is the ability to generate unique ideas, approaches, solutions, etc. Self-understanding is comprehending one's personal needs, interests, values, and motives and recognizing their effects on one's behavior. Patience is the ability to endure life's aggravations and difficulties calmly. SOURCE: EI:024 SOURCE: EI LAP 2\u2014Hustle! (Taking Initiative at Work)  "}, {"number": 28, "question": "The night clerk in a local motel often complains to the manager about having to assist his/her coworkers. This is an example of an employee having a(n) __________ attitude. ", "choices": ["A. negative", "B. productive", "C. innovative", "D. indifferent"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Negative. People who have negative attitudes do not like to assist others. They are usually self-centered and focus only on their own needs. People who are productive and innovative are positive people. Indifferent people lack concern about or interest in things. SOURCE: EI:019 SOURCE: EI LAP 3\u2014Opt for Optimism (Positive Attitude)  "}, {"number": 29, "question": "Instead of going through Jeff's files, Amanda waits until Jeff returns from lunch to obtain a file that she needs to review. This is an example of one coworker ________ of another coworker. ", "choices": ["A. respecting the privacy", "B. violating the workspace", "C. correcting the work", "D. reinforcing the efforts"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Respecting the privacy. When employees respect the privacy of others in the workplace, they are more likely to gain the trust and respect of their coworkers and managers. Respecting coworkers' privacy means that an employee does not read correspondence that is not addressed to him/her. In addition, the employee does not listen to others' private conversations or go through their personal belongings. In the example, Amanda waited until her coworker Jeff returned from lunch to obtain a file that she needed. Because she did not go through Jeff's workspace, she was respecting rather than violating his privacy. The example does not indicate that Amanda's intention was to correct Jeff's work or to reinforce his efforts\u2014she simply needed to review information in the file. SOURCE: EI:029 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (p. 267). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 30, "question": "Behavior that is characterized by a willingness to ignore the rights of others and to exploit them in order to achieve personal goals is __________ behavior. ", "choices": ["A. offensive", "B. passive", "C. assertive", "D. aggressive"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Aggressive. Offensive behavior is unpleasant or displeasing. Assertive behavior is characterized by respect for personal rights as well as for the rights of others. Passive behavior is characterized by a failure to exercise personal rights and a lack of respect for personal needs. SOURCE: EI:008 SOURCE: EI LAP 18\u2014Assert Yourself (Assertiveness)  "}, {"number": 31, "question": "One of the reasons that teams are important to businesses is that they can increase ", "choices": ["A. procrastination.", "B. conflicts.", "C. costs.", "D. productivity."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Productivity. Productivity is the amount and value of goods and services produced (outputs) from set amounts of resources (inputs). The overall output of all employees is often increased when businesses use teams because workers who feel they are an important part of a team often work harder and produce more. Other reasons that teams are important to businesses are that they reduce costs and workplace conflicts. Teams do not increase procrastination\u2014putting off until tomorrow what should have been done today. SOURCE: EI:045 SOURCE: QS LAP 6\u2014Lean on Me (Teamwork Skills)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 19  "}, {"number": 32, "question": "Which of the following statements is true about consensus building: ", "choices": ["A. The agreed upon option is not always each person's first choice.", "B. In most cases, consensus allows for a minority to rule.", "C. Each group member's opinion is less important than the leader's opinion.", "D. Consensus can be reached without everyone's agreement."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The agreed upon option is not always each person's first choice. Consensus is a decision-making outcome that requires the substantial agreement of each group member. This means that for everyone to agree, the option doesn't have to be each group member's first choice, but an option that has been presented and agreed upon as acceptable by all members of the group. Minority rule means that a few people in the group make the decision. Consensus is not minority rule, is not rule by a single leader, and cannot be reached without each group member's input and agreement, which often requires compromise. SOURCE: EI:011 SOURCE: EI LAP 19\u2014It's a Group Thing (Consensus Building)  "}, {"number": 33, "question": "What is true about personal vision? ", "choices": ["A. Realistic visions are based on mission statements.", "B. Good visions have permanent results.", "C. Specific goals are necessary to determine your vision.", "D. Achievable visions are time bound."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Good visions have permanent results. A vision is a desire for the future that is achieved over time with determination and hard work. Good visions create positive results and may involve the input of many people over a long period of time. Visions are not based on mission statements, nor do they start out with specific goals. Visions are timeless rather than time bound. SOURCE: EI:063 SOURCE: QS LAP 11\u2014Picture This!  "}, {"number": 34, "question": "Being a good listener is an example of what type of behavior that builds positive working relationships? ", "choices": ["A. Being cooperative", "B. Carrying your own weight", "C. Getting to know others on your work team", "D. Having a good attitude"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Being cooperative. Being a good listener is an example of being cooperative in the process of building positive working relationships. Being cooperative involves valuing the work of others as much as you value your own work. If someone needs help or is falling behind, you do your best to support him/her. This includes listening attentively when your coworker is communicating with you. Being a good listener is not an example of carrying your own weight. It may go along with getting to know others and having a good attitude, but it is best as an example of being cooperative. SOURCE: EI:037 SOURCE: EI LAP 5\u2014Can You Relate? (Positive Working Relationships)  "}, {"number": 35, "question": "Every pay period, Amanda places $100 from her paycheck into a savings account that earns 4.5 percent interest. In this situation, money functions as a ", "choices": ["A. store of value.", "B. medium of exchange.", "C. form of barter.", "D. measure of income."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Store of value. Money functions as a store of value when it is saved rather than spent. The money can be held over time, and it retains value for future purchasing power. In some situations, money is invested or placed in an account that generates more value. Money also serves as a medium of exchange. This occurs when money is used to obtain goods and services. Bartering involves trading one good or service for another good or service. Money also functions as a measure of value. When money functions as a measure of value, the individual holding the money assesses what s/he is willing to pay for a good or service, thereby communicating the product's value or worth. SOURCE: FI:060 SOURCE: Clark, B., Basteri, C.G., Gassen, C., & Walker, M. (2014). Marketing dynamics (3rd ed.) [p. 43]. Tinley Park, IL: The Goodheart-Willcox Co.  "}, {"number": 36, "question": "Which of the following statements about understanding your spending habits is true: ", "choices": ["A. The first step in creating a financial plan", "B. A key aspect in exceeding financial goals", "C. A key aspect of opening a bank account", "D. The last step in creating a financial plan"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "The first step in creating a financial plan. Knowing how you spend your money\u2014understanding your spending habits\u2014is the first step in creating a financial plan. Knowing your spending habits does not guarantee that you will exceed your financial goals. Although it's helpful to know how many checks you expect to write in a month, you don't need to understand your spending habits to open a bank account. SOURCE: FI:065 SOURCE: QS LAP 31\u2014Set Yourself Up (Setting Financial Goals)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 20  "}, {"number": 37, "question": "When Armand is comparing his checkbook balance with his bank statement, he must make sure that he has subtracted the ____________ from his checkbook. ", "choices": ["A. accumulated interest", "B. transaction fees", "C. payroll deposits", "D. check numbers"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Transaction fees. Reconciling bank statements involves comparing the entries in a checkbook with the entries listed on the bank statement. It is important to make these comparisons to determine inconsistencies and mistakes. If a check is not recorded correctly, and if the mistake is not caught, the individual runs the risk of having insufficient funds in his/her checking account, which results in bounced checks. Some financial institutions charge transaction fees for checking accounts, so it is important to make sure that those fees are subtracted from the checking account balance. Accumulated interest and payroll deposits are added to the checking account balance rather than subtracted from it. Check numbers are not subtracted from the checkbook when reconciling bank statements and checkbook balances. SOURCE: FI:070 SOURCE: Campbell, S.R. (2010). Foundations of personal finance: Teacher's Edition (pp. 193-195). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company.  "}, {"number": 38, "question": "Which of the following is a type of financial-services provider: ", "choices": ["A. Taxation department", "B. Stock market", "C. Commercial bank", "D. Retirement community"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Commercial bank. A commercial bank provides a variety of financial services to individuals and businesses. Besides providing savings accounts and other savings options, banks also make loans and offer credit cards. Many large banks have trust departments and help individuals plan for retirement. Depending on the size of the bank, it may be possible to obtain all necessary financial services from that institution. The stock market itself does not provide financial services. A taxation department collects various types of taxes. A retirement community provides housing rather than financial services. SOURCE: FI:075 SOURCE: Campbell, S.R. (2010). Foundations of personal finance: Teacher's Edition (pp. 179-181). Tinley Park, IL: Goodheart-Willcox Company.  "}, {"number": 39, "question": "A decrease in the availability of raw materials is an economic risk that may result in __________ for a business. ", "choices": ["A. high interest rates", "B. increased regulation", "C. financial loss", "D. lower turnover"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Financial loss. A decrease in the availability of raw materials, supplies, or products needed by a business are economic risks that can result in financial loss for the business. For example, a decrease in the availability of petroleum can cause business's transportation costs to skyrocket. High interest rates is a business condition that can create economic risks. The involvement of government in the regulation of business may cause financial loss for some businesses. High turnover, rather than low turnover, is an economic risk. SOURCE: FI:084 SOURCE: FI LAP 8\u2014Prepare for the Worst; Expect the Best (Nature of Risk Management)  "}, {"number": 40, "question": "What do all businesses need to be aware of with regard to the accounting process? ", "choices": ["A. Legal considerations", "B. Management styles", "C. System specifications", "D. Research techniques"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Legal considerations. There are laws that regulate the reporting of financial information. Since accounting is the process of keeping and interpreting financial records, all businesses need to be aware of legal considerations and understand what is legal and what is not. For example, there are laws regulating the way that businesses report income and pay taxes. If businesses violate the law, they may be fined or face other types of legal action. With regard to the accounting process, it is not necessary for all businesses to be aware of management styles, system specifications, or research techniques. SOURCE: FI:353 SOURCE: SOX-Online. (2003-2012). Sarbanes-Oxley essential information. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.sox-online.com/basics.html  "}, {"number": 41, "question": "Claudia is creating a balance sheet for her business. She lists the full value of all of her assets, even some office equipment she hasn't completely paid for. However, to find the true net worth of her business, Claudia must subtract the money she owes on the equipment, since the debt is considered a(n) ", "choices": ["A. liability.", "B. liquid asset.", "C. accounts receivable.", "D. dividend."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Liability. Liabilities are the financial obligations a business has. In Claudia's case, the money she still owes on her office equipment is considered a liability. To find the net worth of her business, she must subtract her total liabilities from her total assets. This gives her an accurate picture of her business's health. A liquid asset is cash or any asset that can be quickly converted into cash. Accounts receivable are money owed to the business for purchases made by customers. Dividends are sums of money paid to investors or stockholders as earnings on investments. SOURCE: FI:093 SOURCE: Dlabay, L.R., & Burrow, J.L. (2008). Business finance (p. 74). South-Western Cengage Learning.  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 21  "}, {"number": 42, "question": "A business should strive to keep its cash conversion cycle as short as possible so it ", "choices": ["A. can earn dividends.", "B. has cash available to use.", "C. can increase its profit margin.", "D. has fewer liquid assets."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Has cash available to use. The cash conversion cycle is the ratio that reflects the number of days between a company paying for raw materials and receiving cash from selling the products made from those raw materials. The longer this period of time, the longer the company's money is tied up and unavailable for other uses. Therefore, a financial manager strives to keep the cash conversion cycle as short as possible, so that the business has more free cash to work with. A dividend is the amount of money that a corporation pays to a stockholder as earnings on an investment. The profit margin is a product pricing consideration. The profit margin is the amount of money that a business earns on sales after expenses and is expressed as a ratio. Liquid assets are things of value that the business owns, which can be quickly converted to cash. SOURCE: FI:354 SOURCE: FI LAP 7\u2014Money Matters (Role of Finance)  "}, {"number": 43, "question": "One reason why human resources management is important to the success of a business is because this process is responsible for ", "choices": ["A. creating jobs for the company.", "B. eliminating turnover.", "C. staffing the business.", "D. reducing compensation."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Staffing the business. Human resources management is the process of planning, staffing, leading, and organizing the employees of a business. Staffing is an important function because hiring and keeping qualified employees will contribute to the success of the business. Employees who are capable and hardworking usually help the business to achieve its goals and be successful. It is not possible to completely eliminate turnover. Management usually decides if it needs to expand and create more jobs. Human resources management administers the compensation package, but it is not responsible for reducing compensation. SOURCE: HR:410 SOURCE: HR LAP 35\u2014People Pusher (Nature of Human Resources Management)  "}, {"number": 44, "question": "Which of the following is a way that marketers can use data to \u201cfollow up\u201d on any problems or issues with a product: ", "choices": ["A. Providing salespeople with additional training", "B. Determining what new products to offer", "C. Deciding what wholesalers to use for distribution", "D. Budgeting for product development"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Providing salespeople with additional training. Data may show that salespeople need additional training for a certain product. This is something marketers want to provide so sales and profits can be as high as possible. Determining what new products to offer, deciding which wholesalers to use for distribution, and budgeting for product development are all activities that should take place before a product hits the market. SOURCE: IM:012 SOURCE: IM LAP 12\u2014Data Do It (Need for Marketing Data)  "}, {"number": 45, "question": "Software that allows for real-time analysis of marketing information enables businesses to search many databases and identify ", "choices": ["A. obscure relationships.", "B. pricing strategies.", "C. hidden objections.", "D. distribution channels."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Obscure relationships. Advances in technology have created software that allows for real-time analysis of marketing information. The benefit of this software to businesses is that it enables them to search many databases and identify obscure relationships. The software allows businesses to analyze the data as it is collected and compare it with information stored in many other databases. For example, real-time analysis might discover that a customer applying for store credit has the same telephone number as another customer who recently declared bankruptcy. This information would be immediately made available to the credit manager. Pricing strategies are plans for setting prices. A hidden objection is a real objection the customer does not want brought out in the open. Distribution channels are paths, or routes, that goods or services take from the producer to the ultimate consumer or industrial user. SOURCE: IM:183 SOURCE: Kurtz, D. (2013). Contemporary marketing: 2013 edition (p. 261). Mason, OH: SouthWestern, Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 46, "question": "A business should decide at the beginning of a marketing-research project how much it can afford to spend in order to ", "choices": ["A. tell the researcher when to stop the project.", "B. narrow the focus of the research if necessary.", "C. cut the project in half if that is all it can afford.", "D. skip some of the research steps if it needs to save time."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Narrow the focus of the research if necessary. Many businesses allocate a specific amount in the budget for marketing research. If the amount will not cover the expense of the entire research project, then the business should stop at this point or narrow the focus of the project to the part that would be most useful at that time. The steps in the marketing-research process must be taken in a specific order, and none of them can be skipped. Starting a project and then telling the researcher to stop or cutting the project in half would not be effective. SOURCE: IM:010 SOURCE: IM LAP 5\u2014Seek and Find (Marketing Research)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 22  "}, {"number": 47, "question": "A business conducts marketing research when it needs to solve a problem or when it wants to ", "choices": ["A. identify a new market opportunity.", "B. increase its sales staff.", "C. coordinate activities.", "D. analyze financing options."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Identify a new market opportunity. Marketing research is the systematic gathering, recording, and analyzing of data about a specific issue, situation, or concern. To remain competitive in the marketplace, businesses conduct marketing research. One way to remain competitive in the marketplace is to identify, select, and distribute products to a new market segment, whose identification requires marketing research. If the business finds that a new market opportunity is feasible, it might decide to increase its sales staff, coordinate new marketing activities, or analyze financing options. Analyzing financing options is a business activity rather than a marketing-research activity. SOURCE: IM:282 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B. (2010). Essentials of marketing research (4th ed.) [pp. 14, 52]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 48, "question": "Marketers may want to use research to study the economy, a factor that is subject to change. In this context, the economy can be described as a(n) ", "choices": ["A. variable.", "B. case study.", "C. experiment.", "D. hypothesis."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Variable. A variable is any factor that is subject to change. Sometimes, the economy is the variable that marketers want to study through research. A case study is an in-depth analysis of a person, group, or event. An experiment is a marketing-research method that tests cause and effect by test marketing new products or comparing test groups with control groups. A hypothesis is a proposed explanation for something. SOURCE: IM:284 SOURCE: IM LAP 14\u2014Better By Design (Marketing Research Design Methods)  "}, {"number": 49, "question": "The purpose of semantic-differential rating scales is to measure ", "choices": ["A. talent.", "B. behavior.", "C. personality.", "D. attitude."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Attitude. Semantic-differential rating scales are used to measure attitude. Research participants are asked to check the box that best describes their feelings. Each box on the scale contains an adjective or phrase, such as courteous or discourteous. By checking a box, respondents indicate their attitude or how they feel about statements. Behavior is the manner in which individuals act. Personality is an individual's qualities or traits and behavior. Talent is an individual's aptitude for learning specific skills. SOURCE: IM:286 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 348-350]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 50, "question": "What data-collection method can be used to obtain product information during the point-of-purchase process? ", "choices": ["A. Statistical survey", "B. Photographic scanner", "C. Email survey", "D. Volume-tracking scanner"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Volume-tracking scanner. A scanner is an electronic device that reads or translates codes that are placed on products and enters the product information into a computer. Scanners are commonly used during a sales transaction, which is the point of purchase. This is a popular method of collecting information about customers' buying habits and inventory status because the scanning system can track large volumes of goods. Once enough data are collected, researchers evaluate the data to determine how fast or slow certain products are moving, which is information they can use to make business decisions. Photographic scanners, email surveys, and statistical surveys are not data-collection methods that researchers use during the point-of-purchase process. SOURCE: IM:289 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 256-257]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 51, "question": "Which of the following is an example of range: ", "choices": ["A. Consumers buy between four and eight widgets per week.", "B. Consumers buy an average of six widgets per week.", "C. Most consumers buy five widgets per week.", "D. Half of all consumers buy more than four widgets per week."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Consumers buy between four and eight widgets per week. Range is the distance between the smallest and largest value in a set of responses. In the example, four was the smallest number of widgets purchased, and eight was the largest number. The distance between four and eight is the range. Range is often used to describe the relation between numbers, such as the variation between the number of widgets purchased. Mean is the average, such as consumers buying an average of six widgets per week. Mode is the most common response, such as most consumers buy five widgets per week. Median is the exact middle, such as half of all consumers buying more than four widgets per week. SOURCE: IM:191 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [p. 445-446]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 23  "}, {"number": 52, "question": "Which of the following is a source of error in the research process: ", "choices": ["A. Key summary", "B. Interview location", "C. Sample design", "D. Project purpose"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Sample design. When collecting information, researchers usually select a sample of the target population to contact or include in the study. The design of this sample may lead to errors in the research. Researchers need to make sure the sample they select accurately represents the target population. For example, errors may occur if all those in the sample are 20-year-old males who live in one small city, but the research involves all men between the ages of 18 and 50. Interview location, key summary, and project purpose are not sources of error in the research process. SOURCE: IM:292 SOURCE: Hair, J.F., Wolfinbarger, M, Ortinau, D.J., & Bush, R.P. (2008). Essentials of marketing research (p. 136). New York, McGraw-Hill Irwin.  "}, {"number": 53, "question": "Which of the following is a possible weakness associated with a secondary-data source: ", "choices": ["A. Internet accessibility", "B. Recent industry approval", "C. Reasonable purchase price", "D. Inconsistent collection method"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Inconsistent collection method. Secondary data are information that have been collected for purposes other than the project at hand. Marketers collect secondary data from a variety of sources, such as business websites, research companies, trade associations, and industry journals. Although secondarydata sources can be inexpensive and provide current information, researchers must be careful to examine the way in which the source collected information. If the source publishes statistical data it has collected in an inconsistent or subjective way, the data may be skewed or exhibit bias. Industry approval, reasonable prices, and Internet accessibility are advantages associated with secondary-data sources. SOURCE: IM:428 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 164-165]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 54, "question": "The marketing function that best enables a company to make informed decisions about what to sell is ", "choices": ["A. promotion.", "B. product/service management.", "C. selling.", "D. marketing-information management."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Marketing-information management. This function involves gathering, accessing, synthesizing, evaluating, and disseminating information to aid in making marketing decisions. The findings from marketing-information management are used in product/service management to guide product development and improvement. The selling function involves determining customer needs and wants and responding through planned, personalized communication that influences purchase decisions and enhances future business opportunities. The promotion function is marketing function needed to communicate information about goods, services, images, and/or ideas to achieve a desired outcome. SOURCE: MK:002 SOURCE: MK LAP 1\u2014Work the Big Six (Marketing Functions)  "}, {"number": 55, "question": "The owner of a business is meeting with the company's managers and supervisors to set objectives for the next year. This group is developing the company's ", "choices": ["A. business goals.", "B. channels of distribution.", "C. market share.", "D. promotional mix."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Business goals. The goals or objectives of a business are the things the business wants to attain. A particular share of the industry market might be a business's goal. The promotional mix is the combination of marketing communication channels that a business uses to send its messages to consumers. Channels of distribution are the paths, or routes, that goods or services take from the producer to the ultimate consumer or industrial user. SOURCE: MP:001 SOURCE: MP LAP 2\u2014Pick the Mix (Nature of Marketing Strategies)  "}, {"number": 56, "question": "When a local athletic apparel store sells shoes, clothing, and accessories that are designed specifically for runners, it is using ____________ segmentation. ", "choices": ["A. demographic", "B. geographic", "C. psychographic", "D. rate of usage"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Psychographic. Market segmentation is dividing the market into groups that have similar characteristics. Segmenting markets helps businesses identify the people who are most likely to buy their products. Businesses segment markets in different ways. In the example, the athletic apparel store used psychographics to divide the market, which means that the market is divided on the basis of a lifestyle choice\u2014running. Geographic segmentation involves dividing a market on the basis of location (e.g., zip code). Demographics are the physical and social characteristics of the population. A business that segments the market on the basis of demographics considers factors such as the age, gender, and ethnicity of the population. Rate of usage is a type of behavioral segmentation, which involves dividing customers into groups according to their response to a product. SOURCE: MP:003 SOURCE: MP LAP 3\u2014Have We Met? (Market Identification)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 24  "}, {"number": 57, "question": "To evaluate an Internet source, what aspect would you consider when assessing whether its information is clearly laid out so that it is easy to read? ", "choices": ["A. Relevance", "B. Presentation", "C. Objectivity", "D. Timeliness"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Presentation. Presentation is the way in which the information is communicated. It addresses such factors as clarity of language used, sufficiency of font size, clarity of layout, effectiveness of colors, usefulness of graphics or photos, clarity of audio or video (if included), and helpfulness of any animation used. Presentation is particularly important on the Web since so much time is spent reading online. Relevance deals with whether the information pertains to the topic being researched. Objectivity deals with presenting unbiased information. Timeliness deals with how up to date the information is; however, the importance of timeliness will vary from topic to topic. SOURCE: NF:079 SOURCE: Cornell University Library. (2014, February 13). Evaluating web sites: Criteria and tools. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://olinuris.library.cornell.edu/ref/research/webeval.html  "}, {"number": 58, "question": "What do businesses often develop to be able to store and analyze data for the purpose of making business decisions? ", "choices": ["A. Management policies", "B. Operating procedures", "C. Survey methods", "D. Information systems"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Information systems. An information system is a method of gathering, storing, and analyzing data for the purpose of making business decisions. Businesses acquire vast amounts of information that must be stored and analyzed to make it useful. An effective information system enables a business to quickly and accurately process information and use that information to make decisions. Businesses do not develop operating procedures, survey methods, or management policies to be able to store and analyze data for the purpose of making business decisions. SOURCE: NF:083 SOURCE: Rouse, M., & Martinez, C. (2011, March). IS (information system or information services). Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://whatis.techtarget.com/definition/IS-information-systemor-information-services  "}, {"number": 59, "question": "Which of the following is available to all people around the world who have access to a computer that has connectivity: ", "choices": ["A. Extranet", "B. Intranet", "C. Internet", "D. Broadband"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Internet. The Internet is a worldwide network of computers that enables users to access information and communicate with others. The Internet is available to all people around the world who have access to a computer that has connectivity. Today, connectivity may be by dial-up to telephone lines, through broadband technology, or through wireless routers. All people around the world do not have access to an Intranet or an Extranet. Broadband is a type of technology. SOURCE: NF:086 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 223). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 60, "question": "Many presentation software programs allow users to ", "choices": ["A. copyright their graphics.", "B. include voice narration.", "C. calculate numerical data.", "D. analyze organizational progress."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Include voice narration. Many multimedia software programs have options that allow sound (e.g., voice or ringing bell) to be included to add interest to the presentation. Sound should be appropriately placed and pertinent to the presentation theme. Businesses use spreadsheet software to make, document, and calculate numerical data. Businesses do not use presentation software to analyze organizational progress. SOURCE: NF:008 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 215). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 61, "question": "What is one reason that a local business would keep records of all its customer-sales transactions? ", "choices": ["A. To cancel orders", "B. To issue rebates", "C. To handle returns", "D. To budget expenses"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "To handle returns. Businesses, such as retailers, keep a financial record of each sales transaction and give a copy of the record, a receipt, to the customer. When a customer returns an item, a business uses the information in the financial record to issue the customer a refund or a credit. The return transaction also becomes a part of the business's financial records. Businesses do not keep records of sales transactions in order to cancel orders. Rebates are a return of part of the price a customer pays for a good or service. They are usually offered by the product's manufacturer rather than by retailers. Expenses are monies the business spends, whereas sales transactions usually result in income. SOURCE: NF:001 SOURCE: NF LAP 1\u2014Record It (Business Records)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 25  "}, {"number": 62, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a current trend in business: ", "choices": ["A. Protecting consumer privacy", "B. Expanding economic growth", "C. Developing market research", "D. Promoting private enterprise"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Protecting consumer privacy. Businesses are becoming more concerned with ways of protecting consumer privacy because of the new technology that makes it easy to gather and disseminate personal information. The rapid growth of electronic commerce, which enables consumers to purchase products online, also enables businesses to collect information about credit cards, personal preferences, and buying habits that many consumers prefer to keep private. In response to a growing concern on the part of consumers, businesses are trying to develop techniques that will protect consumer privacy\u2014not only online\u2014but also from other types of abuses. Economic expansion and marketing research are fundamental business activities rather than current trends. Private enterprise is an economic system in which individuals and groups, rather than government, own or control the means of production. SOURCE: NF:013 SOURCE: Zikmund, W.G., & Babin, B.J. (2010). Exploring marketing research (10th ed.) [pp. 94-95]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 63, "question": "When conducting an environmental scan, which of the following is an economic factor that a business should consider: ", "choices": ["A. Local demographics", "B. Global trade regulations", "C. Consumer spending habits", "D. Restricted sales territories"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Consumer spending habits. An environmental scan is an analysis of external forces that influence a business's success. By examining economic, political, socio-cultural, and technological factors that affect the business, the business can take steps to ward off the threats and to take advantage of the opportunities based on the information that the scan provides. Consumer spending habits are an economic factor that might be a threat or an opportunity. If spending is increasing because the economy is healthy, businesses will be able to increase production and sell more. Global trade regulations are a political factor. Local demographics and restricted sales territories are not economic factors. SOURCE: NF:015 SOURCE: Boundless. (n.d.). Scanning and analysis. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from https://www.boundless.com/marketing/the-marketing-environment/the-marketingenvironment/scanning-and-analysis/  "}, {"number": 64, "question": "A clothing manufacturer checks one pair of pants out of every shipment to ensure the quality of its product. This process is known as quality ", "choices": ["A. inspection.", "B. guarantee.", "C. delivery.", "D. assurance."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Inspection. Checking a sample item for defects after it has already been produced is part of a process known as quality inspection. Quality assurance is a process businesses use to prevent defective products from being created, not just to eliminate or correct them after they've already been produced. Quality guarantee and quality delivery are not traditional terms used in operations or quality control. SOURCE: OP:189 SOURCE: OP LAP 3\u2014Smooth Operations (Nature of Operations)  "}, {"number": 65, "question": "What should employees who are learning a new skill avoid doing? ", "choices": ["A. Acting safely", "B. Following rules", "C. Taking shortcuts", "D. Asking questions"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Taking shortcuts. Employees who are learning a new skill should work slowly and cautiously, and avoid taking shortcuts. The quickest way is not necessarily the best way to complete tasks. Employees should practice the new skill using the appropriate steps and following the order in which they were instructed to use them. Employees who are learning a new skill should ask questions, follow rules, and act safely. SOURCE: OP:007 SOURCE: Bailey, L.J. (2007). Working (4th ed) [p. 113]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 66, "question": "An author's new book is an example of a ", "choices": ["A. derivative project.", "B. breakthrough project.", "C. R&D project.", "D. platform project."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Platform project. An author's new book is an example of a platform project, one that creates something entirely new. A derivative project enhances, adds to, or extends an existing project. A breakthrough project relies on the use of new technology. An R&D project takes on new visions or pursuits for the business. SOURCE: OP:158 SOURCE: OP LAP 6\u2014Projected to Win (Nature of Project Management)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 26  "}, {"number": 67, "question": "Before identifying the right people to work on a project, it is important to ", "choices": ["A. develop accurate job descriptions.", "B. select necessary supplies.", "C. ask organizations for contributions.", "D. prepare construction specifications."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Develop accurate job descriptions. Before identifying the right people to work on a project, it is important to develop accurate descriptions of the jobs these people will need to perform. The descriptions should explain exactly what is involved such as qualifications, education, or experience. Then, match the skills of project members to the job descriptions to find the people who will be able to do the work. It is not important to select necessary supplies, ask for contributions, or prepare specifications before identifying the right people to work on a project. SOURCE: OP:003 SOURCE: QS LAP 19\u2014Get What You Need  "}, {"number": 68, "question": "When managing a project, the first activity is for the project leader to ", "choices": ["A. develop a schedule.", "B. set goals.", "C. negotiate terms.", "D. monitor progress."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Set goals. It is important to develop a clear understanding of the project's objectives or goals. Without a clear understanding of the desired outcome, a project manager cannot effectively develop a schedule, negotiate terms, or monitor project progress. SOURCE: OP:002 SOURCE: QS LAP 18\u2014Make It Happen  "}, {"number": 69, "question": "A reason that many companies update or alter existing products is to ", "choices": ["A. be able to plan production quantities.", "B. make them competitive with similar products.", "C. create new products to put on the market.", "D. use a familiar production process."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Make them competitive with similar products. Updating or altering an existing product is a good way to compete effectively with similar products produced by other companies. Changing products is usually much less expensive than creating new products. Updated or altered products are not new products but new versions of old products. Changing products does not help the business to plan quantities since it does not know how well the revised product will sell. Being able to use a known production process would not be a valid reason for updating or altering products. SOURCE: OP:017 SOURCE: OP LAP 4\u2014Can You Make It? (Nature of Production)  "}, {"number": 70, "question": "A focus on how things are done, rather than just outcomes, is known as ", "choices": ["A. continual improvement.", "B. lean production.", "C. process orientation.", "D. concurrent engineering."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Process orientation. Process orientation is a focus on how things are done, rather than just outcomes. It is a central principle of ISO 9000. Lean production is maximizing customer value while minimizing waste. Continual improvement is a focus on increasing efficiency and effectiveness in all areas of the organization. Concurrent engineering is performing the stages of product design and development simultaneously, instead of one after another. SOURCE: OP:163 SOURCE: OP LAP 8\u2014Take Control (Quality-Control Measures)  "}, {"number": 71, "question": "When the LXT Audio-Book Company was founded 15 years ago, its target market was blind and visuallyimpaired individuals who enjoyed listening to nonfiction audio books. Recently, though, the company has begun marketing these same audio books as \u201clearning solutions\u201d for individuals with dyslexia and other learning disabilities. This is an example of __________ innovation. ", "choices": ["A. paradigm", "B. product", "C. process", "D. positioning"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Positioning. Innovation is the lifeblood of business, helping firms to stay competitive and to move forward. There are four specific types of innovation: product, process, positioning, and paradigm. Product innovation involves the development of totally new or improved products. Process innovation involves improving of some aspect of a process (e.g., manufacturing process). Positioning innovation involves identifying new, different ways to position a product or a company. LXT capitalized on positioning innovation by finding a different way to position its audio books in the marketplace. Paradigm innovation is a shift in the way of thinking that causes change. SOURCE: PD:126 SOURCE: PD LAP 18\u2014Ideas in Action (Innovation Skills)  "}, {"number": 72, "question": "Which of the following is an example of gathering information before making a decision: ", "choices": ["A. Watching movies", "B. Writing letters", "C. Reading novels", "D. Asking questions"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Asking questions. Before individuals can make decisions, they need to obtain information about the problem or situation. One way of gathering information is to ask questions of friends, family, coworkers, or supervisors. Asking questions enables individuals to gather additional information that may be useful in helping them to make good decisions. Watching movies, writing letters, and reading novels are not ways of obtaining information to use in decision making. SOURCE: PD:017 SOURCE: PD LAP 10\u2014Weigh Your Options (Decision Making in Business)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 27  "}, {"number": 73, "question": "Employees who are unable to manage their time effectively often experience ", "choices": ["A. decreased pressure.", "B. increased stress.", "C. increased self-esteem.", "D. decreased tension."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Increased stress. Stress is a mental or emotional feeling of pressure or tension. Employees who do not manage their time effectively often experience increased levels of stress. They find that they do not have the time to complete their tasks at work, and feel overwhelmed and under pressure to get everything done. The stress may follow them home and impact on their relationships with family and friends. Employees who are unable to effectively manage their time often experience increased pressure and tension, and decreased self-esteem. SOURCE: PD:019 SOURCE: PD LAP 1\u2014About Time (Time Management)  "}, {"number": 74, "question": "What should you avoid doing when filling out an employment application? ", "choices": ["A. Leaving blank spaces", "B. Specifying certain jobs", "C. Providing exact data", "D. Signing your name"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Leaving blank spaces. When completing an employment application, you should answer all the questions and fill in all the blanks. If the question does not pertain to you, write \"NA\" for not applicable. If you do not know the answer, write \"unknown.\" By filling in all the spaces, you indicate to the employer that you have read all the questions even if you don't have the answers. Employment applications usually require your signature. You should always specify the job for which you are applying and provide exact data on the employment application. SOURCE: PD:027 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 596). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 75, "question": "The basic purpose of writing a letter of application concerning a job opening is to ", "choices": ["A. interest the employer in interviewing you.", "B. describe your job skills in detail.", "C. tell the employer how you found out about the job.", "D. provide the employer with your complete work history."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Interest the employer in interviewing you. The purpose of a letter of application is to catch the interest of the prospective employer so that you will be called in for a personal interview. Few employees are hired without a personal interview. The letter of application should tell the employer how you found out about the job, but that is not a basic purpose of the letter. The letter should touch on your work history and job skills, but the complete details should be presented in your r\u00e9sum\u00e9. SOURCE: PD:030 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Succeeding in the world of work (pp. 125-126). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 76, "question": "The primary reason why many people engage in career-oriented networking activities is to ", "choices": ["A. connect with others who might help them accomplish professional goals.", "B. develop an extensive list of sales prospects and contacts.", "C. obtain letters of recommendation from previous employers.", "D. cultivate a wide circle of social and personal contacts."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Connect with others who might help them accomplish professional goals. People engage in networking activities by communicating with customers, friends, family, teachers, and former coworkers. Networking often provides people with information regarding work-related opportunities, such as job openings. Although networking is often used to develop a list of sales prospects and contacts, many people are not involved in selling activities in their occupation. Career-networking activities are primarily used to improve or enhance work-related situations rather than social standing. Obtaining letters of recommendation is often a result of networking activities. However, it is not always the primary reason why people network. SOURCE: PD:037 SOURCE: Kimbrell, G., & Vineyard, B.S. (2006). Entering the world of work (pp. 138-140). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 77, "question": "A characteristic of effective prices is that they must be ", "choices": ["A. high.", "B. inflexible.", "C. competitive.", "D. low."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Competitive. When a similar product is offered by other businesses, a business needs to be aware of the prices of those businesses. If not, the business will probably lose customers because it is not competitive. Businesses must be willing to adjust their prices, depending on the circumstances faced by the business. Changes in the economy, demand, and other factors can affect pricing. SOURCE: PI:001 SOURCE: PI LAP 2\u2014The Price is Right (Nature of Pricing)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 28  "}, {"number": 78, "question": "Which of the following pricing practices is illegal in some countries because it may drive a company's competitors' out of business: ", "choices": ["A. Below-cost pricing", "B. One-price policies", "C. Price skimming", "D. Markup pricing"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Below-cost pricing. When a company prices its products below cost, it makes it difficult for other companies to compete with the low prices, which they cannot afford to charge, and might eventually force them out of business. To prevent this situation from happening, many governments have laws that make it illegal for businesses to use below-cost pricing. When a business charges one price for all items it sells, it is using a one-price policy. Price skimming is a pricing strategy that involves setting prices higher than those of the competition. Markup is the difference between the cost of a product and its selling price. SOURCE: PI:017 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2006). Marketing essentials (pp. 535-537, 544, 549-550). New York: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.  "}, {"number": 79, "question": "One way that advances in technology are impacting the product/service management function is by making it possible for businesses to ", "choices": ["A. improve existing products.", "B. eliminate human errors.", "C. simplify production systems.", "D. control customer preferences."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Improve existing products. As a result of advances in technology, new materials and operating techniques have been developed. These materials and techniques have made it possible for businesses to improve existing products. This impacts the product/service management function because it enables businesses to extend the life of existing products and keep them on the market. Businesses have found that it is usually less expensive to update existing products than to develop entirely new products. Advances in technology are allowing businesses to do this. Advances in technology often help to reduce human errors but cannot completely eliminate them. Advances in technology often make production systems more complex because they rely on complicated computer systems. Businesses are not able to control customer preferences. SOURCE: PM:039 SOURCE: BusinessKnowledgeSource.com. (2003-2010). Pros and cons of improving or changing existing products. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.businessknowledgesource.com/marketing/pros_and_cons_of_improving_or_chan ging_existing_products_023885.html  "}, {"number": 80, "question": "Pick the best response: Where do product opportunities exist? ", "choices": ["A. Anywhere that people have had their needs satisfied", "B. Where people work", "C. Where people participate in their hobbies", "D. Anywhere there is an un- or under-met need"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Anywhere there is an un- or under-met need. People can recognize unmet or under-met needs wherever they are. This could be at work or where they are enjoying their hobbies. When people have their needs satisfied, product opportunities don't exist. It's when there's a problem or situation that isn't being taken care of that people can find product opportunities. SOURCE: PM:134 SOURCE: Katz, J., & Green, R. (2011). Entrepreneurial small business (3rd ed.) [pp. 80-83]. New York: McGraw-Hill Irwin.  "}, {"number": 81, "question": "When using mind mapping to generate product ideas, you begin by writing down the main problem or ", "choices": ["A. situational analysis.", "B. supporting facts.", "C. primary associations.", "D. market opportunity."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Market opportunity. When a situation exists to fulfill a market's unmet needs, there is a market opportunity. Entrepreneurs and businesses use creative-thinking techniques during the productdevelopment process, which involves finding ways to take advantage of the market opportunity that presents itself. Mind mapping is a creative-thinking technique that involves generating ideas by making associations. To begin the mind-mapping process, you write the problem or market opportunity in the center of a large sheet of paper. From that starting point, you draw lines to other words or phrases that relate to the main idea (problem, or market opportunity), and continue the process by making associations, which generates ideas and identifies possible solutions. The mind-mapping starting point does not begin by writing down supporting facts or primary associations. A situational analysis is a determination of a firm's current business situation and the direction in which the business is headed. SOURCE: PM:127 SOURCE: PM LAP 11\u2014Unleash Your Oh! Zone (Techniques for Generating Ideas)  "}, {"number": 82, "question": "True or False: Only express warranties hold up in court. ", "choices": ["A. False; express warranties must be in writing.", "B. True; implied warranties cannot be verified.", "C. False; implied warranties are valid.", "D. True; only written evidence can be submitted in court."], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "False; implied warranties are valid. There was a time when only express warranties held up in court, but today's courts recognize implied warranties as valid. Express warranties are warranties that are in writing or expressed verbally. SOURCE: PM:020 SOURCE: PM LAP 4\u2014Promises, Promises (Warranties and Guarantees)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 29  "}, {"number": 83, "question": "What strategy can make or break a business's product mix? ", "choices": ["A. Positioning", "B. Contracting", "C. Altering", "D. Expanding"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Positioning. Positioning is a product-mix strategy in which a business creates a certain image or impression of a product in the minds of consumers. Businesses must determine the best position to seek for their products because correct positioning is necessary to sales and profits. Positioning can make or break a business's product mix. Contraction is a product-mix strategy in which a business removes, or deletes, product items or product lines from its product mix. Alteration is a product-mix strategy in which a business makes changes to its products or product lines. Expansion is a product-mix strategy in which a business expands its product mix by adding additional product items or product lines. SOURCE: PM:003 SOURCE: PM LAP 3\u2014Mix & Match (Nature of the Product Mix)  "}, {"number": 84, "question": "Text that continues or clarifies the thought expressed in the print ad's headline is referred to as the ", "choices": ["A. tag line.", "B. subhead.", "C. identification.", "D. white space."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Subhead. A subhead, or subheadline, adds information to that expressed in the headline. It is usually positioned below the headline and set in slightly smaller size type. The tag line is a slogan used in an advertisement. It may be part of the identification element, the part of the ad that identifies the product's brand or advertiser. White space is the blank space in a print advertisement that is unoccupied by text or illustrations. SOURCE: PR:014 SOURCE: Farese, L.S., Kimbrell, G., & Woloszyk, C.A. (2012). Marketing essentials (p. 471). Columbus, OH: Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.   "}, {"number": 85, "question": "Why do companies use brands for their products? ", "choices": ["A. To demonstrate creativity", "B. To charge higher prices", "C. To encourage materialism", "D. To differentiate their products"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "To differentiate their products. Companies want their products to be perceived as different from those of other companies. They can do this through the use of brands. Charging higher prices and encouraging materialism are seen by consumers as negative aspects of brands. Creating an appealing brand often requires creativity, but demonstrating creativity is not a purpose of using brands. SOURCE: PM:021 SOURCE: PM LAP 6\u2014It's a Brand, Brand, Brand World! (Nature of Product Branding)  "}, {"number": 86, "question": "Which of the following is an example of a purchase experience touchpoint: ", "choices": ["A. Word-of-mouth", "B. Direct sales", "C. Customer satisfaction surveys", "D. Warranty programs"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Direct sales. Touchpoints are the interactions that customers have with the business, and they can be divided into three categories: pre-purchase, purchase, and post-purchase experiences. Direct sales would occur during a purchase experience. Other examples of purchase experience touchpoints are physical stores and contact with customer representatives. Word-of-mouth is an example of a prepurchase touchpoint. Customer satisfaction surveys, and warranty programs are examples of postpurchase experience touchpoints. SOURCE: PM:207 SOURCE: Flynn, J. (2013, October 31). Purchase touchpoints: Maximizing the brand experience. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://blog.hultmarketing.com/blog/purchase-touchpointsmaximizing-the-brand-experience  "}, {"number": 87, "question": "Many of the town's residents have heard that this coming summer is predicted to be the hottest summer ever. As a result of hearing this, Tim, the owner of an appliance store, decided to do more advertising for air conditioners. Which of the following external factors has affected Tim and his business: ", "choices": ["A. Cultural and social trends", "B. Legal and political factors", "C. Technology", "D. Demand"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Demand. Demand for certain products tends to change with the seasons, such as air conditioners for summer. This means that Tim needs to adjust his promotion to meet this change. Technology deals with technological developments, not demand for a product. Legal and political factors deal with government regulations and restrictions, not demand for a product. Cultural and social trends deal with changes in attitudes, lifestyles, and tastes of the consumers, not demand for a product. SOURCE: PR:001 SOURCE: PR LAP 2\u2014Razzle Dazzle (Nature of Promotion)  "}, {"number": 88, "question": "The specific goal of product promotion is to ", "choices": ["A. persuade consumers to buy a particular good or service.", "B. inform consumers about the company.", "C. show the company's commitment to technology or research.", "D. change a particular attitude toward a firm or its products."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Persuade consumers to buy a particular good or service. Product promotion is used to stimulate consumer purchases of goods or services. Showing the company's commitment to technology or research, informing consumers about the company, and changing a particular attitude toward a firm or its product are goals of institutional promotion. SOURCE: PR:002 SOURCE: PR LAP 4\u2014Know Your Options (Types of Promotion)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 30  "}, {"number": 89, "question": "Which of the following is the most visible element of the promotional mix: ", "choices": ["A. Personal selling", "B. Sales promotion", "C. Publicity", "D. Advertising"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Advertising. Advertising is any paid form of nonpersonal presentation of ideas, images, goods, or services. It is the most visible element of the promotional mix because it can be delivered to a wide range of consumers through a variety of mass media. Sales promotion includes promotional activities other than advertising, personal selling, and publicity that stimulate consumer purchases. Publicity is any nonpersonal presentation of ideas, goods, or services that is not paid for by the company or individual which benefits from it. Personal selling is the form of promotion that uses planned, personalized communication in order to influence purchase decisions and enhance future business opportunities. SOURCE: PR:003 SOURCE: PR LAP 1\u2014Spread the Word (Nature of the Promotional Mix)  "}, {"number": 90, "question": "What type of information are businesses that sponsor sales promotion sweepstakes and contests required to make available to the customers who participate in those promotions? ", "choices": ["A. Odds of winning", "B. Amount of rebate", "C. Value of coupon", "D. Samples of product"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Odds of winning. In order to operate ethically, businesses that sponsor sweepstakes and contests are required to inform potential participants about the odds of winning. By providing this type of information, businesses are not misleading or deceiving customers about the possibility of winning. Customers have the right to know what their chances of winning are in order to decide if they want to participate. A rebate is a return of part of the price a customer pays for a good or service. A coupon is a certificate or part of a printed advertisement entitling the holder to a reduced purchase price. A sample is a small amount of a product. SOURCE: PR:099 SOURCE: California Department of Consumer Affairs. (2014). Be smart, buy smart: What smart shoppers know about sweepstakes, contests, and lotteries. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.dca.ca.gov/publications/sweep.shtml  "}, {"number": 91, "question": "Governments that have passed \u201cdo not call\u201d laws are restricting promotional activities related to ", "choices": ["A. contests.", "B. telemarketing.", "C. Internet downloads.", "D. direct mail."], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Telemarketing. Telemarketing is an advertising medium that utilizes telephone service to promote a product either by phoning prospective customers or providing a number for them to call. In the past few years, consumer groups have complained that telemarketing has become intrusive, so many governments have started to regulate telemarketing practices. Some governments have developed \u201cdo not call\u201d laws. These laws allow consumers to register their phone numbers with a \u201cdo not call\u201d registry. Qualifying businesses must obtain this list and not call consumers who have registered with the program. If they violate these laws, the businesses may be fined. \u201cDo not call\u201d laws do not regulate contests, Internet downloads, or direct mail. SOURCE: PR:101 SOURCE: O'Guinn, T.C., Allen, C.T., & Semenik, R.J. (2009). Advertising & integrated brand promotion (5th ed.) [pp. 142-143]. Mason, OH: South-Western Cengage Learning.  "}, {"number": 92, "question": "A local, exclusive business is having a sale. Which of the following advertising media would be most effective in promoting the sale to the business's clientele: ", "choices": ["A. Out-of-home", "B. Broadcast", "C. Magazine", "D. Direct mail"], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Direct mail. Direct mail is a promotional medium that comes to consumers' homes in the form of letters, catalogs, postcards, and folders. Direct mail would be the most effective medium because the business can choose the clientele who will receive the promotional message. Broadcast and out-of-home media have limited selectivity. Magazine advertising is selective but costly, and the timing of the message may not be appropriate. SOURCE: PR:007 SOURCE: PR LAP 3\u2014Ad-quipping Your Business (Types of Promotional Media)  "}, {"number": 93, "question": "What is the primary goal of viral marketing? ", "choices": ["A. Managing", "B. Staging", "C. Sharing", "D. Manipulating"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Sharing. Viral marketing is a promotional tactic that involves sending or forwarding promotional messages over the Internet (e.g., email, social-media websites, and blogs) to generate buzz about a brand, company, or product. Marketers often use humor, incentives, events, spoofs, videos, and other unusual techniques to spark conversations and encourage people to share their messages with others. It is important for marketers to prepare (stage) and manage the message content; however, staging, managing, and manipulating are not the primary goals of viral marketing. SOURCE: PR:247 SOURCE: Baeldal, T. (2006, November 23). 7 tricks to viral web marketing. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.baekdal.com/analysis/viral-marketing-tricks  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 31  "}, {"number": 94, "question": "What communication channels is a corporation's public-relations department most likely to use to maintain positive relationships with shareholders? ", "choices": ["A. News conferences, consumer blogs, and employee manuals", "B. Press releases, online social networks, and print advertisements", "C. Newsletters, annual reports, and the company's website", "D. Policy manuals, commercials, and sponsorships"], "answer": "C", "reasoning": "Newsletters, annual reports, and the company's website. Public relations involves establishing good relationships between the business and the public. A business tries to maintain positive relationships with different groups that make up the public, such as employees, local businesses, government officials, the media, and the business's shareholders. Because the shareholders are the owners of the company, it is important to develop and maintain positive relationships with them. The public-relations department does this by communicating with them through newsletters, annual reports, the company's website, and online social networks. Print advertisements and commercials are forms of nonpersonal advertising. Businesses use press releases and news conferences to convey information to the media. Policy manuals help guide employees' actions on the job. Consumer blogs can be developed by anyone to communicate positive and negative information about various goods and services. A sponsorship is a partnership in which a company pays a fee to affiliate itself with a team, league, or event. SOURCE: PR:250 SOURCE: Soloman, M.R., Marshall, G.W., & Stuart, E.W. (2008). Marketing: Real people, real choices (5th ed.) [pp. 432-435]. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Prentice Hall.  "}, {"number": 95, "question": "Successful positioning appeals to customers' ", "choices": ["A. emotions.", "B. five senses.", "C. desire to save money.", "D. logic."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Emotions. Successful positioning appeals to customers' emotions. It connects with their feelings rather than just their logical or rational thoughts. Positioning is not a tangible experience that involves the five senses. A product may be positioned as a \u201cvalue item,\u201d or a way for customers to save money, but not all successful positioning depends on this desire. SOURCE: PM:042 SOURCE: PM LAP 19\u2014Getting Piece of Mind (Factors Used to Position Products/Services)  "}, {"number": 96, "question": "When salespeople demonstrate the features and benefits of goods or services, they often are able to ", "choices": ["A. provide jobs for more employees.", "B. add usefulness to products.", "C. develop new and improved products.", "D. create desire for products."], "answer": "D", "reasoning": "Create desire for products. Through the selling process, salespeople are often able to create desire for products by demonstrating the features and benefits of goods or services. By presenting the features and benefits, salespeople can explain to customers how the particular products will satisfy their wants and needs. As a result of creating desire, salespeople are often able to sell the product. Demonstrating the features and benefits of goods or services does not add usefulness to products, develop new and improved products, or provide jobs for more employees. SOURCE: SE:017 SOURCE: SE LAP 117\u2014Sell Away (The Nature and Scope of Selling)  "}, {"number": 97, "question": "Why do businesses try to build a clientele? ", "choices": ["A. Leads to repeat business", "B. Gives the business a new image", "C. Attracts well-to-do customers", "D. Provides continuing sources of new workers"], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Leads to repeat business. A company's clientele consists of a body of customers upon which the organization can rely for significant repeat business. These are the customers who return to shop regularly. Other benefits of building a clientele include reduced selling costs, increased sales volume, and personal satisfaction. A loyal clientele does not change the business's image, provide it with a source of workers, or attract well-to-do customers. SOURCE: SE:828 SOURCE: SE LAP 115\u2014Keep Them Loyal (Key Factors in Building Clientele)  "}, {"number": 98, "question": "Which of the following is a reason why the ethical and legal issues involved in selling activities are extremely important: ", "choices": ["A. Buyers avoid doing business with unethical salespeople.", "B. Sellers must understand how to criticize competitors.", "C. Sales staff must know when they can legally bend the truth.", "D. Sales managers are not responsible for what the sales staff does."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Buyers avoid doing business with unethical salespeople. Unethical salespeople often lose customers and create a negative image of their company. Making erroneous statements about competitors or bending the truth to make a sale are typical examples of unethical sales practices. Sales managers must monitor the practices of their sales staff because they are ultimately responsible for the actions and claims of their staff. SOURCE: SE:106 SOURCE: SE LAP 129\u2014Keep It Real\u2014In Sales (Legal and Ethical Considerations in Selling)  SAMPLE MARKETING CLUSTER EXAM\u2014KEY 32  "}, {"number": 99, "question": "What type of law prevents salespeople from one company from interfering with their competitions' activities? ", "choices": ["A. Product safety", "B. Unfair trade", "C. Consumer credit", "D. Warranty liability"], "answer": "B", "reasoning": "Unfair trade. Activities such as stealing a competitor's trade secrets, or attempting to get a competitor's customer to breach a contract, are considered unfair trade practices and are illegal practices in many countries. Consumer protection laws address issues such as product safety, consumer credit, and warranties. SOURCE: SE:108 SOURCE: Investopedia (2014). Unfair trade practice. Retrieved July 28, 2014, from http://www.investopedia.com/terms/u/unfair-trade-practice.asp  "}, {"number": 100, "question": "A restaurant server might obtain valuable information about the taste of a new menu item by talking to ", "choices": ["A. customers.", "B. the cooks.", "C. friends.", "D. suppliers."], "answer": "A", "reasoning": "Customers. Restaurant customers are often an important source of product information because they have tasted and eaten the menu items. Servers can ask customers if they enjoyed the new menu item and if they would order it again. Customers are usually willing to tell a server if the item was good or if they did not like it and why. Servers can use this information when selling the new menu item to other customers. Suppliers might have information about the various ingredients but not about the taste of a new menu item. The cooks would have an opinion, but it might be biased because they made the menu item. Friends would be able to provide the information only if they were customers. SOURCE: SE:062 SOURCE: SE LAP 131\u2014Get Informed (Acquiring Product Information for Use in Selling"}]}